<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content xmlns="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu http://zagor.hu/xsd/raw.xsd">
  <p id="back_cover">
    <next id="background" />
  </p>
  <p id="background" display="Background">
    <text>
        [p]Get into your time machine and escape from a carnivorous dinosaur, outwit a mad Roman Emperor, tangle with Chicago gangs. Can [strong]you[/strong] return safely to your own time?[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="1"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="1">
    <text>
        [p]“Have you ever watched a moth flying against an old curtain that's got holes in it? Most of the time it just bangs its head. To get through the curtain, it has to find a hole. If the moth knew where the holes were, it would find that easy. If we knew where the holes were, then we could travel through the curtain of time!”[/p]
        [p]That was Professor Zuckermann talking to his students at Chicago University. Not many of them believed him. With Zuckermann weighing twenty stone, it was hard to think of him flying anywhere! INSTRUMENTATION CHECK COMPLETE. TIME ZERO MINUS TWO MINUTES THIRTY SECONDS AND COUNTING.[/p]
        [p]Those were the words flashing across the videoscreen in front of me. Carl Zuckermann had lived just long enough to see the beginning of Project DITAS. DITAS stands for “Displacement in Time and Space”. That was five years ago. It had taken five years and two billion dollars to build a computer which could find Zuckermann's “holes in time”. I was now sitting inside it.[/p]
        [p]SWITCHING TO ONBOARD COMPUTER. ROCKET MOTOR SEQUENCE ACTIVATED. TIME ZERO MINUS TWO MINUTES AND COUNTING.[/p]
        [p]In fact, what I was sitting inside was a bit more than a computer. It had two powerful rocket motors and looked like a small spaceship. It could fly through space. What it was meant to do was to fly through holes in time. This was a Time Machine. TIME ZONE SELECTOR PROGRAM SWITCHED IN AND RUNNING, TIME ZERO MINUS ONE MINUTE AND THIRTY SECONDS AND COUNTING.[/p]
        [p]It was a funny feeling sitting in a rocket ship in the depths of a large building and knowing that there was no blue sky directly above me, only tons of steel and concrete. You don't need blue skies to fly in time![/p]
        [p]I hoped that the computer was going to get its sums right. If I missed the hole, then I would be heading for the wall opposite. With two tons of dipropyl tetrazol in the fuel tanks, there would be a very big bang![/p]
        [p]Your adventure begins in one minute fifteen seconds.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="2"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="2">
    <text>
		[p]TIME ZONE DISPLAY ACTIVATED. INJECTION SYSTEMS ACTIVATED. TIME ZERO MINUS ONE MINUTE AND COUNTING.[/p]
		[p]Two years ago, we had sent the Project Director's watch into time. It had come back in pieces. Last year, we had sent two mice. We had failed to get them back. I was hoping to do better! TIME ZERO MINUS THIRTY SECONDS AND COUNTING.[/p]
		[p]I was looking at the Time Zone Selector Panel. This was the most important thing in the ship. The numbers were still flashing off and on very quickly. When they stopped flashing, men one or more of the numbers would remain lit. Each one would be a hole in time. It might be a hole into the future or a hole into the past. There was no way of knowing. I would have to choose which number to press. TIME ZERO MINUS TEN SECONDS AND COUNTING – NINE – EIGHT – SEVEN –[/p]
		[p]The Environment Panel, next to the Time Zone Selector, was lit. This would tell me whether it was safe to leave the ship, wherever we landed.[/p]
		[p]– FOUR – THREE –[/p]
		[p]The flashing numbers on the Time Zone Selector Panel were slowing down. They stopped flashing – and there they were![/p]
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/2.jpg" /][/p]
		[p]I had just two seconds to choose one of them. – ONE – ZERO – IGNITION – IGNITION – IGNITION –[/p]
		[p]I felt the vibration of the rocket motors. I caught a last glimpse of the underground launch pad before the videoscreen went black. I felt myself forced back in my seat. I felt a pain across my eyes and I could no longer see the instruments in front of me. I was floating in a sea of sound and colour. I was travelling through time![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="15">15</next>
    <next id="8">8</next>
    <next id="11">11</next>
  </p>
  <p id="3">
    <text>
		[p]I was standing at the edge of a huge arena. My eyes were still not used to the bright sunlight, but I could make out a sea of faces above me, row upon row of them, seated all around the open space at the centre.[/p]
		[p]I knew of only one place in history big enough, it was said, to seat a quarter of a million people and even big enough to hold chariot races – the Circus Maximus in Rome at the time of the great Roman Empire![/p]
		[p]On the sand-covered floor were two men. One was on the ground, lying in a pool of blood that had soaked into the sand. The other was still standing. He was wearing a kind of leather armour which covered his chest, but he had no other protection. He carried a three-pronged spear – a trident – and a net made of thin rope. Walking slowly around him were three, full-grown, lions.[/p]
		[p]The crowd hadn't spotted me. But one of the lions had! I thought it could reach me before I could reach the ship. I had a .45, eight shot, automatic pistol strapped to my hip. I decided this was the time to use it.[/p]
		[p]The first shot missed. The second caught the beast between the eyes. The other two lions were now running towards me. I fired once, twice, three times. The second lion, I hit as it sprang at me. It passed so close that it knocked the gun out of my hand. I turned and saw the lion lying dead against the wall behind me. The third lion was also wounded. I saw it disappear into the passage from which I had come.[/p]
		[p]I looked at the man with the net and trident. He was standing quite still. The crowd began to hiss and boo. To my horror, I realised that they wanted him to fight me! He started moving towards me and the crowd began to cheer.[/p]
		[p]With a wounded lion somewhere down the passage, I had no way of retreat. My gun was lying on the sand a good way off. The man had begun to swing his net. I knew the idea. First catch me in the net, then finish me with the trident. I knew a bit about unarmed combat.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="7">If I could catch the net and throw him off balance, I might have a chance.</next>
    <next id="5">On the other hand there was still the gun. Had I time to reach it?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="4">
    <text>
		[p]It was only half a mile from the Circus to the Imperial Palace. I didn't think that I was under arrest, but my gun had been taken from me and, with the centurion walking beside me and six soldiers behind, I had little choice in where I was going. Rome was quite breathtaking, the Imperial Palace, magnificent. The room where I was to meet the Emperor must have been the biggest that I had ever seen. There were all of a hundred people sitting or standing around in it, yet still it looked half empty! The whole of one side opened through a series of arches onto a wide balcony. Beyond the balcony, shining white buildings and dark green cypress trees climbed a hillside and ended in a deep blue, cloudless sky.[/p]
		[p]My escort of soldiers led me across the room to one end, where the marble floor was raised and reached by three wide steps. In the centre of the raised floor, dressed in robes of white and purple, and seated on a throne of golden lions, was Nero.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="10"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="5">
    <text>
		[p]The man was a well-trained fighter. He knew that I was about to move. He didn't know that my move would be not towards him, but towards the gun. He flung the net, but it passed over me. I was already skidding across the ground towards the gun.[/p]
		[p]The hot sand burned the palms of my hands. As I stopped skidding, my fingers closed over the butt of the pistol. I caught a glimpse of the trident raised in the air and knew that he was going to throw it. I rolled out of the way, and as my arm holding the gun came free, I fired.[/p]
		[p]A bullet from a .45 at that range does not leave much to chance and leather armour will not stop bullets. I stood up. The crowd was on its feet and cheering. This time, they were cheering me. I wasn't feeling very proud of what I'd had to do.[/p]
		[p]I stood, holding the gun and waiting for whatever might be coming next. Perhaps someone had decided that I was killing off the afternoon's entertainment too quickly. Soldiers had started moving into the arena.[/p]
		[p]I could not take on what looked like half the Roman Army and I'd had enough of killing. I was ready to let myself be taken.[/p]
		[p]The soldiers stopped before they reached me. I lowered my gun. An officer, who might have been a centurion, stepped forward and walked towards me.[/p]
		[p]“You are commanded to the presence of the Emperor.”[/p]
		[p]My school Latin had never been very good, but I understood what he was saying. Without thinking, I asked, “Who is the Emperor?”[/p]
		[p]He looked at me for a moment or two before answering.[/p]
		[p]“Let me give you a piece of advice,” he said. “You have strange weapons and you are a brave fighter. The Emperor Nero likes brave fighters. He doesn't like comedians. If there are any jokes, he likes to make them himself.”[/p]
		[p]He had answered my question. If the Emperor was Nero, then my ship had brought me to Rome at some time in the first century AD.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="4"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="6">
    <text>
		[p]Wherever it was, it was very dark. I could make out a small square of light and nothing more. The videocameras outside the ship could “see”, even in starlight. I turned up the brightness of the screen.[/p]
		[p]The ship was in a small room of some sort. Part of the walls was built of stones. The rest looked to have been cut from solid rock. The patch of light I had seen was from a small opening in one wall, near to the floor.[/p]
		[p]The room was empty apart from some whitish objects lying about the floor. I zoomed in on some of them with one of the cameras. They were bones. They looked like human bones. I turned the camera. I was looking at a human skull which still had some rotting flesh on it![/p]
		[p]The Environment Panel said “Suitable”. It wasn't the word I would have chosen, but I got into the airlock and opened the outer door. That was when the smell hit me.[/p]
		[p]It was an animal smell, mixed with one of death and decay. I was sick on the spot. Either I got back into the ship or I found out what was on the other side of the opening. It could not be worse than where I was.[/p]
		[p]I peered through the opening. On the other side was another room. It was bigger man the first and lighter. It looked like an animal cage. There was some straw on the floor, more bones and some scraps of meat which I didn't look at too closely.[/p]
		[p]There were bars across one side ot fhe room and these had been slid part way up into the roof so that it was possible to crawl under them. Beyond the bars was a passage. This was where the light was coming from, though the passage sloped upwards and I could not see where it led to.[/p]
		[p]I ducked under the bars and started up the passage. It was getting lighter all the way. And then I heard it. It was the last sound that I would have expected to hear. It was the roar of a crowd, the kind of sound that you could have heard at any Saturday afternoon football match![/p]
		[p]I had come to the end of the passage. Now, I could see the crowd as well as hear it. It was no football match![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="3"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="7">
    <text>
		[p]I grabbed the net as it swung towards me, but I was the one who was pulled off balance. As I half slipped on the sand, the net was whipped away again.[/p]
		[p]I should have worked out that a man who had been chosen to put up a good fight against three lions would be a fair match for me. I had made the wrong choice and should have gone for the gun.[/p]
		[p]The gun was still there. I wondered what my chances of reaching it were. The man with the net had spotted it too and he was going to make sure that I didn't get near it.[/p]
		[p]We worked our way around each other and, so far, I had managed to keep clear of the net. Now I had got nearer to the gun and thought this was my chance to take it.[/p]
		[p]That was my second mistake. That was what I had been expected to do and I found myself struggling on the ground with the net over me. A foot was placed on my chest and the prongs of the trident placed against my throat. I closed my eyes and waited for the end.[/p]
		[p]Nothing happened, except that the crowd had gone suddenly silent. I opened my eyes. The trident had gone and the net was being pulled off me. I stood up in time to see soldiers walking across the arena towards me. They stopped, and an officer, who might have been a centurion, stepped up to me.[/p]
		[p]“You're the lucky one!” he said. “The Emperor doesn't want you killed. He wants to see your weapon.”[/p]
		[p]My school Latin had never been very good, but I understood what he was saying. Without thinking, I asked, “Who is the Emperor?”[/p]
		[p]He looked at me for a moment, before answering.[/p]
		[p]“Let me give you a piece of advice,” he said. “Nero likes brave fighters. He does not like comedians. If there are any jokes, he likes to make them himself.”[/p]
		[p]He had answered my question. If the Emperor was Nero, then my ship had brought me to Rome at some time in the first century AD.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="14"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="8">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/8.jpg" /][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="15">15</next>
    <next id="12">12</next>
  </p>
  <p id="9">
    <text>
		[p]I could not believe what I was seeing on the video-screen. If this was still the Earth, then it couldn't have looked like this for around two hundred million years![/p]
		[p]It was a land of lakes and forest, though like no forest that I had ever seen. Ferns were growing to the size of small trees and, in the distance, I could see something that looked like a clump of “horsetails”, but twenty or thirty feet high. There were lakes of brown water and banks of red mud, and the sun shone from a sky of pale green![/p]
		[p]I looked at the Environment Panel. It said “Suitable”. I unstrapped my seat belt and climbed into the airlock of the ship. A green light told me that it was safe to open the outer door.[/p]
		[p]The air was hot and moist. The place smelled of a forest after summer rain, but much stronger. I lowered the short ladder and climbed down.[/p]
		[p]It was like walking on a wet sponge. Water oozed and bubbled out of the ground where I put my feet. I trod carefully. I did not want to be trapped in a swamp![/p]
		[p]As I pushed my way between some of the smaller ferns, I felt a sudden tug at my foot. I looked down. Some kind of beetle, as big as a saucer, was attacking my boot with jaws that could have opened a tin can. I kicked it away and heard it splash into water. The air was filled with the hum of insects and now I could see a whole swarm as they rose in the hot air, dancing between the trees. They looked like dragonflies, but with wings three or four feet across and shining with every colour of the rainbow. It was a magical sight and I stood, just watching the ever changing patterns of the dance.[/p]
		[p]If I had not been watching the insects, I might have noticed something else moving towards me. When I did see it, it was standing between me and the ship.[/p]
		[p]It was the colour of the mud, with a skin like red leather. It was sitting up on its hind legs and resting on ifs tail. It was about the height of a two-storey house![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="13"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="10">
    <text>
		[p]Even the robes and the golden throne could not hide the fact that Nero was a very small man and going bald. When he opened his mouth, I saw that most of his front teeth were missing. He was taking no notice of me, but talking to a woman who sat on his right. I caught the name “Poppaea” – Nero's wife.[/p]
		[p]There was a murmur from the back of the room and four soldiers came in dragging two men between them. The men were thrown down at the foot of the steps in front of the Emperor. Neither moved. They were filthy, dressed in rags, and looked to be barely alive. The soldiers stood back.[/p]
		[p]Nero stopped talking and stood up. It was then that I saw he was holding my gun! A hush fell over the rest of the room. Holding my gun in both hands, he shot the two men on the steps. He stepped forward and kicked the bodies to make certain that both men were dead. At that distance, he could hardly have missed. His mouth broke into a toothless smile, and he waited while everyone else in the room laughed politely. He turned to me.[/p]
		[p]“Bring forward the barbarian!”[/p]
		[p]I was pushed towards the steps.[/p]
		[p]“We like your weapon, barbarian. It does not have the same pleasure as killing with the sword, but we can see that it has its uses. You will instruct my craftsmen in the making of this weapon.”[/p]
		[p]I noted that he did not say “would I” or “could I”. I could see that the man was mad. I could also see that he was now pointing the gun at me![/p]
		[p]I took a quick look around me. Everyone, including the soldiers, had moved back. No-one wanted to be shot by mistake.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="17">The way to the balcony was clear. Could I make it, and if I did, was there any way down?</next>
    <next id="16">It would be easy to agree to do what Nero wanted, though I didn't think I would be given the freedom of Rome. I would still be a prisoner, though there might be chances of escape.</next>
    <next id="19">I knew something about the gun mat Nero didn't. Could I use that knowledge?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="11">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/11.jpg" /][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="12">12</next>
    <next id="9">9</next>
  </p>
  <p id="12">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/12.jpg" /][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="15">15</next>
    <next id="8">8</next>
    <next id="6">6</next>
  </p>
  <p id="13">
    <text>
		[p]I had seen drawings of dinosaurs. I thought that this one was called Tyrannosaurus Rex. It opened its jaws and made an odd, rasping sound. I didn't like the look of its teeth![/p]
		[p]To get back to the ship, I had to run round it. It hadn't seen anything like me before and, as I started running, it just sat, watching me. Then it began to follow. It was like a giant, running kangaroo, each of its steps equal to six of mine![/p]
		[p]But it had given me the time I needed. I reached the ship, got inside and closed the outer door. As I moved to the inner door of the airlock, I was thrown against it. The thing outside could push the ship around as easily as I had kicked the beetle away.[/p]
		[p]Somehow, I got into the cabin and into my seat. The ship was now on its side. I couldn't fasten the seat straps. My fingers reached for the Time Zone Selector Panel.[/p]
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/13.jpg" /][/p]
	</text>
    <next id="8">8</next>
    <next id="15">15</next>
  </p>
  <p id="14">
    <text>
		[p]It was only half a mile from the Circus to the Imperial Palace. I didn't think that I was under arrest, but my gun had been taken from me and with the centurion walking beside me and six soldiers behind, I had little choice of where I was going. Rome was quite breathtaking, the Imperial Palace, magnificent. The room where I was to meet the Emperor must have been the biggest that I had ever seen. There were all of a hundred people sitting or standing around in it, yet still it looked half empty! The whole of one side opened through a series of arches onto a wide balcony. Beyond the balcony, shining white buildings and dark gttfen cypress trees climbed a hillside and ended in a deep blue, cloudless sky.[/p]
		[p]My escort of soldiers led me across the room to one end, where the marble floor was raised and reached by three wide steps. In the centre of the raised floor, dressed in robes of white and purple, and seated on a throne of golden lions, was Nero.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="18"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="15">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/15.jpg" /][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="8">8</next>
    <next id="12">12</next>
  </p>
  <p id="16">
    <text>
		[p]I told Nero that I would instruct his craftsmen in the making of the weapon, but that first, I must work alone. I told him that in the far country from which I came, the metals and the tools which we used were different. I must see whether the weapon could be made with Roman metals and Roman tools.[/p]
		[p]Nero seemed to believe me, but decided that these were problems for craftsmen and not for emperors. I would be given whatever I needed.[/p]
		[p]He was as good as his word. I was given a house for my work, not far from the Imperial Palace. I had servants to see to my needs and to bring me anything that I might want. The only thing that I could not do was leave the house and its walled garden. Twice I tried, and twice I was stopped by soldiers posted outside the gates. I was told that the Emperor feared for my safety in the streets. It was a nice way of being told that I was a prisoner![/p]
		[p]It was no more than I had expected, and at least I had time to plan my escape.[/p]
		[p]One room of the house had been made into what I suppose the Romans would have called “a well-equipped laboratory”. There was only one kind of weapon that I was interested in making, one which would get me out of the house and back to my ship in the Circus Maximus.[/p]
		[p]I made a list of what the laboratory had to offer. It didn't look too good. The first three things on my list were “dried crocodile, powdered horn of unicorn and mercury”! There were a few things on the list which might be useful. Gunpowder was a possibility, but not easy to use. I did have mercury and that meant that I might be able to make the explosive, mercury fulminate.[/p]
		[p]I sent the servants out to get cattle dung, marble, wood ash and wine. They saw nothing strange in that. I supposed they wouldn't if they were used to being sent out for dried crocodile![/p]
		[p]I worked, almost without sleep, for three days and nights. When I was finished, I had made a small amount of mercury fulminate. While it was still wet, I mixed it with sand and small pebbles and packed it into leather bags.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="23"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="17">
    <text>
		[p]I knew that the gun was empty. It held eight bullets and Nero had just fired the last two shots. However, I wasn't out of danger. As Nero had said, swords can kill as well as bullets, and there were plenty of swords around the room.[/p]
		[p]I didn't think that anyone would be expecting me to run. The balcony was a long way and I needed a head start. I started running.[/p]
		[p]Nobody followed me. They were all waiting for Nero to shoot me in the back. I guessed that Nero must be taking careful aim, because I had covered quite a few yards before I heard the harmless click of the empty pistol.[/p]
		[p]I heard a few more clicks behind me and knew that Nero was still trying. He had given me all of the time that I needed. I was now across the room and had reached the balcony. I looked over to see what lay beneath.[/p]
		[p]The balcony was higher than I expected. Just below me were two cypress trees. Would they break my fall? Shouting had broken out behind me and, suddenly, I felt a burning pain in my left shoulder. I jumped.[/p]
		[p]I crashed down through the branches of the trees, but reached the ground still in one piece. Blood was streaming down my left arm, but my legs were still working. I could see a gateway in the wall and I ran for it.[/p]
		[p]I was out of the Palace and into the busy streets of Rome. I didn't know where I was going. I just ran.[/p]
		[p]Towards the top of the hill, I found myself in a maze of narrow streets. Many of the houses were also small shops selling everything from vegetables to pottery. I stopped beside a cobbler's shop to take a moment's rest. I thought that I was still being followed. In the distance I could still hear shouting, and now me sound of horses.[/p]
		[p]People in the street were staring at me. I was losing a lot of blood and my clothes were covered in it. I was wondering how much farther I might be able to run when my arm was taken in a firm grip.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="25"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="18">
    <text>
		[p]Even the robes and the golden throne could not hide the fact that Nero was a very small man and going bald. When he opened his mouth, I saw that most of his front teeth were missing. He was taking no notice of me, but talking to a woman who sat on his right. I caught the name “Poppaea” – Nero's wife.[/p]
		[p]There was a murmur from the back of the room and four soldiers came in, dragging two men between them. The men were thrown down at the foot of the steps in front of the Emperor. Neither moved. They were filthy, dressed in rags, and looked to be barely alive. The soldiers stood back.[/p]
		[p]Nero stopped talking and stood up. It was then that I saw that he was holding my gun! A hush fell over the rest of the room. Holding my gun in both hands, he shot the two men on the steps. He stepped forward and kicked the bodies to make certain that both men were dead. At that distance, he could hardly have missed. His mouth broke into a toothless smile, and he waited while everyone else in the room laughed politely. He turned to me.[/p]
		[p]“Bring forward the barbarian!”[/p]
		[p]I was pushed towards the steps.[/p]
		[p]“We like your weapon, barbarian. It does not have the same pleasure as killing with the sword, but we can see that it has its uses. You will instruct my craftsmen in the making of this weapon.”[/p]
		[p]I noted that he did not say “would I” or “could I”. I could see that the man was mad. I could also see that he was now pointing the gun at me![/p]
		[p]I took a quick look around me. Everyone, including the soldiers, had moved back. No-one wanted to be shot by mistake.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="22">The way to the balcony was clear. Could I make it, and if I did, was there any way down?</next>
    <next id="16">It would be easy to agree to do what Nero wanted, though I didn't think I would be given the freedom of Rome. I would still be a prisoner, though there might be chances of escape.</next>
    <next id="20">I knew something about the gun that Nero didn't. Could I use that knowledge?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="19">
    <text>
		[p]I knew that the gun was empty. It held eight bullets and Nero had just fired the last two. That did not mean that I was in no danger. As Nero had said, swords will also kill, and there were plenty of those around the room.[/p]
		[p]The Romans believed in gods and magic. I had to show them a bit of magic of my own. I wanted Nero to try to shoot me. I wanted him to pull the trigger![/p]
		[p]I remembered the words of the centurion, “Nero doesn't like comedians. If there are any jokes, he likes to make them himself.”[/p]
		[p]I looked straight at the Emperor and I started to laugh at him. I watched his lace turn through shades of pink and red until it was almost purple. I saw his finger tighten on the trigger. There was a harmless click.[/p]
		[p]“You cannot harm me,” I said, quietly. “I am protected by powerful gods.”[/p]
		[p]Nero kept on pulling the trigger. Finally, he flung the gun to the ground.[/p]
		[p]“I am a god!” he screamed. “No-one defies Nero! No-one laughs at the god Emperor of Rome!”[/p]
		[p]He looked towards the soldiers.[/p]
		[p]“Kill! Kill the barbarian who insults your Emperor!”[/p]
		[p]The soldiers didn't move. They had seen what had happened in the Circus Maximus. Now they had seen their Emperor fail in his attempt to kill me. Seeing that the soldiers would not obey him, tears of anger began to stream down Nero's face. This was my moment.[/p]
		[p]“Wait!” I shouted. “I know that the Emperor Nero is a god and a great magician. I had to show the Emperor that I too have great magic. How else could I expect him to accept my challenge?”[/p]
		[p]There was a murmuring around the room. Nero looked at me.[/p]
		[p]“My magic,” I said, “my magic against the magic of the god Emperor of Rome!”[/p]
		[p]Everyone had heard the challenge. Now, Nero dared not have me killed on the spot without losing face. Nero knew it. He waved back the soldiers and sank down on his golden throne.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="24"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="20">
    <text>
		[p]I knew that the gun had only one bullet left in it. I had watched Nero shoot the two men on the steps and I could see the way he was now holding the gun. A .45 pistol goes off with quite a kick. It was pointed at my head, but the way he was holding it, the bullet would go way over the top of me, I hoped![/p]
		[p]The Romans believed in gods and magic. I had to show them a bit of magic of my own. I wanted Nero to try to shoot me. I wanted him to pull the trigger![/p]
		[p]I remembered the words of the centurion, “Nero doesn't like comedians. If there are any jokes, he likes to make them himself.”[/p]
		[p]I looked straight at the Emperor and I started to laugh at him. I watched his face turn through shades of pink and red until it was almost purple. I saw his finger tighten on the trigger. The bullet almost parted my hair, but now the gun was empty![/p]
		[p]“You cannot harm me,” I said, quietly. “I am protected by powerful gods.”[/p]
		[p]Nero kept on pulling the trigger, but the gun only made harmless clicks. Finally, he flung it to the ground.[/p]
		[p]“I am a god!” he screamed. “No-one defies Nero! No-one laughs at the god Emperor of Rome!”[/p]
		[p]He looked towards the soldiers.[/p]
		[p]“Kill the barbarian who insults your Emperor!”[/p]
		[p]The soldiers didn't move. If their Emperor couldn't kill me, then what chance did they have? Seeing that the soldiers would not obey him, tears of anger began to stream down Nero's face. This was my moment.[/p]
		[p]“Wait!” I shouted. “I know that the Emperor Nero is a god and a great magician. I had to show the Emperor that I too have great magic. How else could I expect him to accept my challenge?”[/p]
		[p]There was a murmuring around the room. Nero looked at me.[/p]
		[p]“My magic,” I said, “my magic against the magic of the god Emperor of Rome!”[/p]
		[p]Now, Nero dared not have me killed on the spot without losing face. He waved back the soldiers and sank down on his golden throne.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="24"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="21">
    <text>
		[p]It was beginning to turn dark. I had seen few people about since I had left the home of the Christians but now, as I came out of a narrow alley and into a wide street, I found myself amongst a crowd.[/p]
		[p]They seemed to be watching something that was moving along the street. I pushed my way nearer to the front of the crowd.[/p]
		[p]It was my ship! It must have been dug out from the lions' cage in the Circus Maximus, and now it was roped onto a flat cart being pulled by a team of eight horses.[/p]
		[p]I listened to the gossip in the crowd around me. It was a magic chariot, they said. Some had heard that it could fly. They were taking it to the Temple of Jupiter. If it was magic, then it could do no harm under the eye of the god Jupiter himself.[/p]
		[p]I did not know where the Temple of Jupiter was, but all that I had to do was follow. I did not have the strength to keep on pushing through the crowd and the ship arrived at the Temple long before me. There were thirty or more steps leading up to the front of the Temple and the ship had stopped at the bottom. The horses were being led away and long ropes were being tied to the cart itself. I could see that they were going to pull it up the steps by hand.[/p]
		[p]There were no more than ten soldiers and one officer. I didn't think that they were going to get it very far.[/p]
		[p]I was right. It wasn't long before the officer called to the crowd to give the soldiers a hand. No-one stepped forward. They didn't want to get too near to any magic chariot. I wanted to get to my ship and I could see only one way to do it. I stepped forward.[/p]
		[p]I must have looked a sorry sight, but it was just what the officer wanted. He shouted at the crowd.[/p]
		[p]“If this one will help, then what's the matter with the rest of you. Are you all mice!”[/p]
		[p]Several people moved forward. I grabbed a rope and tried to look as if I was pulling hard.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="29"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="22">
    <text>
		[p]I knew that the gun had only one bullet left in it. I had watched Nero shoot the two men on the steps and I could see the way he was now holding the gun. A .45 pistol goes off with quite a kick. It was pointed at my head, but the way he was holding it, the bullet would go way over the top of me – I hoped![/p]
		[p]I also hoped that no-one was expecting me to run and that I would be even farther off before the gun was fired.[/p]
		[p]I started towards the balcony. Nobody tried to follow, because they were all waiting for Nero to shoot me. That gave me the start that I needed.[/p]
		[p]I had covered several yards before I heard the gun go off. Wherever the bullet went, it missed me completely. I could hear the harmless click of the now empty gun as Nero went on trying. By now, I was all the way across the room.[/p]
		[p]The balcony was higher than I expected. Just below me were two cypress trees. Would they break my fall? Shouting had broken out behind me and, suddenly, I felt a burning pain in my left shoulder. I jumped.[/p]
		[p]I crashed down through the branches of the trees, but reached the ground still in one piece. Blood was streaming down my left arm, but my legs were still working. I could see a gateway in the wall and I ran for it.[/p]
		[p]I was out of the Palace and into the busy streets of Rome. I didn't know where I was going. I just ran.[/p]
		[p]Towards the top of the hill, I found myself in a maze of narrow streets. Many of the houses were also small shops selling everything from vegetables to pottery. I stopped beside a cobbler's shop to take a moment's rest. I thought that I was still being followed. In the distance I could still hear shouting, and now the sound of horses.[/p]
		[p]People in the street were staring at me. I was losing a lot of blood and my clothes were covered in it. I was wondering how much farther I might be able to run when my arm was taken in a firm grip.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="25"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="23">
    <text>
		[p]What I had made were six small, but effective, hand grenades. Now, I had to work out how to use them. It was late in the day and soon I would be brought my evening meal. I knew that the servants drank whatever was left of the wine after the meal. Tonight they would have more than their fill![/p]
		[p]Of the wine I had used for making the grenades, I still had two large jars. I added to each of them a little of a herb which I had found in the laboratory. I gave the jars to the servants, saying that I did not need them and did not want to waste good wine.[/p]
		[p]It was daylight at five next morning. All the servants were soundly asleep and would go on sleeping for several hours. The streets of Rome were still empty, though the guards remained outside the house. From an upstairs window, I had seen one of them pass die gate in the garden wall.[/p]
		[p]I had worked out that there were always four soldiers, one at the gate and one watching each of the other tfiree sides of the house. I picked up my grenades and made my way through the garden to the gate. I waited for the soldier to pass the gate and threw two of my grenades over the wall.[/p]
		[p]I knew mat the explosions would bring the others running. When I thought that they had arrived, I threw my second two grenades. There was still some shouting. I used the last two – and waited. All was quiet. I opened the gate and looked out. I knew that the grenades would do little more than stun the men and I could see that two of the soldiers were already moving. I started to run.[/p]
		[p]I felt a sudden burning pain in my left shoulder. I put my hand up to it and saw that it was covered in blood. I kept on running.[/p]
		[p]I reached a maze of narrow streets full of small shops. None of them was yet open, but a small yard next to a cobbler's shop looked like a good place to hide, at least for a short while.[/p]
		[p]Blood was pouring down my arm and I couldn't stop it. I must have fainted for, when I came to my senses, the street outside was full of sound and bustle. I tried to get up and felt my arm taken in a firm grip.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="25"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="24">
    <text>
		[p]A small group of people crowded around the Emperor. I could hear angry voices, but I could not hear what was being said. After a while, the group parted and Nero spoke to me again. Now, he looked quite calm.[/p]
		[p]“You say that I am a great magician. That is true, barbarian. Nero does not fear the challenge of any man, but how do I know that you are worthy to make such a challenge? You have shown us tricks with a metal tube which kills with thunderbolts. We have seen many such tricks, but none of them worthy of the Emperor Nero. How say you to that?”[/p]
		[p]I could see that Nero had been well advised, but I too had been thinking. My ship was in the Circus Maximus. By now, it might have been discovered and it might be well guarded. Even if it was not, I still had to get through the lions' cage to reach it. My plan was to have the ship brought to me![/p]
		[p]“The Emperor speaks wisely,” I said, “and would see more of my magic. Then send your men to the place which is called the Circus Maximus. In the inner chamber of a cage of lions they will find a magical flying chariot which brought me there through walls of stone. Have them break down the walls and bring the chariot to the Temple of Jupiter, the greatest of your gods. There, the Emperor may judge my magic for himself.”[/p]
		[p]The argument began again. I knew the risk I was running. Nero did not dare to have me killed here. He might agree to what I asked and have me killed later, calling it an “accident”. The rest of the people in the room were still keeping well away from me. I had a clear run to the balcony even now, and it was not too late to change my mind. Nero was speaking again.[/p]
		[p]“We wish to see this flying chariot. The barbarian shall be our guest until it is brought to the Temple.”[/p]
		[p]He turned to me.[/p]
		[p]“If this is another trick and there is no chariot, I promise that you shall still fly, barbarian – from the top of the highest building in Rome!”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="26">Should I choose to be Nero's guest?</next>
    <next id="28">Or should I try for the balcony?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="25">
    <text>
		[p]The next thing that I remembered was waking up in a strange place. The pain in my left shoulder told me that it had not been all a dream. I was lying on a low bed, and covered by a rough woollen blanket. A young, dark-haired girl was kneeling beside the bed. Behind her, stood a tall, bearded man, several years older than the girl. They were the first kind faces that I had seen since my arrival in the first century. I tried to sit up.[/p]
		[p]“Lie still,” said the girl. “You have lost a lot of blood from the spear wound in your shoulder. You must rest. You will be safe here until you have found your strength again.”[/p]
		[p]I started to speak. I wanted to tell them who I was and where I had come from. I knew they would not believe me. Instead, I asked how long I had been there.[/p]
		[p]“Three days,” was the reply.[/p]
		[p]Three days! What might have happened to my ship? I had to get back to the Circus Maximus. I told them that I could not rest. If I could walk at all, then I must be on my way. I thought it odd that they asked no questions, only that I first take food with them. I was weaker than I had thought, but felt better for some soup and rough bread. The blood had been washed from my clothes and I was given a long wool cloak to cover me and hide my strange appearance.[/p]
		[p]“I have no way of thanking you,” I said, as I was leaving. “I don't even know your names.”[/p]
		[p]“We need no thanks,” said the man. “As for our names, it is better that you do not know. What you do not know, you cannot be made to tell. Know only that we are among those who follow the teachings of a man from Nazareth who is called Jesus. We are called Christians.”[/p]
		[p]My friends had given me careful directions for reaching the Circus Maximus, but neither my mind nor my legs were working too well. I soon knew that I was lost and could see none of the places that I had been told to look for.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="21">I did not know whether to turn right.</next>
    <next id="31">Or left.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="26">
    <text>
		[p]The worst part of being Nero's “guest” was the food. Everything seemed to be cooked in honey and made me feel very ill. When, after three days, I was told that my ship was on its way to the Temple and that it was time to go, I felt hardly able to walk.[/p]
		[p]The inside of the Temple of Jupiter was even bigger than the room in the Imperial Palace. It was empty, but for the huge, seated statue of the Roman god. Like the room in the Imperial Palace, one side opened through tall pillars onto a balcony beyond. It was late in the day and, with the sky almost dark, torches had been lit around the walls.[/p]
		[p]My ship had been brought to the Temple on a kind of low cart. It stood at the foot of the statue while men untied the ropes holding it to the cart. I was waiting for my chance to get into it, but there were too many people and soldiers around.[/p]
		[p]I felt my foot slide on the floor and looked down to see a small pool of red, oily liquid. There was a trail of it across the floor. The fuel tanks were leaking. I wondered how much fuel had been lost. If a naked flame got near to any of it, it could set fire to half the city![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="32"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="27">
    <text>
		[p]The monks of the Tibetan monastery of Tang Shoh nursed me slowly back to health. Only one of them could speak a little English and from him I learned that all of the roads to northern India were closed by snow. It would be many weeks before I could leave the monastery or any message could reach the rest of the world.[/p]
		[p]At least I was back in my own time. I had landed in Tibet just ten days before I had set off on my journey into time. It was three months later that news of my return reached my friends.[/p]
		[p]It took me ten days by mule and train to reach Delhi where I met the Project Director who had flown out to meet me. Twenty-four hours later, I was home.[/p]
		[p]Project DITAS had been a success. Travel in time had been shown to be possible, though no-one else would be going until some safer way was found of[/p]
		[p]getting back.[/p]
		[p]While I had been in the monastery of Tang Shoh, I had had a lot of time for thinking.[/p]
		[p]My arrival in Nero's Rome would seem to have been no more than an accident, but I had been the cause of the burning of the city. History does record such a fire at that time. History blamed the mad Emperor Nero. It has been said that Nero blamed the Christians – or was it a time traveller who had come from nineteen hundred years into the future?[/p]
		[p]I had not changed history by my action – but what if I [em]had[/em] agreed to make guns for the Roman Army?[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="28">
    <text>
		[p]I glanced towards the balcony. The way was still clear, but it was a good way off. I knew the gun was empty, but a lot could happen before I got there.[/p]
		[p]I had taken a few risks already and I thought it was worth trying one more. They all thought that I was a magician. Now I was going to act like one.[/p]
		[p]“So be it,” I said.[/p]
		[p]I raised my arms in the air and, in a loud voice, began slowly to recite in my own language, the words of a nursery rhyme.[/p]
		[p]“Hickory, dickory, dock …”[/p]
		[p]As I recited, I began moving backwards towards the balcony. They were all waiting for the next piece of magic and nobody moved. I might have made it all the way to the balcony, but when I was about half way, my courage failed me and I started to run.[/p]
		[p]The balcony was higher than I expected. Just below me were two cypress trees. Would they break my fall? Shouting had broken out behind me and, suddenly, I felt a burning pain in my left shoulder. I jumped.[/p]
		[p]I crashed down through the branches of the trees, but reached the ground still in one piece. Blood was streaming down my left arm, but my legs were still working. I could see a gateway in the wall and I ran for it.[/p]
		[p]I was out of the Palace and into the busy streets of Rome. I didn't know where I was going. I just ran.[/p]
		[p]Towards the top of the hill, I found myself in a maze of narrow streets. Many of the houses were also small shops selling everything from vegetables to pottery. I stopped beside a cobbler's shop to take a moment's rest. I thought that I was still being followed. In the distance I could still hear shouting, and now the sound of horses.[/p]
		[p]People in the street were staring at me. I was losing a lot of blood and my clothes were covered in it. I was wondering how much farther I might be able to run when my arm was taken in a firm grip.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="25"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="29">
    <text>
		[p]The ship reached the top of the steps. Now it would be easy to drag it the rest of the way into the Temple. I feared that those who were helping might now be sent away, but the officer seemed happy to use the extra pairs of willing hands.[/p]
		[p]The inside of the Temple was even bigger than the room in die Imperial Palace. It was empty, but for the huge seated statue of the god Jupiter. Like the room in the Imperial Palace, one side opened through tall pillars onto a balcony beyond. The sky was getting quite dark and torches had been lit around the walls.[/p]
		[p]The ship was left at the feet of the statue, looking quite tiny beside it. I was waiting for my chance to get into it, but there were too many people and soldiers around. I felt my loot slide on the floor and I looked down to see a small pool of red, oily liquid. There was a trail of it across the floor. The fuel tanks were leaking. I wondered how much had been lost, and where. If a naked flame got near to any of it, it could set fire to half the city![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="32"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="30">
    <text>
		[p]All the instruments said that the ship had landed, though there was nothing on the videoscreen. It was on, but completely white. I tried turning the brightness up and down, but that made no difference. The Environment Panel said “Suitable”. The only way to find out what had happened was to get out of the ship.[/p]
		[p]The outer door of the airlock would not move. It seemed to be stuck. I tried again. This time, it did begin to move, though very slowly. As the first crack of light appeared, there was an icy blast of air and snow began to blow into the airlock.[/p]
		[p]I got the door far enough open to squeeze through it. The ship was half buried in deep, soft snow.[/p]
		[p]A curtain of snow swept steadily across the landscape and made seeing difficult. Every now and again the curtain of snow would break and give brief glimpses of what lay in the distance.[/p]
		[p]I had landed in high mountains – perhaps the Himalayas, perhaps the Andes of South America, perhaps a million years into the past, or a million years into the future. The snow was parting again and I could see the side of the mountain opposite. About half way up it was a building.[/p]
		[p]I would have seen it better with the videocam-eras, but they were buried in the snow. It was just a building, very plain and simple, like the monasteries of Tibet. It might have been built at any time in a period of several thousand years. I had no means of knowing whether there was anyone in it or whether it was nothing more than an empty ruin. If I did set off to reach it, I was not at all certain that I had the strength to get there.[/p]
		[p]I got back into the ship and took a look at the fuel gauges. I didn't need the computer to tell me that I had only enough to make one more trip in time. The choice was clear.[/p]
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/30.jpg" /][/p]
	</text>
    <next id="35">Either I walked to the building.</next>
    <next id="37">Or I used the Time Zone Selector for the very last time.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="31">
    <text>
		[p]When I had left the home of the Christians, I hadn't thought about what time of day it was, but I could see that it was beginning to get dark. I came to the end of another street and there, on the skyline, I could make out the long shape of the top of the Circus Maximus. By the time I reached it, it was[/p]
		[p]almost dark.[/p]
		[p]My luck was in. The Circus was not guarded, and I reached the arena without seeing anyone. In the half light it looked very different from when I had last seen it. I was not sure where the passage lay, and I could see more than one opening in the wall which looked just like it. I worked my way around the edge of the arena until the things I remembered looked to be in the right places.[/p]
		[p]There was an opening in the wall quite near to me. It was pitch black inside but I could feel that the floor did slope downwards, and the smell was right![/p]
		[p]I edged my way forwards in the darkness, stopping more than once to listen, but there was no sound. If the cage was closed and full of lions, I saw no way that I was going to get through it.[/p]
		[p]My hands touched the bars of the cage. I felt around and found that the bars were still raised. The cage was empty.[/p]
		[p]I ducked under the bars and stood, trying to picture the small opening in the wall. I thought that it was right opposite. I walked, carefully, forwards until my hands touched the opposite wall. There was nothing for it now but to get down on my hands and knees and start searching for the opening. My hand touched something slimy on the floor and I tried not to think what it might be![/p]
		[p]I found the opening and squeezed through. It took only two more paces to know that my ship was still there. My legs didn't feel too strong and my head was beginning to swim, but I remembered getting into the ship, strapping myself into my seat and switching on the controls.[/p]
		[p]The last thing I remembered was switching on the Time Zone Selector. It was then that my mind went completely blank.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="34"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="32">
    <text>
		[p]The ropes tying the ship to the cart had been untied and, using wooden rollers, the ship was being slid onto the floor. It had just touched the floor when, not too far off, there was a loud explosion followed by a longer, roaring sound. The sky beyond the balcony glowed white, then yellow. There was shouting and yelling in the streets outside.[/p]
		[p]Everyone rushed to the balcony. I stood where I was, watching the oily trail across the floor. I had a good idea what had happened. If the fire spread all the way along the trail of fuel, it was going to reach the Temple at any second. If it did, that would be the end of the ship and everyone in the Temple.[/p]
		[p]Nothing happened. The trail must have been broken somewhere along the way. I looked over to the balcony. The yellow of the sky had changed to a duller red. I could see flames rising from some of the buildings and the smell of smoke was blowing into the Temple. Rome was burning![/p]
		[p]No-one was looking at me or the ship. I climbed in through the airlock and strapped myself into the seat.[/p]
		[p]I switched on the instruments and looked first at the fuel gauges. Of the two tanks, one was reading empty and the other no more than a quarter full. Both tanks must be damaged and I might still be losing fuel. I asked the computer for a damage report.[/p]
		[p]Two sections of the tank still holding fuel were not damaged and no more fuel could leak out. There was still enough fuel for take-off.[/p]
		[p]I switched on the Time Zone Selector and the videoscreen. As I watched on the screen I could see that the fire was spreading. Trees, dry from a long, hot Roman summer, were spreading the flames from one building to the next.[/p]
		[p]The flashing numbers on the Time Zone Selector had stopped. I took a last look at Rome and made my choice.[/p]
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/32.jpg" /][/p]
	</text>
    <next id="30">30</next>
    <next id="36">36</next>
  </p>
  <p id="33">
    <text>
		[p]The shop door had a Yale lock. I opened it and looked out into the street. For as far as I could see, it was completely empty. I made certain that the shop door could not slam shut behind me and I started to walk along the pavement.[/p]
		[p]I could hear the sound of a car in the distance, but I still couldn't see it. Suddenly, it appeared from around a corner farther up the street. It was big, black and square-looking, and I remembered thinking that it looked just like something out of an old gangster movie.[/p]
		[p]The car had turned and was heading down the street towards me. If I ran back to the dry cleaners, then I was sure to be seen. I stepped back into the next doorway, expecting the car to drive straight past me.[/p]
		[p]Instead, I heard a screech of brakes and tyres, very close to where I was standing. I stuck my head out of the doorway in time to see that the car had mounted the pavement and stopped right outside the dry cleaners shop.[/p]
		[p]I saw die nearside back window of the car wound down and something thrown out. I heard the sound of breaking glass. There was more screeching of tyres and the car took off again, roaring away up the street.[/p]
		[p]I wasn't sure what was happening, but something told me to stay where I was. There was a loud explosion and I saw glass scattering across the road. A split second later, there was another even louder explosion, breaking every window on the opposite side of the road. I knew what the second explosion was![/p]
		[p]Having escaped everything from lions to a mad emperor, it was just my bad luck to be caught in the middle of the Chicago gang wars. It was 1929 and most of the people on Project DITAS had not yet been born. If I did get back to my own time, I was going to be very old — and I was going to have to find a way of making a living.[/p]
		[p]One thing that I could do well was foretell the future![/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="34">
    <text>
		[p]When I came to my senses, I could see on the videoscreen that the ship was moving, not through time, but through space – somewhere above Rome![/p]
		[p]I might have pressed the Time Zone Selector before it had stopped, but I could not see how the ship had got out of the lions' cage without blowing itself to pieces. The Romans must have started to dig the ship out, and I had finished the job for them! I asked the computer for a damage report. STARBOARD FUEL TANK LOST, MINOR DAMAGE TO LANDING GEAR.[/p]
		[p]So where was the fuel ank with almost a ton of highly explosive fuel? The answer appeared on the videoscreen. Somewhere over the city was a burst of flame which showered onto the buildings below. Patches of red and yellow sprang up in the blackness. Rome was burning![/p]
		[p]With one tank gone, I was using up what fuel I had left. I had to escape into time.[/p]
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/32.jpg" /][/p]
	</text>
    <next id="30">30</next>
    <next id="36">36</next>
  </p>
  <p id="35">
    <text>
		[p]The snow was falling less thickly now. I put on everything there was in the ship that might keep me warm, and set off.[/p]
		[p]It was colder than anything I had known, even though I was working hard. The fresh snow was soft and powdery, and my legs often sank up to the knees. For an hour, I had been moving slowly downhill. Now I had reached the bottom of the valley and began to climb again.[/p]
		[p]The building still looked far off up the side of the mountain. It began to snow heavily, once more, and soon I could not see very far in front of me. I was climbing blindly, but I knew that I must keep going upwards.[/p]
		[p]Many times, I wanted to stop and rest, but I knew that once I sat down in the snow, I would never get up again. I began talking to myself, saying, “One more step, you have to take one more step.”[/p]
		[p]I had lost all sense of time. My mind had begun to wander and nothing seemed to matter any more.[/p]
		[p]It might have ended there if I had not seen the dark shape in front of me through the snow. I could hardly feel my legs, but I willed them to carry me forwards.[/p]
		[p]I was standing in front of two great wooden doors set in a wall of stone which towered above my head. I staggered to the doors and began to pound on them with my numb fists. My fists made no sound that I could hear![/p]
		[p]I looked about for a rock or anything hard, but there was nothing but snow. If there was anyone inside, how could I make them hear?[/p]
		[p]I leant against the side of the doorway to get a little shelter from the wind. I was thinking that this must be the end when I saw a rope hanging just above my head.[/p]
		[p]I took it in both hands and pulled. Somewhere, above me, I heard the deep note of a bell. I went on pulling until my hands could hold the rope no longer, and I sank down onto my knees in the snow.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="27"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="36">
    <text>
		[p]The first thing that I saw on the videoscreen was what looked like words! They were a bit fuzzy and I had to adjust the videocamera to bring them into focus. I still couldn't read them, until I realised that they were written backwards. They said, “Carlo's Dry Cleaning Service”.[/p]
		[p]They were written on a shop window and the ship was sitting inside the shop! I used the videocamera to take a look at the opposite side of the street. Above the windows of the shop opposite were the words, “Drug Store and Ice Cream Parlour”. This was America – but in what year?[/p]
		[p]The shop seemed to be closed. I thought that I was safe to get out of the ship.[/p]
		[p]The shop was closed and I also realised that I had seen nothing in the street, neither people nor traffic. It could be Sunday or very early on a summer's morning. I decided to take a look around the shop to see if I could find anything to give me a clue to what year it was.[/p]
		[p]I looked at the racks of suits and dresses which stood along the walls of the shop. From the styles, I guessed that it must be sometime in the nineteen twenties. Then I saw the calendar on the wall. It was 1929. The calendar was presented by the Lake Shore Meat Packing Company – of Chicago.[/p]
		[p]1929 was still much too far from my own time to think of ending my journey here, but I was tired and would have liked to take a rest.[/p]
		[p]I couldn't go to sleep in the ship. Somebody was going to pass the shop sooner or later and see a Time Machine in the window! The shop was hot and stuffy. I was sure that I would feel better if only I could stretch my legs in the fresh air. I could still see no-one in the street.[/p]
        [p class="inlineImage"][img src="resources/st2/36.jpg" /][/p]
	</text>
    <next id="33">I wondered if I might just spend a few minutes on the pavement outside.</next>
    <next id="30">The only other choice was to be on my way to wherever the ship would take me next.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="37">
    <text>
		[p]March 10th 1481.[/p]
		[p]My ship landed in this city of Florence, three months ago to the day. It is safely hidden away and if ever I can succeed in making the fuel for it, it will fly again.[/p]
		[p]That will not be easy. Many of the things that I need are not due to be discovered for another five hundred years.[/p]
		[p]I do have one hope. I have had the good fortune to make friends with the one man living in this time who might have the skill to help me. He is the great artist, scientist and inventor, Leonardo da Vinci.[/p]
		[p]Leonardo does not know that I come from the future. One day, I might tell him but, for the present, it is easier for him to think that I am from some far distant land. Already, he knows that I can explain many of the mysteries of science and that in my travels I have seen many strange things. He likes nothing better than to talk to me, often for hours upon end, and seems to spend little time on his painting.[/p]
		[p]The canvas on which he was working when I first arrived, and which is called “The Adoration of the Magi”, is still unfinished.[/p]
		[p]Today, I have been telling him about machines that can fly through the air like birds and boats that can sail under the water. He has made lots of notes and sketches and his rough drawings of what he understands of an aeroplane and a submarine are just about recognisable.[/p]
		[p]I can see that I shall have to do some more explaining. He still can't see how an aeroplane can fly without flapping its wings, and I must say that I specially like his submarine with rows of oars poking through the holes in the sides![/p]
		[p]I would like to tell him that many of his notes and drawings will survive to my own time, even if I don't return to it, but I don't think that he is quite ready to understand the theory of time travel.[/p]
		[p]I still want to get back to my own time and I will go on working to make the fuel for my ship. If I fail, then I suppose I must take comfort from the fact that a little bit of me will survive – in Leonardo's drawings.[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
</content>