<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content xmlns="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu http://zagor.hu/xsd/sor.xsd">
  <p id="back_cover">
    <text>
        [p][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="background"/>
  </p>
  <p id="background" display="Background">
    <text>
        [p]Your hike through Nepal leads you into a forbidden temple. As punishment for your intrusion, you must survive in the forms of several different animals in order to earn your freedom.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="1" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="1">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="1"][/p]
        [p]It's late summer You've been hiking in the remote mountains of Nepal when you come upon the ruins of an ancient temple. Vines have grown over the wide steps that lead to the entrance. The temple is faced with stone carvings of animals, all worn and crumbling except for one fierce creature – an enormous lion with the wings of a dragon. Its huge jaws threaten to devour anyone who dares to pass.[/p]
        [p]As you climb the steps, you sense danger. You step closer and stare at the lifeless monster towering above you. It seems to be warning you not to pass.[/p]
        [p]Summoning your courage, you continue past the statue into the dark, cavernous temple. You can barely see anything – only a glimmer of gold in the center of the chamber and beside it a frail-looking man in a simple monk's robe.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="2" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="2">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="2"][/p]
        [p]As you start toward him, your legs grow weak. You sink to the temple floor. You try to stand, but you can't. The strength is being drained from your body. You can't even lift your hand. You call out to the monk, but he neither moves nor speaks. You feel your life slowly slipping away.[/p]
        [p]Are you still alive? You are lying on the stone floor of the temple. The monk sits motionless beside you.[/p]
        [p]You try to sit up but you can't. You feel as if you were in a trance. Perhaps you are dreaming. If so, it is unlike any other dream you've had before. Maybe you [em]are[/em]  dead. [/p]
        [p]As if reading your mind, the monk says, ``You are not dead. Neither are you alive.''[/p]
        [p]``How can that be?'' you murmur, still unable to move.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="3" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="3">
    <text>
        [p]``You have fallen into the shadow of death,'' he answers. ``It is forbidden to enter this temple. Those who do not heed the warning of the guardian must give up their lives.''[/p]
        [p]You feel the chill of death hovering about you as you struggle to remain conscious. ``But I didn't know...'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``You knew better than to enter,'' replies the monk. ``The guardian told you quite clearly.''[/p]
        [p]``You mean the statue? I thought that was my imagination.''[/p]
        [p]``The guardian is real,'' the monk says gravely, ``though not part of the world you know. Unless it chooses to release you, you will remain in its power forever.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="4" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="4">
    <text>
        [p]``Remain where?'' you say, trying hard to make sense of all this. ``If I'm in its power, what's going to happen to me?''[/p]
        [p]For the first time the monk looks away from you. ``You must now give up your human life,'' he answers. ``However, you will be given a chance to live in animal form.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="10" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="5">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="5"][/p]
        [p]Straining every nerve, you gather yourself into a bundle of movement. The image of the charging lion burns into your eyes. Almost in unison the other zebras begin to lope away at an easy pace. You bolt, racing toward them. But the big cat is running, too, closing the distance between you at astonishing speed.[/p]
        [p]You veer to the left. Forget about catching up with the herd – you're running for your life![/p]
        [p]The lion can run faster than you, but only for a short way. If you can stay out of reach for a few steps more... but the lion closes in on you. You feel his hot breath on your flanks, then his long, curved claws slashing into your flesh and his full crushing weight bringing you to the ground.[/p]
        [p]In your final agony you watch two other lions, hurrying to join in the feast.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="6">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="6"][/p]
        [p]Something wild has happened. You crash back into the ocean, spraying mountains of water in all directions. Then, with a flip of your massive tail, you dive. Opening your mouth, you strain a few thousand krill from the water. They taste excellent. You swing your tail, accelerating.[/p]
        [p]You dive, deep... deep. The water grows darker. You pass a small fish – a hammerhead shark.[/p]
        [p]You hear the sounds of other whales, calling, ``Come, it's time to migrate to warm waters.''[/p]
        [p]You send a sound message back to them. You've always migrated with the others, but food is plentiful here, and you like the cool waters. Though you know you should join the migration, you're really not ready to leave.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="55" pos="1">If you stay in cool waters</next>
    <next id="21" pos="2">If you follow the other whales</next>
  </p>
  <p id="7">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="8">
    <text>
        [p]Looking over your shoulder, you see gorillas peering at you through the brush. The great silverback lumbers toward you. You tremble in fear. He crouches next to you and bites at the wire noose around your leg. Then he tears down the tree to which it is attached, ripping and biting the wood into little pieces. You are freed from your prison, but the noose is still looped tightly around your leg.[/p]
        [p]Other gorillas come up and rub against you. You feel a glow of happiness as you realize they are trying to comfort you.[/p]
        [p]Your happiness does not last long. Your leg is infected. The wire noose pressing against the wound increases the pain. As your leg swells, the wire cuts more deeply. The pain is more than you can bear. You become hot and dizzy and very sick. A few days later you pass into the eternity of death, a victim of the poachers who roam the mountains with their rifles and snares.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="9">
    <text>
        [p]It's going to be a pretty hot day, and you'd just as soon stay inside, so you jump on the windowsill where you can see everything in the kitchen.[/p]
        [p]``Bye, Jasper. See you later.'' Karen is going out. Before you know it, the door has shut behind her. You jump up on all the places you're not allowed.[/p]
        [p]What will you do now? You could take a nap, but you're not sleepy. You could hunt a mouse, but you haven't found a mouse in the house for months.[/p]
        [p]Oh-ho! The cellar door isn't shut tightly. You pry it open with your paw and slip through the crack, down into the cool, dark cellar. You scamper past the furnace. Hmm... some interesting smells. Ah, what's this? You turn it over with one paw. A snakeskin. It would be fun to find a live snake if it wasn't too big.[/p]
        [p]Oooo. You jump quickly to one side, snarling, but it's only a spider swinging on its thread. You start to swat it with your paw, but then you freeze because you hear very faint sounds from the other end of the cellar.[/p]
        [p]You crouch down and swing the tip of your tail around in a circle. You lick your chin. There's no mistaking that sound – it's a mouse![/p]
        [p]You begin to stalk your prey, but with your first step, you feel yourself changing... [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="103" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="10">
    <text>
        [p]Your skin grows cold, then colder still. You shiver violently. To be turned into an animal... you can't let yourself believe this. Who is this monk anyway? Maybe he's making it all up.[/p]
        [p]But before you can even question him, the monk continues, ``I serve the guardian of the temple. Though I will do my best to help you, I may not interfere with its powers.[/p]
        [p]``You must first be one animal, then another, then another, and sometimes the same one again. Time may seem to go in circles. You may remember your human existence or forget it in an instant.''[/p]
        [p]``But what if I die as an animal?'' you ask. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="11" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="11">
    <text>
        [p]The monk shakes his head. ``If you die as an animal, you die as an animal. What is important is that you [em]live[/em]  as one. For now it is the only way you can live.'' The monk moves closer to you as he speaks. ``You may be any animal in creation, anywhere on earth. You will retain some control over your fate. Whether it will be enough to save you, I cannot say.''[/p]
        [p]You try to speak, but the monk raises his hand, and a wave of darkness sweeps over you. When you next hear his voice, it sounds very far away. ``Would you be lord of the air, lord of the land, or lord of the sea?'' [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="12" pos="1">If you answer, "Lord of the air"</next>
    <next id="16" pos="2">If you answer, "Lord of the land"</next>
    <next id="6" pos="3">If you answer, "Lord of the sea"</next>
  </p>
  <p id="12">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="12"][/p]
        [p]You hear yourself screaming. The sight is so horrible, you shut your eyes. You must have fallen off a cliff! There is nothing under your feet, only rocks, hundreds of feet below![/p]
        [p]Slowly you realize that you aren't falling. [em]You're floating... soaring on the wind.[/em][/p]
        [p]You open your eyes and see great golden wings. They belong to you! You bank and flap, maneuvering into an updraft. You rise gracefully... higher... higher. Beneath you are hills cut by a mountain brook. Downstream the brook widens and weaves through a lush valley checkered with farms and orchards. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="18" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="13">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="14">
    <text>
        [p]You shake the sleep out of your eyes. In a second you're on your feet and trotting through the tall grass alongside your brother. You glance at his deep rust-colored coat and his white chin and throat and think, [em]That's how I look too[/em] ; and indeed you do, because you are a fox.[/p]
        [p]Your human memory is fading fast, and your memory of life as a fox fills your mind. Born this past spring, you have yet to see your first winter.[/p]
        [p]You grew quickly from being a tiny blind puppy in an old woodchuck burrow at the edge of a field. Your parents helped you catch snakes and field mice. Last week, when your mother frightened a small rabbit, it ran into your path and you caught it.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="15" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="15">
    <text>
        [p]Now it's time for you and your brother to go hunting on your own. Night has fallen, and a big round moon is glowing through the trees. You start toward the tall grass, where field mice are plentiful, but your brother has another idea; he nudges you and trots off through the woods as if he knows exactly where he's going. [/p]
        [p]You follow a way, then realize he's heading for the barn with the chickens. You stop in your tracks. Once, when your mother was teaching you to hunt, she led you near the barn. You could smell, see, and hear the chickens. You were all set to race toward the barn and sink your teeth into one of those delicious birds, but your mother nipped you sharply, nudging you back to the meadowland. You could tell by how hard she nipped you that those chickens meant food, but they also meant danger.[/p]
        [p]Still, you remember once when your father brought home a chicken. It was the best thing you ever ate, and right now you're very hungry![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="51" pos="1">If you decide to try to raid the chicken coop</next>
    <next id="30" pos="2">If you decide just to go for field mice and rabbits</next>
  </p>
  <p id="16">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="16"][/p]
        [p]You know instantly what you have become, because you can see your big trunk waving in front of you. You feel your stringy tail whirling back and forth, shooing away flies. You look around at the other elephants walking among the acacia trees.[/p]
        [p]Moving your massive body with ease, you sway slowly through the groves, stopping only briefly to try one sort of vegetation or another. In your curiosity you wander a little way from the herd and soon find yourself at the edge of the savanna. Only a dozen yards from you are two full-grown lions. They turn their massive heads and stare at you with piercing green eyes.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="17" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="17">
    <text>
        [p]With the lingering traces of your human memory – or is it the memory of a vulnerable baby elephant? – you feel a momentary sense of fright. Without thinking about it, you trumpet loudly, stamping the ground with your front foot. The lions spring away from you, running like frightened rabbits! You remember now that with one tap of your foot you could break their backs.[/p]
        [p]You head back toward the herd. The others have stopped grazing and are walking single file across the savanna. Where are they going? you wonder.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="38" pos="1">If you decide to try to rejoin the herd</next>
    <next id="76" pos="2">If you decide to explore the savanna on your own</next>
  </p>
  <p id="18">
    <text>
        [p]You see a little girl standing near a barn playing with a puppy. It seems amazing that you can see them so far away. Everything appears as close as if you were looking through a telescope.[/p]
        [p]You fold your wings to gain speed and dive, then open your wings and pull up short, still hundreds of feet above the ground. You roll and dive again. The rocks and trees are coming at you![/p]
        [p]You pull out of the dive and skim over the tree-tops. A crow hurries out of your way.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="88" pos="1">If you cruise along the coast and look for food</next>
    <next id="79" pos="2">If you cruise over the river valley below you and practice glides and dives</next>
  </p>
  <p id="19">
    <text>
        [p]You can barely see your mother as she lumbers through the woods far ahead of you. You're a Kodiak bear cub, and this is the first time your mother has led you so far from the den you were born in.[/p]
        [p]Where can she be taking you? And why is she leading you into the open? The forest is beginning to thin out, but your mother's still shuffling ahead – out of the forest, through a field of tall grass, and to the bank of a stream you've never visited before.[/p]
        [p]At the sight of it you stop dead. Throngs of salmon – more than you can believe are in the world – are battling the icy waters to swim up- stream. The water is alive with them, and bears are standing all around you, gorging themselves on the easy catch. You're witnessing your first salmon run.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="20" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="20">
    <text>
        [p]You start to charge for the water, but a cuff from your mother's heavy paw sends you sprawling. She's going to teach you [em]her[/em]  way of catching fish.[/p]
        [p]Meekly you sit next to her on the bank and watch. Whenever a salmon flashes too close, your mother darts her paw into the water and flips it onto the bank. You try to copy her, but something goes wrong every time. You keep missing. Once you make such a splash that dozens of salmon rush away from the bank. And when you finally land one, it flips itself right back into the water and swims off.[/p]
        [p]You're starting to get mad. In the deeper, faster water, you can see some boulders where a few huge male bears are fishing. Maybe you'd have better luck out there. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="112" pos="1">If you try to wade out into the deeper water</next>
    <next id="64" pos="2">If you decide to stay next to your mother</next>
  </p>
  <p id="21">
    <text>
        [p]You lash your tail and turn your great body northward toward the other whales. By pointing your head in slightly different directions, you are able to form a sound picture of the bottom of the sea – undersea mountains and valleys, and canyons where rivers once flowed. Sweeping toward the surface, you sound the other whales. There are five of them, but you sense there should be more following.[/p]
        [p]You send a call behind you: ``Hurry, our herd is heading toward the warm waters.''[/p]
        [p]But there is no answer. A great blue shape, the whale farthest ahead, slows. The blue whale is the biggest mammal that ever lived, and this one, leader of the herd, is almost one hundred feet long. He has dropped back to let you swim alongside and sends a sound message to you.[/p]
        [p]``You are new to our ways, friend,'' he says. ``There [em]are[/em]  no others. In years past there were more whales in our herd, but most of them have passed into the great deep.''[/p]
        [p]With a flip of his tail that sets a twenty-foot-high wave coursing through the ocean, the leader accelerates. You are left again at the end of the procession.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="24" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="22">
    <text>
        [p]You swing your tail, lunging at the pale wiggling creature. You dart in for the kill but instead smash your snout. Some kind of wire mesh is blocking you. Enraged, you swing around and lunge from another angle only to crash into the wire again. The pale creature moves quickly now. You can smell its fear. Your hunger grows stronger. For the third time you attack. The wire cuts into you. Your snout hurts. You can't seem to bite the creature inside the mesh.[/p]
        [p]As you turn to lunge again you feel a sharp pain. A spear is lodged in your dorsal fin. Your blood colors the water. If you had another chance, you'd stay clear of those strange pale creatures.[/p]
        [p]Suddenly you [em]have[/em]  another chance...  [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="12" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="23">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="23"][/p]
        [p]Dimly you remember: Pigs aren't tended for their fleece, like sheep; nor for their milk, like cows; nor for their eggs, like hens. They have only one purpose – one destiny. You roll sorrowfully in the mud, knowing that you are nothing more than pounds and pounds of ham and sausage and bacon.[/p]
        [p]Your human memory stirs. You do have a chance. But you'd better go on a diet.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="24">
    <text>
        [p]The days go by and the water grows warmer. The sun is higher in the sky, and you can feel its warmth on your back when you surface to breathe.[/p]
        [p]There's less food now, but you don't feel hungry anymore. You're able to live off your reserves of blubber for a while. You are content and happy as you glide through the waves.[/p]
        [p]A loud clanking sound travels through the water. The herd suddenly veers to the left. Surfacing, you see a great ship pass you.[/p]
        [p]A neighbor calls to you – ``Oil in the water!''[/p]
        [p]Suddenly you feel a slimy, smelly, black film sliding across your face. Some of it seeps into your blowhole! You cough and blow.[/p]
        [p]You let out a long low moan. A memory flashes in your mind: [em]If only you could be a person again![/em][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="26" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="25">
    <text>
        [p]Suddenly the lead dog turns and snarls at you, baring his teeth. You step back a pace and look away. When you look again, he is sniffing at the snow ahead of him.[/p]
        [p]You sniff and smell the other dogs, each with its own distinctive scent. You smell the wood and leather and half-frozen dried food stacked on the sled, and the scent of the men themselves.[/p]
        [p]Curious about the same scent that attracted the lead dog, you step forward. He turns on you, growling. You shrink back. Why is he so unfriendly? The answer comes to you. You are the number-two dog – he is afraid you are challenging his authority. If you could smile, you would, because you realize what power you have, with your human mind.[/p]
        [p]CRACK. ``Mush!'' Instinctively you press forward, taking up the slack and straining with the other dogs to break the sled out of the ice. In a moment you're all trotting along at a good clip, pulling the loaded sled over the hard-packed snow.[/p]
        [p]You have no idea when you'll get to rest. Unlike the other dogs, you think about what you'll do when you make camp for the night.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="100" pos="1">If you decide to try to challenge the leader and become lead dog</next>
    <next id="77" pos="2">If you decide you'll try to escape and gain your freedom</next>
  </p>
  <p id="26">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="26"][/p]
        [p]Suddenly you are you – the human being again – back on the temple floor.[/p]
        [p]``So you are still alive.'' The monk is sitting, gazing into the flame of a tiny oil lamp. The dark chill of the temple cuts through you, and you realize that once again you are unable to move.[/p]
        [p]``Won't the guardian release me yet?''[/p]
        [p]``I think not,'' says the monk, without turning to look at you. ``You are not yet in the realm of the living. The only way for you to survive is to become an animal once again. First you must answer this question: Living as an animal, would you rather be among people, near people, or far away from people?'' [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="33" pos="1">If you say you'd rather live among people</next>
    <next id="14" pos="2">If you say you'd rather live near people</next>
    <next id="69" pos="3">If you say you'd rather live away from people</next>
  </p>
  <p id="27">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="28">
    <text>
        [p]Not long after passing the valley of the bones, you see another small herd of elephants crossing your path. You had thought your group was headed toward better feeding grounds. Why is this group heading a different way? You listen for the rumbling sound of contentment from the leaders of the two herds, but you hear nothing. You search your memories. Gradually the picture forms. There are good feeding grounds to the south, but there are also many humans and their dwellings, their crops, and their guns. To the north is an area where humans rarely kill. But there the trees have been stripped bare, and you will find only parched grasslands where an elephant can hardly keep cool enough to graze.[/p]
        [p]The two herds are regrouping. Some elephants are going north, some south. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="36" pos="1">If you follow the group headed south toward the good feeding grounds</next>
    <next id="97" pos="2">If you head north toward the safe area</next>
  </p>
  <p id="29">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="29"][/p]
        [p]You gallop across the canyon, your flanks foaming with sweat and your lungs burning. You're gaining on the herd, but the other horses are still far ahead. Desperately you drive yourself toward the ravine. Suddenly your right foreleg plunges into a hole in the rocky canyon floor. There's a sharp snap. A searing pain tears through your leg. You stumble and fall to the ground, your leg shattered. Another flash of lightning splits the air as the herd races on.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="30">
    <text>
        [p]You walk slowly through the meadowland, ears perked, straining to hear a sound in the grass that is not a cricket or the wind ruffling leaves, but instead a field mouse or maybe a rabbit.[/p]
        [p]From time to time you stop and sniff the air, ignoring dozens of scents of plants and mosses and the smell of wet earth that tells you there is a spring nearby.[/p]
        [p]What's that? Fresh rabbit scent! You press on, then stop to listen: The grass is parting and closing up ahead.[/p]
        [p]In the light of the moon you might be able to see the rabbit – probably a young one.[/p]
        [p]Your mouth waters. The tip of your nose quivers with excitement You'll stalk your prey and get as close as you can. Once a rabbit bolts, you have to put out everything you've got to catch it. Rabbits have a way of disappearing into thickets that can give you a scratched nose and no dinner for your trouble.[/p]
        [p]The rabbit has climbed up on a little mound. There it is in full view! Should you try to get a little closer, or charge now?[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="54" pos="1">If you try to get a little closer</next>
    <next id="42" pos="2">If you charge now</next>
  </p>
  <p id="31">
    <text>
        [p]You dive for the crab, keeping your eyes on it as it scuttles out of sight Could it somehow have sensed your attack? Still in full plunge, you release your wings from tuck position, bank slightly, and set down on the beach.[/p]
        [p]You smell the salt mud and the rows of kelp, abuzz with flies and gnats. You extract a scrap of meat from a clam, then eye some mussels already picked clean by the gulls.[/p]
        [p]Even though the beach is deserted, you don't feel comfortable on the ground. You beat your wings and launch into the air. You have not been finding enough to eat, and you will have to use a lot of energy to gain a good hunting altitude. The weather is cool and misty. There are no thermals to lift you. You flap your wings continuously to gain altitude. The lord of the air must keep hunting every hour, every day. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="47" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="32">
    <text>
        [p]``I'll take a chance being an animal again.''[/p]
        [p]Even as you speak the room seems to dissolve before your eyes.[/p]
        [p]Your next sensation is one of feeling immensely strong, fearless, and proud. You open your great mouth and let out a deafening roar that would scare you half to death if you weren't making it yourself. You look-down at your huge tawny paws. Turning your head, you see your powerful hindquarters and your splendid, tufted tail. There's no doubt about it – you are a lion![/p]
        [p]But you are in a zoo, a horrible zoo, pacing back and forth in a horrible cage. [em]Three steps, turn, three steps, turn, three steps, turn; stop to look at the gawking people behind the black steel bars. Three steps, three steps.[/em][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="65" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="33">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="33"][/p]
        [p]Suddenly your whole body shudders, and you know you [em]are changing into another you.[/em][/p]
        [p][em]Meearggk. Eeowarr.[/em]  The voice is yours! All you can see are the legs of tables and chairs, and shoes – out of which grow legs, and far above, the human you live with, Karen. She's standing over the counter. Maybe she's making dinner. If only you could see.[/p]
        [p]No sooner do you think that than you feel your muscles tense. You crouch like a coiled spring and leap – six times as high as you stand – and land neatly on the kitchen table.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="34" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="34">
    <text>
        [p] A great hand is swooping through the air, coming right at you. Whoosh – it cradles your hindquarters, pushing you with more force than you can resist, right to the edge of the table. Nothing left but jump. You land neatly on the floor.[/p]
        [p]``Jasper!'' Karen cries. ``You [em]know[/em]  you're not supposed to be on the table!''[/p]
        [p]You pretend to look sorrowful, but you're not sorry. ``Nothing ventured, nothing gained.'' That's your cat philosophy.[/p]
        [p]Your nose smells liver and kidneys. There's your dish descending to the floor! You stroll over to it, careful not to act too eager, like the stupid dog next door.[/p]
        [p]``Well, Jasper,'' you hear Karen say as you feel her long fingers running over your back, ``would you like to go outside?'' [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="80" pos="1">If you run to the door to be let out</next>
    <next id="9" pos="2">If you stay put</next>
  </p>
  <p id="35">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="36">
    <text>
        [p]You fall in line with eight other elephants headed for the land of the humans.[/p]
        [p]For the first few days it's hard going across the dusty plain. Sometimes you have to stop for long periods of forage. But as you work your way south you find lusher vegetation. Then a day comes when you see a dwelling of humans. Food is plentiful, but the elephants are nervous. You pace up and down. Trumpeting loudly, one big elephant charges into the bush. A man rushes after it, his rifle raised. Two other hunters follow him.[/p]
        [p]You hear an explosion, then a bellow of pain. Suddenly your human memory returns. You must stay alive – you must escape the humans![/p]
        [p]You flee into the forest. You can hear the hunters' voices and more shots behind you. Finally, in the darkest part of the forest, you lose them. Here you'll be safe for a while, and maybe... [em]yes, you feel yourself changing...[/em][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="26" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="37">
    <text>
        [p]The moment you hit the water, you realize you are an albatross no more. You're a sea mammal – a sea lion, in fact, paddling through the water. You lunge and catch a fish; perhaps it's the same fish you would have caught had you remained an albatross.[/p]
        [p]There is a small rocky island nearby, jutting out of the sea. The rocks are too steep for you to climb. Waves are sloshing around them, sending spray high in the air. Then you see a way to reach a rock that is safely out of reach of the waves. You swim along, riding the crest of a wave. Just as it surges to its greatest height, you leap up onto the high rock.[/p]
        [p]``[em]Oerrk, oerrk[/em],'' you bark, pleased with yourself.[/p]
        [p]``[em]Oerrk, oerrk[/em],'' another sea lion answers.[/p]
        [p]Looking around, you see others of your kind playing near the island. The sun bakes down on your cool, smooth hide. You blink your eyes and snort. Soon you'll go fishing again. You bask awhile and then slide toward the edge of the rock and roll happily off the edge, but not into the water – you are rolling through time and space, a different form.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="16" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="38">
    <text>
        [p]You follow the herd across the plain. They are moving at a slow walk, and you lope after them to catch up. Some of the other elephants stop to stare at you. The leader, a huge old female, steps toward you. She looks at you with kindly eyes as she makes a low rumbling sound. Another elephant brushes your back with her trunk.[/p]
        [p]The herd stops in a grove of acacia trees, but there is little to eat You work hard, stripping bark and pushing over stumps to find good vegetation. You have to eat and eat and eat. There's so much of you to feed![/p]
        [p]Within a few hours the grove has been stripped. The leader makes a low noise in her throat as she resumes the trek across the open plain. You and the others follow.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="39" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="39">
    <text>
        [p]The weather has been getting drier. You know, without being told, that you are searching for better feeding grounds. It's hard having to eat so much, but at least you don't live in constant fear, like the antelopes, zebras, and giraffes.[/p]
        [p]Your herd has come upon a field in which hundreds of elephant bones lie scattered about. Several of the other elephants pick up bones with their trunks. You watch as the leader carries a bone into a grove of baobab trees. She drops it gently, stands quietly a few moments and then returns to the herd. Did this bone belong to one of her ancestors?[/p]
        [p]Just as you couldn't fully understand the human mind while in human form, you can't expect to understand everything about elephants, even though you are one.[/p]
        [p]The quest for food tugs at the herd, and the procession resumes. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="28" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="40">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="40"][/p]
        [p]You're still swimming in the ocean, but now you're breathing underwater![/p]
        [p]You feel as if you were all teeth![/p]
        [p][em]You are a shark![/em][/p]
        [p]A fish ahead! A juicy bass! Your tail vibrates. Your body quivers as you home in on your prey. In an instant you've torn it to shreds.[/p]
        [p]You're still hungry.[/p]
        [p]Fat tuna! You pivot, and barrel toward it. It sees you. Extra speed. Open mouth. Your teeth rip into it, and you bite off its tail. The tuna can't get far now. Seconds later, only bloody water remains. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="41" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="41">
    <text>
        [p]You're still hungry.[/p]
        [p]A nice squid. You dive. It's sending out thick black ink. You can smell the squid right through the ink. Extra speed. The squid is good for one bite.[/p]
        [p]You're still hungry.[/p]
        [p]Ah, that slow, chunky creature with no fins and two long kicking limbs hanging behind it. Should you attack? It looks as if it would taste good, but there is something about it that makes you nervous.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="22" pos="1">If you attack</next>
    <next id="83" pos="2">If you swim off in another direction</next>
  </p>
  <p id="42">
    <text>
        [p]You charge and the rabbit is off! He runs in a straight line, then veers sharply. You almost lose your balance trying to change direction. There he goes – into the thicket! You're right behind him. Gaining! [em]Got him![/em][/p]
        [p]As you sit down to enjoy your dinner you hear the barking of a dog in the distance. A shot rings out, and another.[/p]
        [p]You hope your brother will make it home tonight But your hope quickly gives way to fear, because you feel yourself changing into a very different you.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="16" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="43">
    <text>
        [p]You feel a wave of darkness sweep over you. Then, blinking your eyes, you find yourself hunched over, your weight supported in part by your long arms and hands, which are pressed, knuckles to the ground. As you stand erect you realize that your body is covered with furry brown hair and that you are enormous – standing seven feet tall, weighing almost four hundred pounds![/p]
        [p]You walk a few steps, but quickly drop down so you can use your knuckles as two front feet. It's more comfortable that way. You move rapidly though the thick vegetation that covers the mountainside.[/p]
        [p]You stoop down to grab some stalks of wild celery and stuff them into your mouth. There is a stout tree in your way. You reach out and knock it over[/p]
        [p]As you work your way up the mountainside, you notice some other gorillas. They look happy, lounging in the grass and soaking up the sun. Some of them are sitting alone, grunting and belching. Others are picking gnats and lice off each other's backs. On a knoll above them a huge silverback gorilla surveys the scene. He is obviously the leader, you know he might attack you if you tried to join his group. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="46" pos="1">If you decide to approach the group</next>
    <next id="81" pos="2">If you decide to explore elsewhere</next>
  </p>
  <p id="44">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="44"][/p]
        [p]Suddenly you feel your legs drawing close to your body. You look down to see that you are a great white bird with black patches on your wings and tail and a very large orange bill. You're an albatross, sitting on a nest on a tiny island off a mountainous coast.[/p]
        [p]It's bitter cold and a fierce wind is blowing, but you don't mind. You can fly with a windchill of forty below and hardly notice it[/p]
        [p]You feel like taking off and flying a few thousand miles.[/p]
        [p]With a ten-foot wingspan, you can glide effortlessly over the waves, almost forever.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="45" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="45">
    <text>
        [p]You stretch your neck and spread your wings, webbed feet beating the water, paddling at full speed, headed into the wind. Soon your breast is out of the water, your feet slapping a wave top. With a strong beating of wings you're up, whirling above the waves![/p]
        [p]Flying across the endless sea, your memory stirs. You remember that you are really a human, and that whether you will survive as a person depends on whether you can survive as a bird! And you're worried, because you are beginning to tire – you need to rest. In the distance you see an island jutting out of the sea. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="37" pos="1">If you land on the sea to rest</next>
    <next id="90" pos="2">If you fly onto the island</next>
  </p>
  <p id="46">
    <text>
        [p]As you knuckle-walk over to the group, the gorillas look you over. Most of them grunt. Some of them sound friendlier than others. Suddenly the big silverback stands erect. He beats his chest. He roars. The others show their teeth and scream. For a moment you want to run, but you hold your ground. After all, you are a [em]gorilla![/em][/p]
        [p]The silverback starts toward you. Without quite knowing why, you crouch down and fix your attention on a celery stalk. The silverback sniffs at you, then withdraws. A couple of smaller gorillas come closer. You exchange sidelong glances and grunts. Another gorilla throws an arm around you – you have been accepted in the group![/p]
        [p]As the days pass you become close friends with the other gorillas. Your group travels together on the lush green mountain slopes, feeding on succulent plants. Sometimes you find an old nest of twigs, branches, and leaves. Sometimes you make a new one. You are happy playing, resting, and foraging with the others.[/p]
        [p]One day you hear strange noises. Peering through the trees, you see funny-looking little hairless apes. Something about them looks familiar.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="106" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="47">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="47"][/p]
        [p]Suddenly you are human again, back in the runs of the temple. This time you find yourself standing. You try to walk, but your feet seem roted to the floor.[/p]
        [p]The monk sits before you. ``You are doing well,'' he says.[/p]
        [p]``Well, thanks,'' you say, surprised. ``Does that mean I can go now?''[/p]
        [p]``It means only that you are doing well. Tell me, how did it feel when you changed from human to animal?''[/p]
        [p]You think back to that strange moment. ``It was confusing. Sometimes my human memory went against my animal instinct''[/p]
        [p]``Ah, then you would rather have no trace of human memory?''[/p]
        [p]``I'd rather have it completely,'' you say. ``If I could always have remembered that I'd been human, I'd have been an extrasmart animal.'' [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="48" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="48">
    <text>
        [p]``But,'' says the monk, ``knowing you were a human being who is trapped in the body of an animal would be very hard indeed. You might panic. When you are an animal, it is better to be wrapped in the mist of forgetfulness.''[/p]
        [p]``I don't know which would be worse,'' you admit.[/p]
        [p]``Sometimes you must make a decision even when you can't decide,'' the monk says gently.[/p]
        [p]You start to protest, but the monk's eyes are like glowing coals. His voice seems to burn into your brain:[/p]
        [p]``You are about to become an animal again. You must choose whether you will keep your human mind or live without a trace of human memory.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="60" pos="1">If you choose to keep your human memory</next>
    <next id="70" pos="2">If you choose to give it up</next>
  </p>
  <p id="49">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="50">
    <text>
        [p]Instinct tells you that there's something dangerous about a den that lifts itself through the water. As the clay jar rises you slip out.[/p]
        [p]You cruise along the reef, scuttling along with one tentacle over another, looking for either a new den or a juicy soft-shell crab. You poke into a few holes that are already inhabited, and then you smell food on a ledge above you. Using three tentacles at once, you reach higher... lunge... and clamp down on a hermit crab. You scoop it up and pass it from suction cup to suction cup into your mouth.[/p]
        [p]No sooner have you finished eating than a sand shark eyes you for lunch. Turning bright red with fear, you propel yourself away with your jet stream. You know you can't stay ahead of the shark for long. You release a cloud of ink to distract it. Immediately you change color and look for a hiding place.[/p]
        [p]There's a pile of old bottles up ahead. You shoot toward them, but the shark has swum through the ink cloud and is gaining on you. You'll never reach shelter fast enough, and this time you're out of ink![/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="51">
    <text>
        [p]You race to the edge of the meadow, darting through the tall grass. The full moon is flickering through the treetops. You see the farmer's house, the barn, the chicken coop. You hear the chickens. You also see that noisy white-and-brown dog, head resting on his forepaws, sound asleep – at least he seems to be.[/p]
        [p]Your brother trots off to approach the coop from the other side of the barn. You stalk toward the coop. You're downwind from the dog, so there's no danger of his getting your scent.[/p]
        [p]Now, closer, you can see the barn door is ajar; you could slip through and enter the coop from the barn. But suppose the door shuts after you?[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="52" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="52">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="52"][/p]
        [p]You'll just have to risk it. You run toward the door and slip inside. Before you even reach the chicken coop, you hear the dog barking. No time to think – you dash into the coop and grab the fattest chicken. What a racket of cackling, squawking, and flapping! It's enough to scare you out of your wits.[/p]
        [p]``[em]Hey, Blazer![/em] '' A human voice – a man! He'll be running toward the barn. You're scared. Why did you even try this? You wheel and start back toward the door. Suddenly you see the dog – big as a bear, staring at you through the chicken wire, barking madly – trying to bite his way through.[/p]
        [p]You almost drop the chicken in fright as you run into the barn and head for the door. Suddenly you realize that you'll reach the door just about the time the dog does. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="53" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="53">
    <text>
        [p]You dive, chicken and all, behind a big metal smelly thing. A second later, the dog races past – into the chicken coop! In a flash you're outside. Moments later you reach the tall grass, dragging the chicken along.[/p]
        [p][em]Boom![/em]  A loud noise – it came from where you saw the man! A few moments later your brother appears, running toward you. His coat is spotted with blood, but he can't be badly hurt because he darts ahead and breaks a trail for you through the tall thick grass. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="47" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="54">
    <text>
        [p]Cautiously you edge forward. The rabbit's nose is quivering. It senses danger. You instinctively crouch – you've seen a moving shadow on the ground. [em]Hawk overhead![/em][/p]
        [p]You'll never forget the first time you saw a shadow like that. A second later the big red-shouldered hawk swooped down and snatched your sister away.[/p]
        [p]Now you're much bigger. A hawk would think twice about attacking you. Suddenly the hawk dives! You bare your teeth, growling. In an instant the hawk lands, seizes the rabbit, and flaps off through the trees. You're out of danger, but your dinner is gone.[/p]
        [p]You look up wistfully at the moon. Wouldn't it be wonderful, you think, to be a great bird that could soar through the sky...[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="44" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="55">
    <text>
        [p]You're glad you chose to stay in the cool waters – the krill here are very good. You've just finished breakfast, but you gobble up a few thousand more for a little snack.[/p]
        [p]You practice dives and turns, whacking the water with your tail. You arch your body and watch the spray shooting in the air. You dive into the cold depths and cruise in the stillness of the deep Then, rising like a rocket, you breach the surface and blow stale air out of your lungs, sending up a great plume of spray.[/p]
        [p]Cruising, you see a shape on the water that grows larger as it approaches. Maybe it's another whale.[/p]
        [p]But the shape is larger, much larger, than a whale, and most of it is way up out of the water.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="109" pos="1">If you swim toward the moving shape</next>
    <next id="67" pos="2">If you try to get out of sight</next>
  </p>
  <p id="56">
    <text>
        [p]Chances for seizing the crab look slim. Instead of diving, you fly inland, over a pine forest, then over pasture land close to the sea, gaining altitude so as to have a wider field of view. If you were to climb much higher, you would be immersed in the dark, wet, low-hanging clouds.[/p]
        [p]At the edge of the meadow below, you see something that quickens your blood. Eight hundred feet below, a fox has pulled down a plump jackrabbit! Its jugular vein severed, the rabbit lies quivering in the grass. The fox, muzzle bloodied, stands panting, resting after the chase.[/p]
        [p]You dive like a shot! As you close in, your mighty talons stretched to the full, your scream cuts the air. The fox scampers away. The rabbit belongs to you, lord of the air. But as you eat you feel your throat tightening. Your body's becoming smaller, your feathers changing to fur...[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="63" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="57">
    <text>
        [p]You fly over a cluster of old houses, a patch of meadow between two roads, a cemetery, a white church with a spire so high you could almost stretch your talons down and touch it... The bell in the steeple tolls. GONG... GONG... GONG...[/p]
        [p]The sound fades as you fly on over concrete and blacktop, trucks and buses, buildings and cars – always cars, sending up fumes.[/p]
        [p]The sun beating down on the parking lots sets up a thermal, and you take advantage of it to rise high above the ugly sight. Far above the church spires, your powerful eyes survey the people rushing in all directions. There is no food to be had. You pull away from the acrid smell of the cars and chimneys.[/p]
        [p]You bank, swinging your wings, intent on finding your way back to the wilderness.[/p]
        [p]Just after flying over a cow pasture that is being used as a junkyard, you hear a [em]crack[/em]  and a whistling noise, and you feel the pain of death.[/p]
        [p]Someone shot you for sport.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="58">
    <text>
        [p]Once again the wave of darkness sweeps over you. You feel as if you were spinning wildly, and then everything is still. You are [em]you[/em]  again.[/p]
        [p]The monk is sitting there, looking serene as ever. Doesn't he ever get up and stretch or walk around? – you wonder. He must eat, though not very much, judging by his frail appearance. His high cheekbones seem barely covered with skin. His brown eyes are set far back in their sockets.[/p]
        [p]The monk interrupts your thoughts. ``Well, have you been happy as an animal?''[/p]
        [p]``Happy?'' you say slowly. ``I don't know. It felt so different. It's hard...''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="59" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="59">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="59"][/p]
        [p]``Ah, then, you would be happier being a simpler animal. A simple animal of the air, of the land, or of the sea – which?''[/p]
        [p]``Wait a minute,'' you protest. ``What about the guardian and – ''[/p]
        [p]``There is no other way.'' The monk's voice is gentle but firm. ``It is not I who ordains your destiny.''[/p]
        [p]You grit your teeth and answer.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="70" pos="1">If you say you'll be a simple animal of the air</next>
    <next id="63" pos="2">If you say you'll be a simple animal of the land</next>
    <next id="108" pos="3">If you say you'll be a simple animal of the sea</next>
  </p>
  <p id="60">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="60"][/p]
        [p]No matter what it's like to be a dog with a dog's understanding, it's terrible to be a dog when you have human understanding. You know, because that's what happened to you! And you realize instantly that you aren't going to have an easy life as a dog – a poodle in a fancy house in California or a golden retriever curied up before a fireplace in Vermont. No, you can see that you have a hard life ahead.[/p]
        [p]You're a husky – a big strong one. Thank goodness for that, you think, as you look around and see the other six in your team. You're all hitched to a sled, waiting for the command to break it out of the ice. There are three men in fur clothes loading the sled. They have rifles, and you shrink down on your haunches, thinking about how any one of them could shoot you, and no one would care. You quiver as you recall how, when Eskimos get trapped in bad weather and can't find enough to eat, they shoot a dog or two for food...[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="61" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="61">
    <text>
        [p]``That one!'' One of the men is pointing at you. You're quivering and shaking. You must look sick. They might shoot you because they don't want the sled held back by a sick dog! You leap to your feet and stand alert, as if eager to pull the sled. The men exchange a few more words and resume their work. Phew![/p]
        [p]You look over the other dogs, and judge yourself to be stronger and bigger than all of them except the lead dog. Even he is scarcely larger than you. You must be the second dog in the team.[/p]
        [p]Three men and seven dogs across the Arctic tundra. Where are you bound? For what purpose? You have no way of knowing.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="25" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="62">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="63">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="63"][/p]
        [p]You pad through green silky grass, searching for turnip snips and wild rhubarb, and, when you find them, [em]munch, munch;[/em]  you stop, your nose quivering, whiskers trembling. The cool breeze against youir soft nose brings scents of lush spiny growths: berries and blossoms, tart parsnips and skunk cabbage. And you feel the soft coolness of wet earth through your furry hide. Your short legs take you not over but through the land, the clumps and lumps of hardened mud and tufted grass, the rocky, mounded earth. You lap at trickles of water from a spring.[/p]
        [p][em]Snip, snip, chomp;[/em]  you eat again. Then, burrowing in beneath a large flat rock, you sleep, oblivious to the snoring animal beside you, which is, like you, a hairy-nosed wombat.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="82" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="64">
    <text>
        [p]You watch as your mother grabs another salmon and flips it onto the bank. Bones crunch between her teeth as she gobbles it down.[/p]
        [p]You'll never be able to fish the way she can![/p]
        [p]You walk a few feet up the stream bank and plop yourself down on the ground, sucking your paw. Then something catches your eye. What's that over there, next to that rock?[/p]
        [p]It's food! Some kind of salty meat between two thin pieces of spongy white stuff. Crunchy brown sticks with more salt sticking to them. And a moldy old apple – you've seen them before.[/p]
        [p]You don't know it, but you've found the remains of a camper's lunch. It's not as good as fish, but you're too hungry to care.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="91" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="65">
    <text>
        [p]How you hate concrete under your paws! You roar again. The people shrink away from the bars. Some of them laugh. Some of them snicker. One of them tries to roar back. How ridiculous they are! And those who have imprisoned you in this miserable cell, what a stupid lot they are![/p]
        [p]Then you remember your human self; you will be returned to your own human body in three weeks! At least you are safe where you are. Humiliating as it is, you're grateful to be in a zoo. No one will shoot you.[/p]
        [p]Thinking of this, you want to smile. But, since lions can't smile, it comes out as a great big yawn.[/p]
        [p]``Wow!'' shouts a little boy. ``Look at those teeth!''[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="66">
    <text>
        [p]You waste no time breaking into a gallop, ignoring the herd, trying to hold your distance from the charging lion. You stretch your legs, lungs, and heart to the utmost.[/p]
        [p]Then somehow you sense that the lion has quit, his effort spent. You slow your pace and glance back. The king of beasts is slinking away into the tall grass.[/p]
        [p]You're alive and free, but your human memory is taking hold again, and you sweat the cold sweat of fear. If only you could be an animal that no lion would dare attack![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="43" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="67">
    <text>
        [p]You swim away from the moving shape, diving hundreds of feet below the surface, waiting as long as possible before coming up to blow.[/p]
        [p]Deep within the ocean you hear the distant call of another whale. A few moments pass. The other whale sounds a shrill note of distress. Something is attacking it! You know there can be only one predator: the shape you saw is a killer ship.[/p]
        [p]Knowing it may already be too late, you call to the other whale: ``To the depths! Only the depths are safe!'' There is no answering call. But as you swim away from the ship you hear the higher-pitched sound of a much smaller whale. You call back to it, and soon a calf swims toward you. Together you flee the humans, surfacing only to blow, then quickly slipping below the waves. As you dive you feel your human memory beginning to return. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="103" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="68">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="69">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="69"][/p]
        [p]You are an octopus, drifting down toward the ocean floor. As you settle on a rocky ledge you change your color and texture to blend in with your new surroundings. Perfectly camouflaged, you wait until your favorite food – a lobster – approaches.[/p]
        [p]With amazing speed you propel yourself toward it. The lobster wheels on you, pincers wide apart releasing a jet of ink to distract it, you sweep over to the lobster's side. Swiftly you slap one tentacle around its back, another over its rear claws, and a third around its head. In almost the same motion your sharp beak rips open the lobster's soft underside.[/p]
        [p]Your hunger satisfied, you swim off, searching for a den. Like all octopuses, you feel safest when you're hidden in a dark snug place. Ahead of you is a clay jar. You approach it curiously and, with one tentacle, gently explore its inside. It's empty, so you slither over the side into your new home. Curled up in the bottom, you sleep.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="73" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="70">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="70"][/p]
        [p]You take flight from the surface of the marsh. It's a hot summer evening, and you're in search of blood.[/p]
        [p]Instinct guides you toward the house and through the broken part of the screen. You hover over a sleeping girl. As you buzz by her ear she turns. Her arm lashes out and you dart away. You light on a wall, waiting until she's quiet again. You focus on a bare shoulder and dive![/p]
        [p]Silently you set to work, drawing out her rich red blood. The girl swats hard, but you fly out of range. As soon as she settles back down, you land on her hand to finish your meal. This is the best blood yet![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="71" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="71">
    <text>
        [p]Suddenly the girl sits up and switches on a light. Once again you take to the air.[/p]
        [p]``All right, mosquito!'' She stalks around the room, looking for you. You light on the back of her neck and walk slowly down her spine.[/p]
        [p]``Gotcha!'' the girl cries, slapping herself on the shoulder.[/p]
        [p]You move down a little farther.[/p]
        [p]The hand whips around again.[/p]
        [p][em]Splat![/em][/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="72">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="72"][/p]
        [p]As you gaze around at endless, brown grasslands, you notice that you are in a herd of animals with black-and-white stripes. Looking at your legs and your hindquarters, you can see that you are one of them.[/p]
        [p]You leap into motion – prancing through the tall grass, enjoying your speed and strength. The morning sun is blinking through the trees. Ahead is a water hole, spilling over its banks after recent heavy rains.[/p]
        [p]You pause to graze on the sweet grass. The early morning air smells cool and fresh. You breathe deeply and snort. You shiver your hindquarters to shake off the flies, then break into a joyful canter across the plain.[/p]
        [p]As you slow to a trot a new scent reaches your nostrils. You stop short and prick up your ears. You hear nothing, but your eyes register an image that alerts every nerve and muscle.[/p]
        [p]Not far away a lion is crouched, his yellow-green eyes fixed on you. You know he is waiting for the right moment to charge.[/p]
        [p]You want to get back to the herd. Among zebras there's safety in numbers. Should you try to make it? Your chances of outrunning the lion would be better if you ran [em]away[/em]  from the herd, but then you would be even more isolated. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="5" pos="1">If you run toward the herd</next>
    <next id="66" pos="2">If you run the other way</next>
  </p>
  <p id="73">
    <text>
        [p]You awake to an odd sensation. Though you are still in the jar, you're being pulled through the water. Something is carrying you to the ocean's surface. You're curious but very wary. Should you stay in the jar or slip out now?[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="85" pos="1">If you stay in the jar</next>
    <next id="50" pos="2">If you slip out of the jar</next>
  </p>
  <p id="74">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="75">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="76">
    <text>
        [p]You cross an open plain and wander through the acacia groves, breaking off thick limbs with your trunk and munching on leaves and twigs. A giant python slithers out of your path. A leopard leaps in front of you and disappears into the dense undergrowth. Insects swarm about, but they can't bite through your thick hide.[/p]
        [p]You reach a fast-flowing stream and wade in. It's deep and cool. The cool water sloshes against your belly. You suck up a trunkful and spray it over your head. What a good feeling! You wade out on the other side and graze on the tall, succulent grass growing at the water's edge. You trumpet from time to time in hopes that another elephant will hear you. As you reach a wide clearing you are startled to see two humans holding guns. At first you're confused. This scene seems so familiar; yet you know that as an elephant this is the first time you've seen men.[/p]
        [p]``Look at the tusks on this one!'' one of the men cries.[/p]
        [p]Now you know exactly what's going to happen. You turn to run. You hear the gun fire and feel a searing pain in your chest, then another in your head as you sink to your knees. Your massive body crumples on one side. You gasp for air, but you're not breathing. You're dying – the victim of a poacher who is eager to cut off your ivory tusks and sell them.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="77">
    <text>
        [p]After a long day on the trail you feel like a slave sentenced to a short life of hard labor. That evening, after eating your ration of half-frozen seal meat, and before being chained for the night, you start running. The men yell after you. You glance back. One of them has picked up a rifle, but he doesn't fire. They know they can't catch you. You're free![/p]
        [p]After a while you slow to a trot and head south, constantly sniffing the breeze. Though you have just been fed and aren't particularly hungry, you know you must find game. A never-ending search for food is the price of freedom.[/p]
        [p]A scent reaches your nose – a heavy, oily, musky scent. You trot toward it, trying to get directly downwind. The scent grows stronger. You hear noises. In the pale moonlight you can see large, dark shapes of animals – caribou![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="96" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="78">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="79">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="79"][/p]
        [p]You cruise over the river valley. For the sheer fun of it you fold your wings and drop like a rock, accelerating, enjoying the wind whipping your feathers and fanning your head. Then you stretch your wings and pull out into a graceful glide. With an easy motion, flexing, you gain speed and slowly climb, instinctively finding a thermal updraft.[/p]
        [p]Half a mile below, a brown rabbit nibbles some fresh green grass near a pond. Your eye scans the sloping meadow around the pond. The rabbit is quite a way from the briars along the edge of the woods. There are no ground holes or old stumps nearby. Chances look good.[/p]
        [p]You plunge like a meteor, feathers pinned back by the wind, eyes fixed on your prey! Its ears quiver: Does it already sense danger – a slight darkening of the sky, a faint, blurred shadow on the pond, a tiny increase of air pressure?[/p]
        [p]Your talons stretch in expectation. Still plunging – falling so fast that if you were to strike the earth your bones would be crushed – you do nothing to slow your fall. You unfold your wings part way, altering your glide. The distance closes. The rabbit is in full flight, shrieking in terror. Almost upon the quarry, your wings spread fully! [em]Rabbit streaking toward the briars![/em]  You tilt your left wing, bank, stretch, and, extending talons, seize your prey.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="92" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="80">
    <text>
        [p]The door opens and you run out to the lawn. After sniffing the new-mown grass and watching a couple of noisy birds, you lie down in a patch of sunlight and roll on your back, stretching your legs. Ready for a short nap, you've just closed your eyes when you hear a low, throaty growl. Instantly you're alert and on your feet, your tail slashing the air. The neighbor's dog, Rufus, is loose, and he's after you![/p]
        [p]Quickly you're off. The two of you race away from the houses and out into an open field. Your powerful legs move quickly, but Rufus is bigger and faster. This was dumb, you realize; there isn't even a tree to climb. Rufus is coming closer, barking loudly, and you've had about enough of this![/p]
        [p]You wheel around hissing, your back arched and your fur standing on end. Rufus charges. You let him move in until he's just the right distance. Then your claws lash out, raking his nose. Rufus stops short, howling in pain. Hissing furiously, you attack again. The dog runs.[/p]
        [p]You sit down in a patch of clover and clean your paws; then lazily you start home. But as you walk down the street you walk out of your life as a cat. Suddenly you are very far away and very much larger! [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="72" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="81">
    <text>
        [p]You turn away from the other gorillas and ramble down the mountain slope, weaving through the dense vegetation. Suddenly you feel a searing pain as you fall flat on your back. One of your legs is suspended by a wire noose that grips ever more tightly as you try to wiggle free. You dig your fingers under the wire, trying to pull it loose. But your great strength is no help. The wire cuts into your fingers. You sink back in despair. You lie there helplessly as the sun arcs across the sky. Every time you try to wriggle free, the noose tightens, cutting your flesh.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="8" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="82">
    <text>
        [p]You can feel yourself stretching, your arms and legs growing longer. Strength is surging into your human body. Laughing, you leap into the air and come down – in the temple! At first you shudder to be back inside the huge dark room, but then you realize you can still move. The shadow of death no longer clings to you.[/p]
        [p]``How was it, being a simple animal?'' the monk inquires gently.[/p]
        [p]``It was awful – to be able to [em]feel[/em]  but not [em]think[/em].''[/p]
        [p]``Ah, you would rather not think and not feel...?''[/p]
        [p]``No, I'm – ''[/p]
        [p]Were you asleep? you wonder. It doesn't seem so, though you're rubbing your eyes as if you were.[/p]
        [p]The monk sits in the lotus position, impassive as before. ``Go to the door,'' he tells you, ``but do not cross the threshold.''[/p]
        [p]Careful to stay inside, you go to the open door and blink in astonishment. The stairs of the temple are covered in deep drifts of snow. In fact, everything is covered by snow except for the statue of the temple guardian. Months have passed![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="89" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="83">
    <text>
        [p]You swim away and cruise just below the surface. You weave and dive, searching, always searching. You chase after a school of bluefish. They dart over a sandbar. Too much trouble to follow them into shallow water, you think, and head out to sea. You're starving now. You haven't eaten in minutes.[/p]
        [p]There's a sunfish! After it! Got it! That's better. You feel good. Except that you're [em]very hungry.[/em]  You speed along, looking for a big fish, something fat and meaty and oily – a big yellowfin tuna, And there it is! You put everything you have into the chase.[/p]
        [p]Nothing else matters until you sense a shadow above you... the shadow of black-and-white... [em]Orca – killer whale – coming at you![/em]  You dive instantly. Then, with a sharp flip of your great tail, you turn and accelerate, your jaws wide, your hundreds of razor-sharp teeth ready for their deadly work. You should be headed right for the whale's underbelly. Where is it?[/p]
        [p]As you turn your head to see, the whale's jaws clamp like a great vise on your midsection. You writhe and bite, bite, bite – on water.[/p]
        [p]Your dull brain blanks out.[/p]
        [p]You [em]were[/em]  a shark.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="84">
    <text>
        [p]Keeping a safe distance, you watch the wolves try in vain to reach the caribou. With quick gulps and bites the bear manages to devour half the carcass. Then he looks around, licks his chops, and lumbers away.[/p]
        [p]The wolves are instantly on the remains of the feast. You try to join them, but they savagely drive you back.[/p]
        [p]Even with all your human intelligence there is nothing more you can do but what dogs have always done; you sit forlornly, howling...[/p]
        [p]What is happening to you?[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="6" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="85">
    <text>
        [p]Though the jar is moving, it feels safe inside. The ocean grows warmer as you near the surface. Steadily the jar continues to rise. Then suddenly your den is ripped from the water, and a hand reaches into the jar and grabs your body. You cling desperately with all of your tentacles, but you're not strong enough to resist. The hand yanks you out of the jar and throws you on the deck of a boat.[/p]
        [p]Around you are dozens of jars. And beside each one lies an octopus. Some are already dead, the others weakening. The hot sun is beating down on you; you know you can't survive long out of water. Your eyes rise up like periscopes. The edge of the boat isn't far. Using all your strength, you crawl to it. In a moment you're over the side and back in the cool water![/p]
        [p]As you swim toward the bottom a strange thing happens. You become aware of your own escape, moving through the ocean as if you were part of it. Your swimming never felt this effortless, you think, and slowly you realize that your human memory has returned![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="47" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="86">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="86"][/p]
        [p]``All right,'' you say reluctantly, ``I guess I'll take one more chance at being an animal, but can you promise me that I'll survive and come back?''[/p]
        [p]His face stern and impassive, the monk replies, ``I can't guarantee anything. You may return [em]if[/em]  you can stay alive for three weeks as an animal. If you don't want to take that chance, then you must remain here with me for three weeks.''[/p]
        [p]``And then what?'' you ask.[/p]
        [p]``The trails have been completely covered by the snow. In three weeks time hikers will pass this temple. They will guide you down the mountain.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="87" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="87">
    <text>
        [p]``Well, then,'' you say, ``I'll just stay here for three weeks.''[/p]
        [p]The monk rises to his feet. Though he looks old and frail, he walks to the temple door as gracefully as a dancer. ``Sometimes being human can be as dangerous as being an animal.'' He points to the snow-laden mountainside that rises steeply above the temple. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="93" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="88">
    <text>
        [p]You fly along the seacoast, which becomes rockier and more rugged as you glide downwind. From time to time you plunge upon a small bird, a young woodchuck, or a fat mouse.[/p]
        [p]You pass over the town and villages, a stinking factory, a wharf that smells of dead fish. You look down at the humans on the boats and on the docks, at the hundreds of gulls hovering above them. You glide over the harbor, keeping an eye on a pair of cormorants winging over a weathered rock-spit of land. You eye a crab just below the surface as it emerges from under a rock. Will it scoot back into hiding before you can pluck it out of the water? [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="31" pos="1">If you go for the crab</next>
    <next id="56" pos="2">If you decide not to waste your energy, but to fly on in search of something better</next>
  </p>
  <p id="89">
    <text>
        [p]``Have I been asleep since summer?'' Your voice, silenced for so long, is husky.[/p]
        [p]``You have not been asleep,'' the monk replies. ``[em]You've been a tree.[/em] ''[/p]
        [p]You try to imagine yourself as a tree – standing, rooted, half your lower trunk covered with snow, your branches and twigs quivering in the winter wind, [em]un-feeing[/em] .[/p]
        [p]The monk breaks into your thoughts. ``You have shown courage and new understanding. The guardian of the temple is pleased with you. You will be allowed to return to your human life – unless you choose to become an animal again.''[/p]
        [p]``Why would I do that?''[/p]
        [p]The monk smiles. ``Few humans are given the opportunity to experience life as another creature. You may never have this chance again.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="86" pos="1">If you say you'll try being an animal again</next>
    <next id="114" pos="2">If you say you don't want to risk being an animal again</next>
  </p>
  <p id="90">
    <text>
        [p]You fly to the island and set down on a stretch of grass not far from the sea. As you fold your great wings, you feel yourself blacking out. Something is happening that means it is not yet time for you to be you.[/p]
        [p]Moments later the light of day reaches your tiny pink eyes, and there is no doubt about what you are: standing on four short legs, your long flat snout sticking over a trough – you are just one other pig in the lot, snorting and gobbling some kind of slop. In a minute the trough is empty. You flop down in the mud and grunt and snort; you roll on your side as the other pigs mill and push and spatter mud over you. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="23" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="91">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="91"][/p]
        [p]In a few minutes you walk slowly back to your mother's side. Bears can digest almost anything, but you're feeling queasy. You've just had your first junk food, and unless you learn how to fish better, it won't be your last.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="92">
    <text>
        [p]You rip the bloodied rabbit to shreds and gulp down the meat. Satisfied, you flap up to the rocky ledge, where you doze until a certain restlessness overtakes you. Then, with strong wing beats, you rise over the river valley until you can see the ragged countryside for many miles on either wing.[/p]
        [p]You bank and set your course toward the sea. Beneath you are forests and fields, farmhouses, and white churches with their spires reaching up. Only racing white whispers of clouds are above you.[/p]
        [p]Soon you see the blurred outline of a city. You start to swerve away, but check yourself and continue on. Perhaps it is your human memory that pulls you closer.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="57" pos="1">If you fly on toward the city</next>
    <next id="88" pos="2">If you fly along the seacoast</next>
  </p>
  <p id="93">
    <text>
        [p]You cannot answer – you are in such awe of the mountain. In the clear, dry air it seems so close, you feel as if you could reach up and cap the jagged peaks with your hand. The sky is such a deep blue above the mountaintop that you feel as if you were staring, not at the sky, but into space itself. Plumes of snow are blowing off the upper slopes.[/p]
        [p]The strange old man beside you has been waiting for you to finish your reverie. Seeing you look at him, he says, ``Never have I seen the snow lie so deep on the mountain. Spring will be here soon, and the sun is growing stronger. I do not know when, but in the season that is now upon us, an avalanche will bury this temple. It is foretold. Think of that before you decide whether you will stay here three weeks.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="98" pos="1">If you say you'll stay anyway</next>
    <next id="32" pos="2">If you say you'll be an animal for three weeks</next>
  </p>
  <p id="94">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="94"][/p]
        [p]You race through the mesquite thickets, instinctively dodging the tangle of branches. Your legs are torn and bloody from the spiny thorns, but your spirit keeps you going. All of your energy is directed to saving the herd.[/p]
        [p]As you burst out onto open ground and gallop toward the ravine, you see the herd nearing the edge. You run alongside, nipping and snorting. As you pull ahead of the lead horses you rear up on your hind legs, striking out sharply with your hoofs. They wheel away. None of them dares to approach you.[/p]
        [p]For a moment they stamp and snort in confusion. A crack of thunder echoes through the sky, and one of the yearlings bolts away. Swiftly you're at him, turning him back to the others. The herd slowly settles down, and you lead them back through the canyon.[/p]
        [p]The wind has shifted. The storm is over. In the clear night air you stand alone, once again watching your herd. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="58" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="95">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="96">
    <text>
        [p]Slowly, cautiously, you approach. One of the animals snorts and looks around nervously. You freeze. In a few moments you can move closer. But as you look over the scene, you lose heart. There are no helpless calves, nor any animals that smell sick or old enough for you to cut out of the herd.[/p]
        [p]A big bull caribou with powerful antlers turns his head toward you. You realize you can't tackle these animals alone. You need a team, a pack to hunt with.[/p]
        [p]Forsaking the caribou, you resume your course southward, moving at a brisk trot. Perhaps you'll scent an Arctic hare you can run down, or find a pack of wolves to hunt with. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="104" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="97">
    <text>
        [p]You join the other elephants headed along an ancient route to the north. The herd stops to feed, but there is very little to eat. Other elephants have stripped bare most of the trees along the way.[/p]
        [p]Later, when you are hot and thirsty and reach a stream bed, you find the water has dried up. You watch the other elephants paw at hard, sunbaked clay. With your mighty front legs you are able to dig down several feet A pool of muddy water appears at the bottom of the hole. You eagerly suck it up through your trunk. After a long time you're able to get a gallon or so, not really enough.[/p]
        [p]The herd moves on. As the days go by, some of the old elephants weaken. Without adequate water they are unable to cool their great bodies. One old cow drops to her knees, then crumples to the ground. Some of the largest animals try to lift her by sliding their tusks under her body. It's no use. She takes one great gasp of air and lies still.[/p]
        [p]Two elephants stay awhile with the body. The others move on. You follow them.[/p]
        [p]You reach another dried creek bed. The other elephants stand waiting. You are in a safe area, but you are worried because of the lack of water.[/p]
        [p]Then you hear the other elephants' rumbling sounds of contentment. Soon you understand. The sky has grown darker. Before long, rain is falling in torrents! The dry season is over! For a while you and the others in your herd will be well-fed, safe, and happy, as lords of the earth should be. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="103" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="98">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="98"][/p]
        [p]``I'll take my chances staying here,'' you say. ``Very well,'' says the monk. ``So it shall be.'' For the next two weeks you share the monk's rice and tea, nuts and dried fruits.[/p]
        [p]Each day you look up at the mountain anxiously. The sun shines brightly, and the days grow warmer. The great snowpack still hangs over the temple.[/p]
        [p]Then, near the end of the third week, while drinking your morning tea, you hear a sound like thunder. You throw open the great wooden door. A mountain of snow is hurtling down on you![/p]
        [p]Over the roar of the avalanche you hear the monk's voice. ``[em]In your next life you will be the most rare and sacred animal of the mountains – a snow leopard, never to be seen by human eyes.[/em]''[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="99">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="100">
    <text>
        [p]As you and the others pull the sled along on hard-packed snow, you feel strength and energy flowing through your body. You are a strong dog in the prime of life. The wind is bitter. The breath of the dogs is like puffs of smoke. Icicles form around your nose and mouth, but your coat is thick and warm.[/p]
        [p]At noon the men stop to rest. The other dogs become restless, and you do too. You smell food and realize how hungry you are. The men are unpacking seal meat. They throw a chunk to each dog – the largest to the lead dog. He bites off a piece and smugly lifts his head and looks away while he wolfs it down.[/p]
        [p]This is as good a time as any: You dash in and grab the lead dog's meat. It takes a moment for him to understand what's happened. Then he charges, his brutal jaws open, razor teeth bared.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="101" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="101">
    <text>
        [p]But you have a plan. Using your human mind, you seize the chunk of meat and swing it around, slapping the lead dog in the face as he lunges for your throat Confused, he stops short, torn between wanting to grab the meat and wanting to attack you. In that instant you strike, seizing his throat and biting deeply enough to get a grip, taking care not to sever the jugular – you don't want the men to decide you're a killer.[/p]
        [p]Sensing that he is helpless, the other dog squeals. You hear the men talking, coming closer. You tighten your grip and twist the other dog onto his side. He goes limp, but he's not dead. He is submitting to your authority! You relax your grip. The other dog slinks away.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="102" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="102">
    <text>
        [p]In a few minutes the men hitch up the team. This time you are in the lead position. The men are talking excitedly. They must be impressed by how you conquered the other dog. You are pleased with yourself. Next time you'll get the biggest piece of meat The trouble is, you think, you're still only a dog.[/p]
        [p]That night, as you are dozing off to sleep, you feel a great change taking place in your body, in space and in time.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="16" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="103">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="103"][/p]
        [p]You're surrounded by silence and darkness. You can't feel or see anything. Then from out of the void you hear the sound of your own breath. As you concentrate on keeping your breathing deep and even, a feeling of calm fills you.[/p]
        [p]You can sense your body now. You are sitting, legs crossed, your spine perfectly straight Once again, you are in the temple, and like the monk, in the lotus position. But unlike him, you can't stand up.[/p]
        [p]``You have achieved a state of meditation,'' the monk says.[/p]
        [p]``I still can't move,'' you answer.[/p]
        [p]``Indeed, it is good.''[/p]
        [p]``Good? Does that mean the guardian will release me?'' you ask, trying to keep the excitement out of your voice.[/p]
        [p]``Not yet,'' the monk replies. ``But you have learned to focus your being. It may serve you well in your next incarnation.''[/p]
        [p]``But – ''[/p]
        [p]``There is more you must understand,'' the monk breaks in. ``You must learn about leadership.'' You start to protest, but the monk stops you merely by looking into your eyes. ``Now,'' he says gently, ``would you be a leader of animals or be guided by another animal?''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="105" pos="1">If you say you will lead other animals</next>
    <next id="19" pos="2">If you say you will be guided by another animal</next>
  </p>
  <p id="104">
    <text>
        [p]Later, during the night, you hear the sound you've been listening for – the howling of wolves. You trot toward them, but approaching from upwind, you fail to pick up the scent before bursting into a clearing and suddenly finding them – six white wolves, facing you, teeth bared![/p]
        [p]You are about to run for your life when one of the wolves pricks up his ears, sniffing. The others follow his lead. Instinctively you do the same. There is a new meaty scent in the air! As if on signal, the wolves set off on a trot, and you join them.[/p]
        [p]The source of excitement is not far away – the pack quickly finds a huge polar bear standing over a fresh-killed caribou calf! You and the wolves edge toward the bear, prancing around it, growling and snapping. The bear roars at the wolves, then turns and tears a hunk of meat from its prey. The wolves dart in closer. You watch eagerly as the bear tries to feast on his kill and keep back the wolves at the same time.[/p]
        [p]Here's your chance, you think. You could dash in and bite the bear's flank, distracting him long enough for the others to get the carcass. The pack would certainly accept you then. Should you try it? [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="111" pos="1">If you try to attack the bear</next>
    <next id="84" pos="2">If you stand back and play it safe</next>
  </p>
  <p id="105">
    <text>
        [p]You are standing on a bluff. A blustering wind is blowing through your thick mane. The sun has just set, and a full moon is rising over the rim of the canyon. The horses grazing below are in your herd. You are their leader – a powerful chestnut stallion.[/p]
        [p]To the north you can see clouds gathering. You raise your head into the wind. You can smell the approaching storm. The herd is growing restless.[/p]
        [p]Suddenly a tremendous bolt of lightning shatters across the valley. Wild screams come from the herd as the horses break east across the canyon. Terrified, they run blindly toward a jagged ravine. You've got to cut them off before they reach the edge![/p]
        [p]Without hesitation you tear down the side of the canyon. Stones fly out from under your hoofs as you skid down the steep, twisting trail. Reaching the canyon floor, you explode into a gallop. You're the fastest horse in the valley, but the herd is well ahead of you. You may not be able to turn them back in time![/p]
        [p]There's one chance. By cutting through the thicket of mesquite, you may be able to save them – it's the shortest route to the ravine. But in the near-darkness you could easily twist a hoof in the tangled brush.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="94" pos="1">If you cut through the mesquite</next>
    <next id="29" pos="2">If you continue along the canyon floor</next>
  </p>
  <p id="106">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="106"][/p]
        [p]Hidden in a dense thicket, you watch the hairless apes. They fascinate you; your human memory is rekindled. These are humans. The objects they hold are cameras; they are filming the silver-back gorillas.[/p]
        [p]The other gorillas have caught the human scent and have retreated deep into the jungle. Your instinct is to join them, but you long for human company.[/p]
        [p]As you peer through the brush you notice a woman looking directly at you through her binoculars. ``I can't believe it,'' she says to a companion. ``Normally it takes months before they'll let themselves be seen. This one looks almost friendly. Get the cameras!''[/p]
        [p]Lonely without your gorilla companions, you decide to give the people a show. You let them film you foraging, grooming, and playing. After a while you begin to enjoy it. You're becoming quite a star! If only you could tell the humans that inside, you are really one of them. Even when you sleep, you dream of being a person again...[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="58" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="107">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="108">
    <text>
        [p]A poet called you ``a pair of ragged claws.'' And so you are, and nothing more, because nothing occurs to you but hunger; searching; and, in fear, retreating. Instinctively you dig into the sand to keep the waves from overturning you.[/p]
        [p]What brought you out from your hiding place, the rock ledge near the shore?[/p]
        [p]What brought you out? A morsel of food?[/p]
        [p]You ate a mussel and a worm, but you don't remember it, or anything else, because you are only a crab, living in the present, the ever-changing present, and you don't know why you scuttled back under the rock ledge as an eagle dived toward you.[/p]
        [p]You are safe in the shallow water now, though only for now, in the ever-changing present...[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="82" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="109">
    <text>
        [p]You swim toward the shape, swinging your great tail. With one kicking motion you surface. Brilliant light meets your eyes: the sparkling ocean. You feel the soft wind against your body. Half your body rises out of the water, and you can see ocean for miles around. You arch over, slapping the wave tops, knocking whole waves askew and sending fountains of spray in all directions.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="110" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="110">
    <text>
        [p]At that moment a terrible image is fixed in your left eye. A ship is headed toward you! A pole is mounted on the bow. Sailors are standing by it. Coils of rope are wound around a giant spool. From your dim memory – is it your whale memory or your human memory? – you recall that though some people have tried to stop others from killing whales, especially the rarest whales, the hunt goes on. It means nothing to the whalers that they are killing the largest creatures that ever lived on earth. They have no understanding of the mind of a whale – [em]your[/em]  mind.[/p]
        [p][em]Whoosh![/em][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="113" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="111">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="111"][/p]
        [p]Surely you're faster than this big, lumbering brute. While the bear is tearing flesh from the caribou, you dash in and sink your teeth into his hindquarters.[/p]
        [p]It takes less than a second to release your grip and get your legs in position to spring out of reach, but in that flash of time the bear smashes a huge paw down on your neck. You hear your bones snap, and nothing more.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="112">
    <text>
        [p]You're tired of waiting for salmon to come along. You're going to catch some your way! But you have to wait until your mother stops watching you so closely.[/p]
        [p]In a few minutes a skinny half-grown bear tries to nudge your mother from her fishing spot so he can sit there. Your mother's not having any of that! With a growl she turns and starts pushing the younger bear out of the way. Here's your chance![/p]
        [p]Gingerly you wade into the stream and scramble onto a rock. You lean over the water and dip your paw in. Then you pull it out again. Now what did your mother do? Did she use her claws? You wish you could remember.[/p]
        [p]There's a huge one! Without thinking, you launch yourself into the stream – and find yourself in much deeper water than you'd expected. You're being carried downstream![/p]
        [p]The current's carrying you faster and faster. You can't right yourself, and your head keeps going under. You're bruised from bumping into rocks. Salmon crowd against you in their frantic rush upstream, but you can't get a breath to catch one. Where is your mother? Why didn't you stay next to her? As the water drags you along you wish that you knew how to swim better...[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="69" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="113">
    <text>
        [p]Too late. You feel terrible pain as a steel harpoon tears deep into your side.[/p]
        [p]You thrash mightily – twisting, diving, then breaching the surface. But now the fountains of spray you send up are colored with blood. You may be dying, but you fight to live. Then you are overwhelmed: Your human awareness has suddenly returned. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="58" pos="1">If you wish you were back in the temple again</next>
    <next id="40" pos="2">If you are filled with thoughts of revenge and wish you could be the fiercest creature on earth</next>
  </p>
  <p id="114">
    <text>
        [p]``No, thanks,'' you say. ``I've had enough of being an animal. It feels great being human again. I want to stay this way.''[/p]
        [p]``Very well,'' says the monk. ``But you will not be able to find the trail through the snow. I will guide you down the mountain. Come, it is safe for you to cross the threshold now.''[/p]
        [p]Slowly you step out of the temple. The dazzling white mountains rise around you. All your senses seem sharper. You've never felt so alive. Then your eyes fall on the statue of the guardian, and a familiar chill goes through you. You take a deep breath and stare into the great stone face.[/p]
        [p]``Hurry!'' the monk calls from below. You look back for the last time and sprint down the broad stone steps.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="115" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="115">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="115"][/p]
        [p]For three days you follow the monk down steep, winding trails. Finally, just below the snow line, you reach a beautiful valley covered with wild flowers. That night you stay in a monastery where you meet travelers who offer to guide you to the city of Katmandu. From there you'll be able to take a plane home.[/p]
        [p]In the morning you bid the monk good-bye and thank him for his kindness. In turn he gives you a Tibetan [em]thanka[/em], a sacred painting.[/p]
        [p]``I will also leave you another gift,'' he says, ``this one from the guardian of the temple. You can neither see it nor touch it, but it will stay with you forever – the gift of friendship with all animals.''[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
</content>
