<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content xmlns="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu http://zagor.hu/xsd/sor.xsd">
  <p id="back_cover">
    <text>
        [p][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="background"/>
  </p>
  <p id="background" display="Background">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="0"][/p]
        [p]You have been kidnapped by an insane geneticist and turned into a hulking beast![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="1" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="1">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="1"][/p]
        [p]The blue Mercedes screeches to a stop beside you.[/p]
        [p]``Get in!''[/p]
        [p]The heavyset man wearing a black homburg isn't kidding. Before you can run, a man jumps out of the back and shoves you inside. The car speeds off. None of the passing motorists notices – [em]you've been kidnapped![/em][/p]
        [p]Wedged in the backseat between two thugs, you try to think about what you can do.[/p]
        [p]``Look, you must think I'm someone else – some rich kid you can get ransom for – ''[/p]
        [p]``Shut up. We want [em]you[/em].'' The muzzle of a .45 jabs into your side.[/p]
        [p]The Mercedes swerves around a corner, headed toward an outlying district.[/p]
        [p]A blindfold pulls tight over your eyes. ``You were looking curious,'' a voice says.[/p]
        [p]It must be about ten minutes later when the car stops and you hear the door opening.[/p]
        [p]``Get out!'' A firm grip is on your arm.[/p]
        [p]When your feet touch the ground, you tear the blindfold off, twist out of the man's grip, and start to run![/p]
        [p][em]CLUNK![/em]  A gun butt comes down on your head. You're out cold. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="68" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="2">
    <text>
        [p]Dr. Firenze gives you a sedative, so you hardly feel it when he injects you with his genetic formula. It isn't long before you begin to feel strange sensations. Within a few hours it's clear what's happening: you're shrinking – and that's good news. The bad news is that you're not getting back the fine, young body you once had. Instead, you're becoming spindly and smaller than you were, and you still have hair all over! What's worse, you're growing a tail! And when you try to talk, all you can make are little screechy sounds![/p]
        [p]You can't help but think about what it is you're becoming, especially when you notice you've developed a tremendous craving for bananas.[/p]
        [p]The hospital staff provides you with everything they think you want, even going so far as to install a trapeze in your room. One day while you're hanging by your tail you hear footsteps coming down the hall. You drop down on your bed just at the moment Dr. Firenze, Amanda, and Mr. and Mrs. Vandergraft walk into your room. You sense that they've come because Dr. Firenze has done everything he can for you, and it's time for the next stage in your life to begin.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="96" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="3">
    <text>
        [p]When everyone is reasonably used to having you around, and after you've helped clean up the kitchen, you all sit down in the living room for a family conference. There aren't any seats big enough for you and you don't want to break anything, so you just sit on the floor in front of the fireplace.[/p]
        [p]Your spirit has been lifted by coming home, most of all because you've been accepted by your family and know everyone still loves you, even though you're a monster.[/p]
        [p]But now suddenly you feel very let down and depressed. How can you go to school the way you are? No matter how nice your family is, you're going to be nothing but a repulsive and terrifying sight to everyone who sees you – at best an object of curiosity, like some freak.[/p]
        [p]Your head droops, your brain feels numb, you don't know what to say. You've never felt lower than you do right now.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="7" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="4">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="4"][/p]
        [p]Dr. Nair holds up his hand. His thin mouth lengthens into a smile. ``It's too late. I've already implanted you with the genes of a young gorilla, who was himself implanted with genes of a giant bear.''[/p]
        [p]``Wha- ?''[/p]
        [p]``Now,'' Dr. Nair interrupts in a brisk and businesslike tone, ``someone will bring you dinner, some books, and a TV set. I want you to feel relaxed...''[/p]
        [p]Before you can reply, this strange and terrifying man walks out the door. A lock turns.[/p]
        [p]You run to the window. You're on the second story of a run-down, old brick building. The window faces onto a paved inner courtyard. Two cars and a truck are parked below. The building encloses the courtyard, except for the entrance, where an armed guard is posted.[/p]
        [p]There's a bathroom attached to your room. You look inside, but it offers no means of escape. Your heart sinks. It's not going to be easy to get out of this place. Then, the real shock comes as you glance at your arms. They seem thicker and longer than you remember, and a downy growth of dark brown hair has appeared on the back of your hands. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="81" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="5">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="6">
    <text>
        [p]``It's Vargas!'' Meyerstraub yelps.[/p]
        [p]Vargas, you remember, is the man Meyerstraub wanted you to frighten.[/p]
        [p]``Get us out of here!'' Meyerstraub screams at the pilot as you clamber on board.[/p]
        [p]The jet engines roar even before you have the hatch shut. The plane starts down the runway.[/p]
        [p]The helicopter, traveling faster, swoops closer.[/p]
        [p]``Duck!'' the pilot yells.[/p]
        [p]A hail of bullets rips through the fuselage! One of them nicks you in the back. For the first time you see the blood of a monster – your [em]own[/em]  blood![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="105" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="7">
    <text>
        [p]``It's terrible what you've been through,'' your mom finally says. ``I only hope the police can catch the man who did this to you.''[/p]
        [p]You nod.[/p]
        [p]``I can see you're feeling down,'' your dad says. ``It's perfectly understandable, after your ordeal.''[/p]
        [p]``I think it would be a good idea for you to see Dr. Rasmussen,'' your mom says. ``He's a very good psychiatrist, and maybe he can help you adjust to the situation you're in.''[/p]
        [p]``Yes, that's a [em]very[/em]  good idea,'' your dad says. ``I think you'll find it very helpful to talk to Dr. Rasmussen.''[/p]
        [p]You hardly stir from your place on the floor. At last you look up. ``Sure, Mom, Dad... anything you say.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="13" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="8">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="9">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="9"][/p]
        [p]Every day you keep growing. It's near the end of the first three weeks when you first bump your head while walking into the bathroom. It doesn't hurt, it just knocks a strip of wood off the transom, but it's this fact – bumping your head – that makes you realize you've been pretending you're still the regular, normal kid you were before. Finally you dare to look at yourself in the full-length mirror on the back of the bathroom door. There you are, or there's [em]part[/em]  of you – for you have to squat and wiggle from side to side to see all of yourself.[/p]
        [p]You let out a scream that rattles the windows and echoes through the yard. Your body is as massive and hairy as a gorilla's, but your face is far more frightening: Your black-capped snout is like a grizzly bear's. Your jaws and two sharp, slightly curved fangs remind you of a saber-tooth tiger, and your huge, overhanging brow looks like that of a hammerhead shark.[/p]
        [p]You slap at the bathroom door. It flies off the hinges. The mirror shatters. You roar in agony and rage. There is no doubt what's happened: You are no longer the person you were – YOU ARE A MONSTER! [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="90" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="10">
    <text>
        [p]Another car is traveling fast down the road. Best to keep out of sight for now, you think, ducking behind a thick clump of bushes. Peering through the branches, you see that the car is a police car. So is the one behind it, and the one behind that! They're stopping in front of the house. One car blocks the entrance. Two cops jump out. Each has a hand on his holster as if ready to draw. They must have been tipped off about Dr. Nair and figured out that he's the one who kidnapped you. But they showed up too late. If only they'd found out about him three weeks ago, you'd still be the happy, normal kid you were, instead of the weird, hulking monster that you are now.[/p]
        [p]You hear a cop yelling from inside the courtyard. One of the others pulls his gun. Should you come out of hiding and explain what happened? After all, the cops are on your side – except that if you show yourself the way you look, one of them might just blow you away![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="87" pos="1">If you come out of hiding</next>
    <next id="14" pos="2">If you stay hidden</next>
  </p>
  <p id="11">
    <text>
        [p]``I've been thinking about your future,'' says Mr. Vandergraft. ``The way I see it, you can never be really happy – never lead a normal life – unless you can be turned back into yourself again.''[/p]
        [p]``But how can that ever happen?'' you wonder aloud.[/p]
        [p]``Well, for one thing, there's a new unit at Federal Hospital, specializing in genetic change. The director, Dr. Firenze, is practically a genius. He might be able to return you to your normal self. But I have to tell you, it may be risky. If it doesn't work...''[/p]
        [p]Mr. Vandergraft's voice trails off, but you don't have to hear his words to know what he was about to say. He's thinking that you might end up in an even more monstrous form than you're in now.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="89" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="12">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="13">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="13"][/p]
        [p]Two days later you find yourself in the office of Dr. Karl Rasmussen, the renowned psychiatrist, He is a large man who sprawls, rather than sits, on the leather chair he pulls out from behind his desk.[/p]
        [p]``Sit wherever you like.'' He motions you toward a leather sofa and an oversized chair next to it. ``Maybe you'd like to sit on the floor and lean back against the sofa.''[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH[/em],'' you say softly, and sit on the floor so you're now eye-level with the famous doctor.[/p]
        [p]``You certainly are quite a monster,'' he begins.[/p]
        [p]``I'm not a very happy monster,'' you say. ``I can never lead a normal life. I can't go to school looking like this – everyone will be afraid of me. Or make fun of me.''[/p]
        [p]The doctor nods. ``Yes, that may happen for a while, but not for long.''[/p]
        [p]``Really? Why?''[/p]
        [p]``Because you'll know how to handle the situation. '' Rasmussen's eyes twinkle while he talks, as if he is delighted at thinking how well you will adjust.[/p]
        [p]``How do you mean?'' you ask.[/p]
        [p]``Well,'' the doctor replies, ``imagine that you were a normal student and one of the other kids was the monster. How would you react?'' [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="82" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="14">
    <text>
        [p]You stay hidden in the brush while the police search the house. You have nothing better to do, so you practice learning to talk again. Your mouth has changed so much, your tongue feels as if it's tied in knots. The cops seem to be taking forever. You wonder what they thought of the splinters of wood they found upstairs where you smashed down the door to your room.[/p]
        [p]Finally they come out, muttering among themselves. They drive off, but you know they'll be keeping a close eye on the place until they find Dr. Nair. Meanwhile, you've got to figure out what to do – you need as much food as three grown men, and you don't have any money.[/p]
        [p]Maybe someone would take you in as a pet. You could go home, of course, but your family would be just too broken up to learn that you've turned into a monster. For now it seems better to have them just think you ran away.[/p]
        [p]You wander along, keeping behind hedges and walls. You're in the richest part of town, and most of the houses are set well back from the road. You've only gone a short way when you have to duck through a hedge to keep from being seen. You almost run into a woman cutting flowers in her garden.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="54" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="15">
    <text>
        [p]``My men will show you to your room,'' Meyerstraub purrs. ``It's specially made for you out of concrete and steel. You'll get all the good food you like, so you ought to be pretty happy.''[/p]
        [p]And so you're in prison once again, besieged, lonely, and endangered.[/p]
        [p]Your bed is soft, but you can't get much sleep. In the morning the guards come for you, and once again you are brought before Meyerstraub. Smiling and cheerful, he says, ``Well, Monster, I hope you slept well. Now it's time for you to go to work.''[/p]
        [p]``What do you mean?'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``Do you know who I am?''[/p]
        [p]``You're a big crime boss,'' you answer.[/p]
        [p]``Not a big boss. I'm the [em]biggest[/em]  – the king – you got that?''[/p]
        [p]You nod your huge, shaggy head.[/p]
        [p]``And I'm king because I get what I want. You know how I get it?''[/p]
        [p]``No,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``I get it by using the carrot and the stick. I appeal to two major human traits: greed and fear. And I do that by doling out lots of money, and an equal amount of terror.''[/p]
        [p]You sit there dumbfounded by what Meyerstraub is telling you. Yet you also know that he speaks a dark truth: Money and terror are the tools by which he has amassed so much power.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="25" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="16">
    <text>
        [p]You continue on over the brow of the rise and across a spacious, sloping lawn graced with magnificent trees. As you walk past a sprawling copper beech tree, a voice calls down from above.[/p]
        [p]``I see you, Monster.''[/p]
        [p]You try to see who's calling down from the branch – and find a girl, perhaps ten or eleven years old.[/p]
        [p]``I see you too,'' you answer. ``Do you live in that big house?''[/p]
        [p]``Uh huh,'' the girl replies. ``My name is Amanda Vandergraft, and I like you.''[/p]
        [p]``Like me? That's amazing! Everyone else hates me. Why would you like me?''[/p]
        [p]``You didn't hurt my dogs,'' Amanda says, ``so I know you're a nice monster.'' She jumps down from the tree and lands a few feet away from you. ``You're nice, but you're ugly.''[/p]
        [p]You hang your head. ``I know.''[/p]
        [p]She reaches up with her little hand and touches your right paw. ``I've read all about you in the newspapers, and you're on all the news programs on TV. The police are looking for you.''[/p]
        [p]``I know -''[/p]
        [p]``Why haven't you gone home to your family?''[/p]
        [p]``I don't think they could handle it,'' you reply, ``knowing their kid has turned into a monster.''[/p]
        [p]``I see what you mean,'' says Amanda. ``Well, you can stay at our house for a few days. We have lots of room and plenty of extra food in the freezers. It's up to you.''[/p]
        [p]``Your parents wouldn't mind?''[/p]
        [p]``I think I can talk them into it,'' Amanda says firmly.[/p]
        [p]You're grateful for Amanda's kindness; at the same time you're feeling a little homesick. You're not sure what to do.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="65" pos="1">If you decide to accept Amanda's invitation</next>
    <next id="55" pos="2">If you decide to go home</next>
  </p>
  <p id="17">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="18">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="18"][/p]
        [p]A few days later you start school again. None of the kids tease you or make comments. But you almost wish they would. They're too respectful, as if they've all been told you're very fragile and they [em]have[/em]  to be nice. Even your best friends talk to you very softly and respectfully, as if you're a very old person visiting the school.[/p]
        [p]But gradually things loosen up. By the end of the year you've been elected president of the Student Council and, of course, captain of the football team. You've more friends than ever and, feeling good about yourself once again, you learn more too.[/p]
        [p]When you graduate, you write a book, [em]My Life as a Monster[/em]. You appear on all the talk shows and in music videos (you cut a few records of your own), and make it big in the movies and on the stage. In just a few years you earn three Grammys, five Emmys, two Tonys, and a couple of Oscars. By then lots of people are calling you ``that lucky monster.''[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="19">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="20">
    <text>
        [p]Another week has passed. You're still in police custody and being guarded twenty-four hours a day. You miss your family and friends, but you just can't face their seeing you as a monster – at least not now. You've been looked at, examined, photographed, and talked to by dozens of detectives, politicians, scientists, and reporters. All these people have asked you so many questions, you have a stiff tongue from answering.[/p]
        [p]You've learned things too. You've found out that the cops know Dr. Nair is the evil scientist who transformed you, that he's still at large, and that everyone is worried what he'll do next. One reason they want to catch him is that he's the only person in the world who might be able to reverse your condition, except for maybe a doctor at one special hospital.[/p]
        [p]The mayor himself arrives and informs you of their decision. ``Look,'' he begins, ``you're an innocent victim of this man. And we're doing everything in our power to bring him to justice. You are entitled to your freedom, but for your own safety as well as others', we can't give it to you. You would frighten too many people. If you were found wandering around loose, sooner or later some crazy nut would shoot you.''[/p]
        [p]``What about my civil rights?'' you say. ``You have no right to keep me locked up!''[/p]
        [p]The police commissioner shakes his head. ``The fact is, you have no civil rights,'' he says brusquely. ``They only apply to people – and you're not a person anymore – you're a monster!'' [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="102" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="21">
    <text>
        [p]It's four A.M. You're standing outside the bedroom door in the Key West oceanfront villa of Guillermo Vargas, who is supposed to be second only to Meyerstraub as the most powerful crime boss in the world.[/p]
        [p]Two men with machine guns are downstairs. Meyerstraub has warned you that they'll finish you off unless they hear Vargas screaming. That'll be the only proof they'll accept that you've done your job.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="23" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="22">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="23">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="23"][/p]
        [p]You carefully open the door to Vargas's bedroom. It's enormous, and you can see quite well by the reflected glow of the security lights in the yard. Vargas, wearing fancy striped pajamas, is sprawled on his stomach in the middle of a canopied four-poster bed. He's almost surrounded by pillows. You wonder whether he has a gun under one of them.[/p]
        [p]The room is cluttered with electronic equipment, and you count three different telephones. But what most attracts your attention are the hundreds of packs of currency stashed on the floor. You inspect them closely. Each pack contains at least a hundred fifty-dollar bills! You wonder whether they're counterfeit, or if they're real – stolen from banks![/p]
        [p]Vargas stirs fitfully in his sleep. He mumbles something, but you can't make out the words. He seems about to wake up. You've got to act now.[/p]
        [p]You glance out the window. It's about a twelve-foot drop to the soft grass. Maybe you can jump for it and escape from the thugs waiting on the stairs below.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="116" pos="1">If you continue to follow the plan and roar to terrorize Vargas</next>
    <next id="49" pos="2">If you try to jump for safety</next>
    <next id="111" pos="3">If you try to call the police to tip them off</next>
  </p>
  <p id="24">
    <text>
        [p]You agree to submit to a genetic implant, and you're given a room in the Advanced Genetics wing of Federal Hospital. While you're waiting for Dr. Firenze to begin his treatment, you walk restlessly around your room. Pretty soon you hear weird sounds – sort of a [em]cloppity-clop, clop[/em]  in the hall. You peer out to see what's going on. A man – or some kind of creature – is walking by, with orderlies marching along on each side of it (or him). The creature is walking on four legs, and the lower part of his body looks like that of a small horse, but the upper part looks like the upper body of a man! You remember seeing creatures like these, called centaurs, in your mythology books in school.[/p]
        [p]A nurse walking by stops to talk to you. ``Quite an achievement, don't you agree?'' He gestures toward the centaur, which has reached the oversized elevator farther down the hall.[/p]
        [p]``Is that Dr. Nair's work, too?'' you ask.[/p]
        [p]The nurse shakes his head. ``No, that's the work of Dr. Firenze – didn't you know?''[/p]
        [p]This news hits you like a bombshell. You realize that, although he's working in Federal Hospital, Dr. Firenze is an [em]experimenter[/em]  and may not be very different from Dr. Nair! Who knows what experiment he has in mind for you![/p]
        [p]You're not going to wait around to find out. You go back to your room, grab your toothbrush, and head for the exit. Everyone stares as you hurry past. People scream and run, knocking over carts as they scramble to get out of your way.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="106" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="25">
    <text>
        [p]``You'd think,'' Meyerstraub continues, ``that you could scare people enough simply by pointing a gun at them. But this is a tough business. Sometimes it's very hard to convince them. Do you follow me?''[/p]
        [p]``Sure.'' You've only been half listening, because you've been quietly inching forward, transferring weight to the balls of your feet and calculating the possibilities of springing onto Meyerstraub and holding him hostage.[/p]
        [p]``Well,'' the crime king continues. ``I have a certain rival. Guillermo Vargas, who is very smart, and very tough. He has a powerful organization. I want him to work for me, but he refuses. Do you see the problem?''[/p]
        [p]You nod, casting a glance at Meyerstraub's two guards. They look pretty relaxed.[/p]
        [p]``Now as I say, Guillermo is very tough,'' Meyerstraub continues, ``but he's very superstitious. If I warn him that he'll sleep uneasily if he doesn't cooperate, and then if he has a real [em]nightmare[/em], that might bring him around.''[/p]
        [p]``Sure, that makes sense,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``So,'' Meyerstraub says triumphantly, ``you're going to appear in Guillermo's bedroom – while he's sleeping – and you will be his nightmare!''[/p]
        [p]``But isn't he guarded?'' you ask.[/p]
        [p]``His guards can be bribed. I provide the money; you provide the terror, got it?'' [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="30" pos="1">If you jump Meyerstraub</next>
    <next id="98" pos="2">If you decide to play along with his plan</next>
  </p>
  <p id="26">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="26"][/p]
        [p]You try to answer, but your mouth is no longer the same shape as it used to be, and all that comes out are grunts and garbled words.[/p]
        [p]``Can you understand English?'' the chief asks.[/p]
        [p]You nod.[/p]
        [p]He takes off his cap and scratches his head. He looks around at his men as if hoping one of them will suggest something, but they all seem equally dumbfounded.[/p]
        [p]``Okay,'' the chief says after a while, ``Robertson, take your squad in and search the place. Mullen and I will take this creature back to the station house.''[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH[/em],'' you answer.[/p]
        [p]Three cops move in with their guns ready; you have no choice but to step into the van.[/p]
        [p]You sit quietly on the floor. There's nothing you can do. A heavy, wire mesh screen separates you from the cops. You're sure that you could smash open the door and jump out, but what would be the point? Sooner or later they'd capture you and either shoot you down or lock you up behind bars that even you couldn't break out of.[/p]
        [p]You're depressed. It's bad enough being a monster, but not being able to talk and explain things makes it twice as bad. ``[em]Ah cn tak[/em] – I can talk -'' you say, struggling to form words that once came so easily.[/p]
        [p]One of the cops whirls around. ``Hey, it can talk!''[/p]
        [p]``That ain't talking,'' the other one says.[/p]
        [p]You'll have to practice when you're alone. You've just got to learn to talk once again.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="20" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="27">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="28">
    <text>
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]'' You let forth a mighty roar and advance toward your foe.[/p]
        [p]The grizzly roars back – and charges! He lunges to bite your neck, but you deflect his head with a single chop of your arm. It would be more than enough to knock a lumberjack flat on his back, but the grizzly isn't even fazed. He comes at you again.[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em] '' You bring your massive paw down on the bear's neck, but you miss as he ducks and grabs your midsection. He's trying to crush you![/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]'' Now you're mad. You kick the bear's shins with such force, the animal bellows with pain. Then with one mighty heave you throw him over your head and hurl him to the ground.[/p]
        [p]The grizzly lies there, stunned. Then he slowly gets to his feet. He walks up to you, his head bowed in submission, and rubs along your legs like a house cat. Out of the shadows up ahead, two other adult grizzlies and a couple of half-grown cubs appear. They make no move to attack and seem content to follow their leader in his submission. You have not only been accepted by the bears as one of them, but you've been acknowledged as their leader![/p]
        [p]The other bears group and start into the forest. They travel only a dozen feet, then stop and look at you. They want you to come with them. You're amazed and happy. None of the humans at the lumber camp have wanted to be your friends, but these bears do. Maybe you should go with them. Maybe it would be the best life for you – living like a bear. It's tempting to join the grizzlies. You certainly don't want to stay in this lumber camp anymore, especially with Fenwick out to get you. On the other hand you're not a bear, after all, and you long for human companionship.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="103" pos="1">If you go with the grizzlies</next>
    <next id="33" pos="2">If you run away by yourself</next>
  </p>
  <p id="29">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="30">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="30"][/p]
        [p]Your mighty leg muscles contract, and in a spasm of unleashed energy you lunge at the crime boss. Horror flashes across his face as he raises his hands in defense. Your claws reach not for his neck but for his shoulders, so that in one deft motion you can twist him around and use him as a shield.[/p]
        [p]Only a single second is involved, but time seems to slow to a crawl. It seems as if the trigger-happy goons should have plenty of time to fill your body full of holes. Perhaps they are too stunned, but that long second passes without a bullet being fired, and in the next instant you have Meyerstraub in your claws. You whirl him around and confront the guards. ``Drop your weapons!''[/p]
        [p]``Drop them,'' the crime king commands.[/p]
        [p]Their machine guns hit the floor.[/p]
        [p]``Very good, very good,'' Meyerstraub says. ``You are more talented than I realized. Now that I know that, I'm going to reward you.''[/p]
        [p]Surprised by his sudden turnaround from a frightened coward to a smooth-talking underworld boss, you grip his shoulders even more tightly.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="95" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="31">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="32">
    <text>
        [p]You let Meyerstraub down gently to the ground. ``I'll accept your offer, subject to my conditions,'' you say. ``First of all, I want you to order your entire security force in here so you can tell them I'm in charge. That way, there won't be any mistake about it.''[/p]
        [p]Meyerstraub looks up at you. He straightens his rumpled jacket. ``Sure, I'll summon everyone over the public-address system I control from my desk.''[/p]
        [p]You follow the crime king closely toward his desk, but you never reach it. A hail of bullets knocks you down. As you fall you turn and see the guards. They had hidden pistols.[/p]
        [p]It takes a lot of bullets to kill a monster, and you live long enough to hear Meyerstraub say, ``Good work, boys. Monsters are just too dangerous to keep around the house.''[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="33">
    <text>
        [p]You decide not to go with the grizzlies but instead go off by yourself, determined to make it on your own.[/p]
        [p]Though you're protected by a growth of shaggy hair, you've no desire to endure the bitter cold winters of the interior. Knowing the climate is milder along the coast, you head west through the wilderness, living on deer, rabbits, and wild berries.[/p]
        [p]You have to learn to hunt and move through the forest like any other wild animal. You notice things most people don't – faint impressions in the grass, broken sticks, a spoor – that mark the trail of your prey. You sleep wherever you please – on a mossy patch, a bed of leaves, or in a hollow under a cliff. It doesn't matter. No animal would dare attack you.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="40" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="34">
    <text>
        [p]Outside the window you see the flashing lights of the first police cars. Then you hear shouts in the yard below. Lights shimmer around the room – reflections from searchlights. Then voices, footsteps, running, shots![/p]
        [p]``[em]Freeze![/em]''[/p]
        [p]An eerie silence.[/p]
        [p]``Take them away!'' someone shouts.[/p]
        [p]You feel easier – the thugs are in hand![/p]
        [p]Then a rapping at the door. ``Walk out slowly with your hands over your head!''[/p]
        [p]That's just what you do, carrying Vargas above you.[/p]
        [p]The cops do a double take, but they get the picture fast.[/p]
        [p]``You're not just a monster,'' the chief tells you as he reaches up to pat your shaggy shoulder. ``You're a hero!''[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]  I mean, thanks,'' you say humbly.[/p]
        [p]You know you'll always have some problems as long as you remain a monster. But at least now you have proven that you are not a threat to society.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="35">
    <text>
        [p]One evening you come upon a small cabin. You peer in the window. No one is there. The door isn't locked, so you push it open and walk in. You cast your eyes at the bunks, the kitchen, and the big locking chair facing a fieldstone fireplace. Seeing this cozy cabin makes you long for human companionship.[/p]
        [p]You wave your paw over the wood stove in the corner – it's still warm – someone must have been here earlier. Then you notice a newspaper lying on a table. The headline says: MONSTER SIGHTED NEAR TELEGRAPH PEAK. There's a very fuzzy picture of you. A smaller headline is really alarming: MOUNTIES HUNT MONSTER.[/p]
        [p]You slump down on a couch that runs along the wall opposite the fireplace. It creaks and groans under your weight. You groan, too, because you've just about given up all hope of getting back to the way you were. You're not a criminal, but you're being hunted like one. It makes you feel like crying. Then the idea of a monster crying makes you laugh![/p]
        [p]Suddenly the cabin door opens.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="71" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="36">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="37">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="37"][/p]
        [p]After a few days at the logging camp, you can see why they wanted you to work here. With your enormous strength you can throw huge logs around as if they were pieces of kindling wood. Most of the time you work at carrying heavy machinery and supplies over rough terrain where even a tractor can't move. Joe, the foreman at the camp, is a nice enough fellow. ``I don't ask questions about the men working for me,'' he tells you. ``I just ask how much work they've done each day. Of course, you're not a man, but I'm going to treat you the same way.''[/p]
        [p]You feel a little better, but not a lot better. Although some people act decently toward you, you aren't able to make friends with anyone. People are just too afraid of you – afraid you'll suddenly [em]act[/em]  like a monster. And then there's Mike Fenwick. He used to be the leader around this place, and he doesn't like the fact that, next to you, he looks like a weakling. You figure it's just a matter of time before he makes a move against you.[/p]
        [p]One day you're cutting down small trees with chain saws. You're so much stronger than the others, you start doing their work too. Climbing down in a hollow, out of sight from the others, you notice Fenwick working on a stump.[/p]
        [p]``I'm having trouble with this,'' he yells over the roar of machines.[/p]
        [p]``I'll help you,'' you say, ambling over. As you start cutting, something makes you look up – just in time to see Fenwick swinging at you with his chain saw![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="108" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="38">
    <text>
        [p]``Yes. He's living at a house in Elm City – about fifty miles from here. My men tracked him down by tracing purchases of lab equipment. He set up a lab in the house he's bought, and if I'm not mistaken, it's only a matter of time before he kidnaps someone else and turns him into a monster!''[/p]
        [p]``If only I could get my claws on him,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``This is his picture.'' Zena holds out a Polaroid photo of a man standing on the front porch of a large white house.[/p]
        [p]``But that's not Dr. Nair!'' you exclaim. ``I'd recognize him anywhere!''[/p]
        [p]Zena smiles. ``You were fooled, just as the police were. You forget this man is a genius – he was able to give himself just the right injection of genetic formula to cause his face to change.''[/p]
        [p]``Then how do you know it's Dr. Nair?''[/p]
        [p]``Voice analysis,'' Zena says. ``We got hold of a tape of a speech he made at the university a few years ago, before he took up his criminal ways. Then last week we made a tape of his voice when we reached him on the phone. Computer analysis of the two was conclusive.''[/p]
        [p]``That's incredible!'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``It's good news for another reason,'' says Mr. Vandergraft. ``It means Dr. Nair has gotten so advanced in his methods that he can probably turn you back into the person you were.''[/p]
        [p]``But how can we make him do that?''[/p]
        [p]Mr. Vandergraft looks sterner than you've ever seen him.[/p]
        [p]``We'll [em]make[/em]  him,'' he says.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="64" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="39">
    <text>
        [p]``If there are genetic-transplant techniques that can change one's body,'' you say, ``there must be ones that can change one's personality. Isn't that right, doctor?''[/p]
        [p]``Why, of course,'' Dr. Nair says, squirming as he speaks. He acts more afraid of you now than he did when you were a monster.[/p]
        [p]``Then you shall transplant yourself – not to change your body, but to change your personality – from that of a psychopath to that of a decent human being.''[/p]
        [p]``But I can't do that.''[/p]
        [p]``You must,'' Mr. Vandergraft says sternly.[/p]
        [p]Dr. Nair lets forth a squeal as if he'd been stuck by a pin.[/p]
        [p]``What's so bad about becoming a decent person?'' Amanda demands.[/p]
        [p]Dr. Nair's eyes widen. He looks at her, imploringly. ``[em]My brain![/em]  No! I can't change part of my brain without changing all of it. I would lose my skills at genetic manipulation.''[/p]
        [p]Mr. Vandergraft steps up to the strange little man. ``That's just as well, doctor. That's just as well.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="76" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="40">
    <text>
        [p]Occasionally you pass another lumber camp or a hunter's cabin. From time to time you cross a logging road. Finally you reach a highway. You stand near the edge of the road and watch a big truck roll by. It weaves crazily for a moment, then slows, then speeds up as it rounds the bend. The driver must have seen you. You walk along the road a way, ducking into the brush when a car or truck appears. Up ahead you hear the sound of machinery. You round the bend and see a crew at work repairing the road. One of the workers looks up. He yells. The others stare at you, dumbfounded. One man runs toward his truck. He reaches inside and yanks a heavy-gauge shotgun from under the seat.[/p]
        [p]You waste no time slipping into the woods. You trot a bit, dodging through the trees, then scramble up a steep, rocky slope. You're safe, but you've been reminded again that most people fear you. It's a general truth, it seems: What people fear, they tend to hate.[/p]
        [p]You continue on for the next few weeks, heading west and living off deer and small game. You try to keep clear of the roads and settlements, but the region is becoming more populated as you get nearer to the coast.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="35" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="41">
    <text>
        [p]``Don't shoot!'' you cry. ``I'm [em]human![/em]''[/p]
        [p]The man doesn't reply until he has his rifle unsnapped and leveled at you.[/p]
        [p]``That ain't what's in the papers,'' he says. ``What about that guy Fenwick up at Twin Lakes Camp? He says you tried to kill him and he had to hold you off with a chain saw.''[/p]
        [p]``That's a lie! He was out to get me – he wants to frame me.''[/p]
        [p]``Then why did you run away from the camp?''[/p]
        [p]You bury your great head in your paws. ``I was miserable there.'' You throw up your paws in despair and then quickly lower them as the man nervously fingers his rifle. ``Everyone hated and feared me, just the way you do!''[/p]
        [p]The man rubs his stubby beard for a moment. ``Look, I don't hate you, but you've got to admit you're frightening.''[/p]
        [p]``See, that's what everyone thinks!''[/p]
        [p]The man lowers his rifle so it's just pointing at the floor near your feet. ``I'd feel more comfortable,'' he says, ``if you'd just sit over on that bunk in the corner. Then I can get some soup going on the stove. I've worked up quite an appetite out hunting.'' He looks at you curiously. ``Do you eat regular food?''[/p]
        [p]You nod. ``I'd love some.''[/p]
        [p]The hunter gets out some cans from a cupboard and starts opening them. ``Okay,'' he says as he works. ``Maybe we can reach an understanding, then we'll have some soup.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="84" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="42">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="42"][/p]
        [p]Out of the corner of your eye you see shadowy figures lurking in the bushes, but no glint of any weapons. When you reach the limo, you squeeze into the back, moving Meyerstraub around to shield yourself as much as possible.[/p]
        [p]``Tell the driver to go,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``To the airstrip,'' he squeaks.[/p]
        [p]The limo roars off – still no shots are fired.[/p]
        [p]Ten minutes later, as the car drives through the valley far below Meyerstraub's hideaway, you're relieved to see the airstrip up ahead. The same plane that brought you here is sitting outside the corrugated tin shack that serves as the airport building.[/p]
        [p]``Pull up real close,'' you tell the driver.[/p]
        [p]You see the pilot looking out from the cockpit. You scan the airport shack but see no sign of any of Meyerstraub's men. It seems almost too easy. You get out with the human luggage under your arm and start up the three-step portable staircase next to the door of the plane.[/p]
        [p]Suddenly there's a [em]thap-thap-thap-thap-thap[/em]  in the sky – a helicopter swoops toward you![/p]
    </text>
    <next id="6" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="43">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="44">
    <text>
        [p]You plan to get up in the night and do a little hunting. Otherwise, you'd have to finish off all of your host's supplies by breakfast time.[/p]
        [p]``I've been thinking about you,'' Watkins says. ``It ain't good hiding out from the law all the time. I know. Enough time has gone by so I think I can go back without being caught, and I think you better go back too.''[/p]
        [p]``I'd like to, but what could I do?'' you ask. ``People hate me. They fear me and treat me as if I were -''[/p]
        [p]``- a monster?'' Watkins completes your sentence for you. ``Yeah, well, that's what you are, of course.''[/p]
        [p]``If only I could track down Dr. Nair – he's the evil scientist that did this to me,'' you say. ``He's the only one who can reverse my condition.''[/p]
        [p]``If you're ever going to get back to the way you were, you're going to need money,'' Watkins says gravely.[/p]
        [p]``I agree, but -''[/p]
        [p]``I've got a couple of ideas. My brother-in-law works for the Apalachicola Circus – they're the second biggest one in America now. They'd pay you plenty.''[/p]
        [p]``I've always liked the circus,'' you say. ``It might be fun to be in the show.''[/p]
        [p]``My other idea,'' Watkins says, ``is to get a movie contract. You could make a million in half a year if you're lucky.''[/p]
        [p]``Yeah – if I'm lucky.''[/p]
        [p]``Well, what do you think? Whatever you decide, I'll be your agent. Just give me twenty percent of what is paid to you for landing you the job.'' Watkins is all smiles now. He looks like a little kid who's excited by a new toy.[/p]
        [p]You finish your soup and lay into the stale carrot cake Watkins set out on the table. You're tired of living alone in the wilderness, and you sure could use a million dollars to help you get cured. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="61" pos="1">If you decide to join the circus</next>
    <next id="50" pos="2">If you decide to try to land a movie contract</next>
  </p>
  <p id="45">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="46">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="46"][/p]
        [p]Early one day you leave the bears and set out on your own, heading southwest, toward the coast. Your shaggy coat has grown so thick that you hardly notice the blustery winds blowing out of the north, even though they sometimes bring sleet and rain, sometimes snow.[/p]
        [p]One morning you poke your snout out of a den you've dug out under some rocks and find the ground covered with a foot and a half of snow.[/p]
        [p]Though winter has arrived, you soon find yourself liking it, because it's easier to track game when there's snow on the ground. Roaming across the country in search of food, you revel at the sight of the majestic mountains, the great stands of spruce and fir, the ice-clad streams, and the white, puffy clouds scooting across the sky. You breathe great gulps of pure, cold, pine-scented air. You're so glad to be alive and free that you let out a roar of delight. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="59" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="47">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="48">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="49">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="49"][/p]
        [p]You work your way quietly to the French doors leading out onto the balcony. They're open to let in the breeze off the ocean. You step out on the balcony and look down. It's quite a drop, but you'll be landing on grass, not concrete, and once on the ground you should have no trouble. The dogs are tranquilized, and Vargas's two guards at the gate have already been paid their bribes and are out of the picture. Meyerstraub's thugs are still waiting for you at the bottom of the stairs. All you have to do is run out the gate and slip into the dense brush around the corner. The thugs won't dare follow you.[/p]
        [p]You heave your great bulk over the railing and jump.[/p]
        [p]You land harder than you'd expected – with a loud thud. A stabbing pain goes through one leg It's broken! You thought that you would have no trouble because of your massive bones. You didn't realize that big animals fall faster and land harder than little animals.[/p]
        [p]You look up but can't focus at first. Gradually you notice Vargas staring down from the balcony. Then you see Meyerstraub's thugs coming out the front door. The only question is who will shoot you first.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="50">
    <text>
        [p]``A movie contract – that's for me!'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``I don't think you're making a mistake,'' Watkins says.[/p]
        [p]``But how do I get there without being seen?''[/p]
        [p]``No problem,'' Watkins replies. ``I have a Winnebago – borrowed it from a friend of mine. I pay a farmer to let me keep it behind his barn. It's about ten miles away over the ridge.''[/p]
        [p]It's a four-day trip from British Columbia to Hollywood, and once you get there you have to stay in the Winnebago (which is not even air-conditioned) while Watkins tries to convince a movie producer he has a great monster for the screen. It's hard to get an appointment with these producers, much less get a contract from them, and Watkins is delayed even more because he has to disguise himself and get phony identification in case the cops are still looking for him.[/p]
        [p]At last he lines up a meeting between you and the casting director of a movie being made – [em]Swamp Creature on the Loose[/em]. You're hired on the spot. The work is easy. All you have to do is walk around the set, roaring every now and then, while the movie people set off smoke bombs that are supposed to look like mists rising up from the swamp.[/p]
        [p]You get pretty good pay for making the film, but the movie turns out to be a bomb at the box office.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="72" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="51">
    <text>
        [p]Watkins stares right into Tazewell's eyes. ``The monster gets ten percent of the gross plus five percent for me.''[/p]
        [p]Tazewell is on his feet, his face so red, you're afraid he'll have a heart attack. ``What do you mean – this is robbery!''[/p]
        [p]Watkins answers in a low tone, but it's very firm just the same. ``It's not robbery at all – it's the best deal you ever had, and you know it. With the monster you'll double your business in no time.''[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]'' You let out a roar of agreement.[/p]
        [p]Tazewell practically jumps out of his chair, then he bursts out laughing. ``I still say you're a thief, Watkins, but you're on. Hold out your paw, Monster, and we'll shake on it.''[/p]
        [p]It's not easy for you to shake hands with humans without breaking a few of their hand bones, but you remember that you're basically civilized, so you're very careful.[/p]
        [p]Tazewell and Watkins toast to their business deal, while you wolf down a few big chunks of meat that were meant for the tigers. Suddenly it occurs to you that Watkins has decided to take more of your pay for himself instead of the twenty percent he mentioned originally. You decide to let this pass, however, because he did such a good selling job with Tazewell. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="75" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="52">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="52"][/p]
        [p]Once again you lie writhing and moaning while your body undergoes horrendous changes. But this time, though the experience is still frightening, you feel hope. You can feel your snout shortening, your body shrinking. Your two-inch-long fangs fall out, and new, normal teeth come in. Shaggy hair falls off your body. From time to time you brush it off your bed.[/p]
        [p]You reach the point where you're half monster and half human. Then nothing more happens. I hope it doesn't stop here, you think. But soon you begin changing again, faster than ever.[/p]
        [p]Only a few days later, Zena, all the Vandergrafts, and Dr. Nair, himself, still under guard, are once again standing around your bed. Everyone is smiling, even Dr. Nair. Amanda has brought a big mirror into the room. You look into it and grin – you're you again! You scream with delight in your regular voice. You're still a little weak and shaky, as if you were just getting over the flu, but you've never felt happier in your life![/p]
        [p]A nurse rolls in a cart and you all celebrate with cake and ice cream.[/p]
        [p]``I still have the appetite of a monster,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``You look as nice now as you used to look nasty,'' says Amanda.[/p]
        [p]``Now what shall we do about Dr. Nair?'' asks Mrs. Vandergraft.[/p]
        [p]``We certainly can't just let him loose,'' Mr. Vandergraft says.[/p]
        [p]``I have a better idea,'' you say.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="39" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="53">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="54">
    <text>
        [p]``[em]Ahheeek![/em]'' the woman screams louder than you thought anyone could. She starts running toward her door, yelling for help every step of the way.[/p]
        [p]A maid opens the door and sees you. She screams even louder than the woman who was cutting flowers.[/p]
        [p]You know the cops will soon be on their way to that house, so you cut back through the hedge and lope along the side of the road at a good clip, not even trying to avoid being seen by the cars and trucks passing by. You keep your eyes on where you're running, but you hear the horns honking, brakes screeching, and people yelling out their windows.[/p]
        [p]You cut down a side street. There aren't many houses here, just woods and fields on one side and a huge rolling lawn on the other Scattered here and there around the lawn are enormous trees Beyond the lawn, perched on a knoll about a hundred yards from the road, is a huge house made of brick and fieldstone. It has six gables, four chimneys, and a red tile roof. Beyond this mansion is more lawn and then thick woods. The people who live here must be [em]really[/em]  rich![/p]
        [p]You race across the lawn, keeping well away from the house. You figure that if you get over the rise ahead and reach the woods, you can keep clear of the cops who will be swarming the place where you were first spotted.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="101" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="55">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="55"][/p]
        [p]You're anxious to get home, but it seems best to call first and prepare your family for the shock. Your monstrous heart beats at a tremendous rate as you reach into a phone booth and dial your number.[/p]
        [p]``Hi, Mom, it's me,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``Oh, at last!'' she cries. ``It's so good to hear your voice, though it does sound a little strange – are you all right?''[/p]
        [p]``Yes, Mom... sort of. I'll be home soon and tell you all about it.''[/p]
        [p]``Well good, darling I don't want to hold you up talking, I can't wait to see your face again. Can't we pick you up in the car?''[/p]
        [p]``No, Mom, I'll get home by myself ''[/p]
        [p]``Will you be safe?'' she asks[/p]
        [p]``Don't worry, Mom. Nobody's going to jump me.''[/p]
        [p]``Well then, please hurry home – and we'll talk about it later.''[/p]
        [p]``Just one thing I want to tell you before I get there, Mom.''[/p]
        [p]``What's that, darling?''[/p]
        [p]``I've become a monster.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="78" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="56">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="57">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="58">
    <text>
        [p]The next three weeks are very relaxing. The Vandergrafts couldn't be nicer The cops have given up searching in the area. You've grown stronger than ever – feasting on everything your monstrous stomach craves – and you've gotten into terrific physical shape racing the German shepherds around the grounds. Amanda has even taught you to play tennis She started out beating you every time, but lately you've been smashing the ball down the line so hard she can't even reach it, much less get it back over the net. On the other hand, she still beats you in swimming races in the pool. Your monstrous arms churn up a lot of waves and foam, but they can't move you through the water as well as human arms could.[/p]
        [p]Mrs. Vandergraft has been giving you French lessons (your strangely shaped mouth makes it easier for you to speak French than English!) and Leonie, the cook, has taught you how to make what she calls monster pie. It's mostly chocolate.[/p]
        [p]All in all, life couldn't be more pleasant. Still, you're restless. Great as life is, you know you can't stay with the Vandergrafts forever. The other members of the family know this too, and one evening all of you discuss it at dinner.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="11" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="59">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="59"][/p]
        [p]Years have passed since you left the bears and began to roam the forests and mountains alone. Only rarely have you caught sight of human beings, and even more rarely has one of them seen you. More often, hikers come upon your tracks. They measure and marvel at them. Legends about you spread far and wide – some of them fanciful, some of them true. Most people call you Bigfoot. But, of course, that's not your name. Only you know who you really are.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="60">
    <text>
        [p]One paw on the weasel-faced thug who's threatening you would be all you'd need to subdue him, but you'd take fifteen or twenty machine gun slugs in your chest before you could lay a claw on him. Powerful and monstrous as you are, there's nothing to do but back up.[/p]
        [p]``Just what do you think you're doing?'' you say.[/p]
        [p]The thug smiles. There's a wild look in his eyes as he advances a step toward you, brandishing his gun, his finger on the trigger. ``Do what I say!'' he screams. ``We're taking you to Buck Meyerstraub.''[/p]
        [p]``Who's he?'' you ask.[/p]
        [p]Your question brings forth a brainless cackle of laughter. ``You don't know the name?''[/p]
        [p]You shake your head.[/p]
        [p]``Meyerstraub is the biggest crime boss in the Caribbean – maybe the world.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="92" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="61">
    <text>
        [p]Three weeks later you are in the office of J. Taylor Tazewell, owner of the Apalachicola Circus. Watkins transported you the thirty-three hundred miles from British Columbia in his Winnebago van. Where he got it is a question you may never get the answer to, but you can't help wondering if he's resumed the type of activity that got the law after him in the first place.[/p]
        [p]Tazewell is a short, chubby-faced man in his fifties, with thinning red hair and an oversized mustache. His office is cluttered with boxes and papers, and the walls are plastered with photos of circus acts. He doesn't even get up from his spindle-backed chair or take his feet off his rolltop desk when Watkins brings you in.[/p]
        [p]``Good morning, Mr. Tazewell,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]Tazewell waves his corncob pipe in a little circle by way of acknowledgment. He looks you up and down, then smiles with satisfaction. ``You are some monster,'' he says. ``With you around, we're gonna become the most famous circus in the world.''[/p]
        [p]``That's just the way I figured it,'' Watkins says.[/p]
        [p]``What's more,'' says Tazewell, ``we'll see you get room and board and a hundred bucks a month bonus.''[/p]
        [p]Watkins stiffens. ``That ain't the way it's going to be, Tazewell.''[/p]
        [p]The circus owner wheels in his chair. ``What do you mean?''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="51" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="62">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="62"][/p]
        [p]Mr. Vandergraft makes all the necessary arrangements for you to enter Federal Hospital and be seen confidentially by Dr. Firenze. Louis, the chauffeur, drives you in the family's Rolls Royce. Of course, you take up nearly all the backseat and extra floor space, so Amanda, who has come along to keep you company, sits in the front with Louis. The public is very curious to know where you've been since you disappeared after your escape from Dr. Nair's house.[/p]
        [p]The genetic unit of Federal Hospital has been alerted to your impending arrival, and when the Rolls pulls up in front of the special entrance at the west wing of the hospital, security guards come out to escort you. They have cleared a couple of hallways and are able to lead you to your bedroom without your being observed by anyone other than staff doctors and nurses, who have been sworn to secrecy.[/p]
        [p]You've just settled down in the oversized chair that's been installed in your room when Dr. Firenze, chief of the unit, enters. He hardly gives you time to get out of your chair as he steps briskly forward, his hand outstretched.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="69" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="63">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="64">
    <text>
        [p]The next morning brings you your chance to confront Dr. Nair: You're sitting across from him in Mr. Vandergraft's office. Two plainclothes security men stand on either side of the evil scientist.[/p]
        [p]You want to shred him with your claws, but he looks so different – thin-faced with brown eyes instead of blue ones – that you can't believe he's the same man. But as you watch him fidgeting in his chair, you observe the same evil expression on his face, the same gestures of his hands, and then, as he speaks, that same high-pitched, nasal voice.[/p]
        [p]``What do you want of me?'' he squeals. ``Let me go. I have my rights.''[/p]
        [p]Zena waits until Dr. Nair has calmed down.[/p]
        [p]``You're going to turn the monster back into a person,'' she says.[/p]
        [p]Dr. Nair's eyes dart nervously around the room. ``I'm not sure I can.''[/p]
        [p]Mr. Vandergraft, who has been standing quietly in the back of the room, steps forth. ``You'll do it, Nair, and you'll succeed; otherwise, there is no future for you – [em]none whatsoever.[/em] ''[/p]
        [p]Dr. Nair winces. He looks furtively around. Two of Vandergraft's detectives are blocking the door. ``All right,'' he says softly ``I'll try.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="52" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="65">
    <text>
        [p]``Thank you, Amanda. I'd be grateful if I could stay at your house for a few days,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]Your new friend leads you up the hill and across a beautiful, closely cropped lawn. The German shepherds fall into step behind you as you walk past marble statues, a triple-tier fountain, two clay tennis courts, a row of twelve-foot-high lilacs, and then onto a secluded grass court in which is set a large swimming pool lined with Italian marble. Tables and chairs are set out under huge umbrellas, but no one is in sight. You continue on past the cabanas and sauna and more fountains and finally reach the great brick mansion that Amanda calls home.[/p]
        [p]``You sure have a nice place here,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]Amanda smiles at you, then points to the driveway, surfaced with pink-tinted pebbles. You gaze admiringly at the sleek red Saab 9000 Turbo; the silver Rolls Royce, and the shiny, new bright green Porsche.[/p]
        [p]``Daddy's home,'' Amanda cries happily. ``Come along! He'll be very excited to meet you!''[/p]
        [p]You reach down and touch your paw to Amanda's arm. ``Wait a minute. Don't you think you ought to warn him first?''[/p]
        [p]Amanda looks you up and down, mostly up. ``Yes, I see what you mean. Wait in that cabana till I have time to warn my parents and calm them down.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="109" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="66">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="67">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="67"][/p]
        [p]``I think you've made the right decision,'' Mr. Vandergraft says. ``You're too fine a person to spend the rest of your life as a monster. I'm going to hire one of the best detectives in the country to make sure we find Dr. Nair.''[/p]
        [p]``I can't thank you enough, sir,'' you reply.[/p]
        [p]During the following days you wait anxiously for news from Zena Hearne, the detective hired by Mr. Vandergraft. One morning, while you're playing soccer with the German shepherds, you hear Amanda calling you from the patio off the east wing.[/p]
        [p]``The detective says she's found Dr. Nair!'' Amanda calls as you come bounding across the lawn. ``Come into the drawing room. Zena Hearne wants to talk to you.''[/p]
        [p]You follow Amanda through the guest quarters, then through the library and the great hall, then through the living room and into the drawing room. There, standing by the grand piano, is a rosy-cheeked woman with frizzy reddish-brown hair.[/p]
        [p]``Pleased to meet you,'' she says, holding out her hand, which you touch with your big, scruffy paw. Zena Hearne doesn't look like a detective, but she certainly seems agreeable.[/p]
        [p]You sit on the floor so you'll be the same height Zena Hearne is while she's standing. ``Amanda tells me you think you've found Dr. Nair,'' you say.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="38" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="68">
    <text>
        [p]You wake up in a bed, your head aching. There's a lot of equipment around. Everything is made of shiny stainless steel. You wonder if you were hit by a car on your way home from school, taken to the hospital, and just had a nightmare about being kidnapped.[/p]
        [p]A thin, slightly stooped man with a tightly clipped beard enters your room. Something tells you he is not a doctor.[/p]
        [p]``Don't worry about that little bump on your head,'' he says in a high-pitched nasal tone. ``You are a perfect subject for our experiment. My name is Dr. Hendrik Nair.''[/p]
        [p]You sit up. feeling even more frightened than when the gunmen pulled you into the car. ``What kind of experiment? What are you talking about?''[/p]
        [p]The man steps closer. He fixes his eyes on yours. ``Have you ever heard of genetic engineering – genetic transplants?''[/p]
        [p]You're too stunned to answer.[/p]
        [p]``Well, you're going to learn a lot more, since I'm the greatest expert in the field. You'll be my most important patient.''[/p]
        [p]``Oh, no – you're not going to touch me!'' You're out of the bed, looking for a way out – maybe through the window.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="4" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="69">
    <text>
        [p]``Welcome,'' he says, as you let him place his small white hand in the grip of your enormous paw. He is a short, lean man with fuzzy reddish-brown hair.[/p]
        [p]After polite inquiries about the Vandergrafts and how you've gotten along living with them for the past month, Dr. Firenze pulls up a straight-back metal hospital chair, flips it around, and sits on it backward, resting his arms on the back.[/p]
        [p]``Now, let's get down to business,'' he says. ``As Mr. Vandergraft told you, there's a chance I may be able to help change your body back into its original self through genetic-transplant treatment. I think I know what Dr. Nair's method was, and we should be able to reverse it. But I have to warn you that my work is still in the experimental stage, and I can't guarantee success.''[/p]
        [p]``That's all right, doctor,'' you say. ``I'm willing to try anything.''[/p]
        [p]``You must understand,'' he says, ``that if I fail, you will not only never return to the normal youngster you were before, you may become even [em]more[/em]  horrible – more monstrous – than you are now. So I must ask you: Are you sure you want to go through with this experiment?''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="2" pos="1">If you say yes to Dr. Firenze's experiment</next>
    <next id="73" pos="2">If you say no to Dr Firenze's experiment</next>
  </p>
  <p id="70">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="71">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="71"][/p]
        [p]A tall, lanky man with a few days' growth of beard stands at the entrance. He's wearing a red hunting cap, a plaid flannel shirt, blue jeans, and heavy boots. A rifle is slung across his back. He does a double take on seeing you, but he doesn't scream or run. He just looks a little to one side of you and doesn't move at all.[/p]
        [p]You're so surprised by him and by the way he just stands there, that you're kind of frozen, yourself. Then, while you're trying to think of what to say, you notice he's very, very slowly moving a hand toward the strap that's holding his rifle. [em]He's treating you just the way he would a bear![/em][/p]
        [p]Once he unsnaps the strap he'll be able to raise that rifle and fire it in about half a second.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="77" pos="1">If you lunge to keep him from raising his rifle</next>
    <next id="41" pos="2">If you talk to him</next>
  </p>
  <p id="72">
    <text>
        [p]Not that it matters much. By the time the movie is released, the cops have caught up with Job Watkins – and with you too. You're brought in and soon find yourself in the interrogation room at the Los Angeles office of the FBI.[/p]
        [p]``What does the FBI have to do with this?'' you demand of the sandy-haired agent seated across the desk. He's wearing sunglasses, even though you're indoors. It makes you wonder if he's going to shine a bright light in your eyes.[/p]
        [p]``We're involved because you're a national menace. You frighten people.''[/p]
        [p]``But I haven't committed any crime!''[/p]
        [p]The agent takes off his shades, blows on them, and then rubs them with a tissue he pulls out of his pocket. He puts the glasses back on before looking at you again.[/p]
        [p]``You don't have to have committed a crime,'' he says.[/p]
        [p]``This is going nowhere,'' you say. ``I'll stand on my constitutional rights!''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="113" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="73">
    <text>
        [p]You sit thinking for a moment. It's so awful being a monster, you're willing to try almost anything. But the thought of becoming an even [em]more[/em]  horrible monster – maybe one that can only crawl, or can't talk, or smells awful, or goodness knows what – is too much to contemplate. ``I don't think I want to take the risk, doctor,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]Dr. Firenze frowns but nods his head. ``I understand completely,'' he says. ``No one can tell you what is the right decision in such a case.''[/p]
        [p]``What's next for me then, doctor?'' you ask, aware that the Vandergrafts can't be expected to keep you as a guest any longer.[/p]
        [p]``I've discussed this with everyone, and we all think the best thing for a while would be for you to live on a farm or a lumber camp, where you could get a lot of exercise working, earn your keep, and be in a small, friendly community that's isolated, so you won't be bothered by outsiders.''[/p]
        [p]You feel depressed on hearing this, but you seem to have no other choice. A few days later, a van comes to pick you up and take you to a lumber camp in British Columbia, Canada. Tears run down your monstrous cheeks as you bid farewell to Amanda and her family and set out on your journey.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="37" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="74">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="75">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="75"][/p]
        [p]The circus season opens in three weeks, so you have just a short while to get to know the people and animals and learn your job. The ringmaster helps you train for an act where you scare the clowns, then become their friend, and then become a clown yourself. You also work with the animal trainers. When you walk past the elephants, one by one they rear up and trumpet wildly.[/p]
        [p]The tigers are another act. When you go into a cage with a tiger, he starts stalking you. But you roar so fiercely, he backs off. Later you learn to ride on his back. The tiger is agreeable, but you're so heavy that he soon tires and sits down. For the fun of it, you get under him and give him a ride![/p]
        [p]Tazewell is nearby, jumping up and down. ``This is the greatest act of all time!'' he shouts.[/p]
        [p]Watkins was right: Circus business soars once word is out that you're the main attraction. They have to turn people away at the gate. Your act is televised and shown on national TV. By the end of the season you're famous, not as a dreaded, feared monster, but as a circus superstar![/p]
        [p]Of course your ten percent of gross receipts adds up to a lot of money: You're rich! Watkins finally admits to you that he had embezzled money from a bank. At last he's able to pay it back, and the charges against him are dropped. You and he agree – it's nice to be rich, but what's [em]really[/em]  nice is to be free.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="76">
    <text>
        [p]Dr. Nair has been turned back into an ordinary person. After spending several years in jail, he begins a new career – as a shoe salesman.[/p]
        [p]And you are back home again. Your parents are very glad to see you. Of course they'd heard about the monster, but they never really believed such a thing could have happened to you.[/p]
        [p]Your mom says she missed you so much, she'd have wanted you to come home even if you were still a monster. Your dad says it may have been just as well that you waited until you could be changed back. ``It would have broken our hearts to see you that way,'' he says.[/p]
        [p]But everyone agrees that it's all worked out in the end, and that's what counts. Tomorrow you'll be starting school again. You've got some catching up to do, but one thing's certain: You've learned all you need to know about monsters.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="77">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="77"][/p]
        [p]You lunge toward the hunter before he can raise his rifle and shoot. With your tremendous strength you would only need to get one paw on him to bring him down, but he steps nimbly back through the entrance. As you follow, he backs away, edging close to the front of the cabin, and raises his rifle.[/p]
        [p][em]Crack![/em][/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em] '' You roar – not a human sound. but the anguished cry of a dying monster.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="78">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="78"][/p]
        [p]Even though your family is prepared for the shock, everyone is startled to see your grotesque figure blocking the doorway. Your mom reels back as if she's going to faint. Your dad props her up, but he looks awfully pale himself. The dog crawls under a table and hides. Your brother just stares open-mouthed at you, while your sister reaches for the camera.[/p]
        [p]``Hi, everybody,'' you say cheerfully.[/p]
        [p]Your mom finally gets hold of herself. She starts hesitantly toward you, her arms outstretched as if she's determined to hug you – though she won't be able to get her arms around you.[/p]
        [p]You're afraid to move closer, for fear of scaring her to death, but finally you step forward very slowly.[/p]
        [p]``It's hard to believe,'' your dad says, ``but I do believe it's you.''[/p]
        [p]``You must be hungry,'' your mom says, motioning you toward the kitchen. ``Come and sit down.''[/p]
        [p]You hate to eat all the food in the house, but you're pretty hungry, so you polish off a loaf of bread, a box of cereal, two quarts of milk, a large jar of peanut butter, a pack of hot dogs, a quart of orange juice, and four bananas.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="3" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="79">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="80">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="81">
    <text>
        [p]You're so depressed, you just sit on the bed and stare at the wall, thinking about the terrible mess you have fallen into.[/p]
        [p]Through the days that follow, your body changes in ways almost too horrible to describe. Your captors bring you all the food you need, which is a lot, because you're always hungry. The whole time you're too scared to even look at yourself in the bathroom mirror.[/p]
        [p]Pain. That's the worst part of it. You can hear your bones crackling as they grow. Your muscles are growing too. They ache as they stretch to keep up with your bones – especially your arm bones, which are lengthening and thickening the most. Your skin is expanding, trying to cover your widening body surface. Sometimes it's stretched so thin, you're afraid it will split, but it always seems to cover. If you were just growing up fast, into an adult, that wouldn't be so bad. It's the [em]way[/em]  you're growing that frightens you – you're becoming much more massive than any human – much broader and thicker—and stronger! That's why they've boarded up your door with three-inch oak planking. It's also why they stopped feeding you through the door after the first few days and started throwing food in through a hole in the ceiling. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="86" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="82">
    <text>
        [p]``Oh,'' you say, thinking for a moment, ``I would react nicely – very kindly – and I would treat the monster as a regular person.''[/p]
        [p]``Well then, you see?'' Dr. Rasmussen looks at you triumphantly.[/p]
        [p]``No, I don't,'' you reply. ``The reason I'd act that way is that I know what it's like to be a monster. The other kids don't.''[/p]
        [p]``Ah,'' Dr. Rasmussen says, undaunted. ``I'm glad to see you are so intelligent.''[/p]
        [p]``Hmmm.''[/p]
        [p]``Well then,'' the doctor says softly, ``since you are intelligent, all you have to do is ignore those who would taunt you.'' He leans forward and looks at you intently. ``Slowly the others will come to understand. They will become wiser because of the example you set.''[/p]
        [p]``I hope so,'' you murmur.[/p]
        [p]You're impressed by what the doctor has said but not completely convinced.[/p]
        [p]``Do I really have to go to school?'' you ask.[/p]
        [p]The doctor shrugs. ``No, but you can't just sit at home watching cartoons all day. I know of a cattle ranch where you might want to work,'' he says. He glances at his watch. ``Oh my, our time is up. Think it over and let me know what you decide.''[/p]
        [p]You both get up. He reaches out and grabs your paw. ``I think you'd like this ranch,'' he says. ``Whatever your decision is, I wish you good luck.''[/p]
        [p]You thank Dr. Rasmussen and walk down the street, ignoring the stares of startled passersby. You have a decision to make.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="18" pos="1">If you decide to stay home and go back to school</next>
    <next id="88" pos="2">If you decide to leave home and go work on a cattle ranch</next>
  </p>
  <p id="83">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="84">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="84"][/p]
        [p]``Watkins is my name,'' he says. ``Jeb Watkins. Now, I've read something about you in the papers. Even before I met you I felt some sympathy for you. You see, I've been chased by the law myself for the last two years – over fifteen states and three countries.''[/p]
        [p]``What are you in trouble for?'' you ask.[/p]
        [p]Watkins looks at you for a moment without answering. You guess he didn't like your question.[/p]
        [p]``I don't care what you got in trouble for – you seem like a decent man to me,'' you say.[/p]
        [p]Watkins stirs the soup on the stove while he looks over his shoulder at you. ``Thanks, I appreciate that.''[/p]
        [p]He invites you to sit opposite him. The two of you sit down and polish off the soup. It's not enough to fill you, of course.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="44" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="85">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="86">
    <text>
        [p]When you look at the thick, coarse hair on your body you feel like crying. But that's nothing compared to the feeling of two long, canine teeth – sharp as spikes – growing out of your jaw, and the massive brows, overlapping your face like a ledge on a cliff.[/p]
        [p]Your captors don't talk to you – they don't even show their faces – though you've pleaded with them by shouting when they throw down food, or yelling out the window. You've even roared like a caged lion.[/p]
        [p]You're as strong as a lion, too. You can throw your bed around the room with one hand and shake the walls so hard that plaster falls from the ceiling. But the walls hold, and so does the door. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="9" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="87">
    <text>
        [p]You lumber out from behind the bushes, your fangs exposed full length as you try to smile. You may look like a fierce monster, but you feel more like a frightened rabbit. Sure, you could bash a police car flat with one slap of your paw, or grab a cop by the arm and hurl him across the courtyard, and finish off another with one chomp of your super-powerful jaws. But you couldn't stand up against a hail of bullets.[/p]
        [p]That's what the cop behind the car blocking the courtyard must think, because he sends a bullet whistling past one of your sharply pointed ears.[/p]
        [p]You freeze. Any other reaction would mean instant death, because at least half a dozen cops are now crouching, with their weapons leveled at you.[/p]
        [p]``Hold your fire!'' the chief orders. The red-faced man with a fancy bronze insignia on his lapels steps forward. ``Just what are you, some kind of alien?''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="26" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="88">
    <text>
        [p]Once you decide you definitely don't want to go to school, arrangements are quickly made to send you away to the ranch Dr. Rasmussen recommended. The plan is for you to earn your keep as a hired hand. The head of the ranch likes the idea of having someone big and strong enough to wrestle steers, herd cattle, and carry heavy loads.[/p]
        [p]The ranch is in Wyoming, and you're to fly there in a small chartered plane. The passenger seats have been ripped out to make room for you. Someone has taped up a sign that reads: Monster Section. Very funny, you think.[/p]
        [p]There aren't any flight attendants on board, but food and water have been set out for the six-hour trip. You'd expected the pilots to be a little friendly and keep the door to the cockpit open, but it's locked.[/p]
        [p]About two hours into the flight you notice something very strange. All you can see below is the ocean – or maybe it's the Gulf of Mexico. It sure isn't Lake Michigan – the water is just too blue, and you can't see land anywhere. It's obvious you're not on the way to any ranch. You're being abducted! But where to? And why?[/p]
        [p]You bang on the door to the cockpit. ``What's going on?'' you demand. ``Where are you taking me?''[/p]
        [p]Suddenly the door flies open, banging you in your snout. A submachine gun is pointed in your face.[/p]
        [p]``Back up! And keep your paws up!'' [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="60" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="89">
    <text>
        [p]``Why get Dr. Firenze?'' Amanda inquires. ``Why not get Dr. Nair?''[/p]
        [p]``Who would that be, dear?'' her mother asks.[/p]
        [p]``He's the one that caused all this,'' Amanda says. ``If we could catch him, we could make him undo his evil work.''[/p]
        [p]Mr. Vandergraft bites his lower lip and shakes his head ever so slightly. ``Maybe... maybe...''[/p]
        [p]``But how could we trust Dr. Nair to do what we want?'' Mrs. Vandergraft asks.[/p]
        [p]Amanda looks fiercely around the table. ``We'll [em]make[/em]  him!''[/p]
        [p]Mr. Vandergraft looks at you. ``Well?''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="62" pos="1">If you agree to enter Federal Hospital</next>
    <next id="67" pos="2">If you ask the Vandergrafts to hire detectives to find and capture Dr. Nair</next>
  </p>
  <p id="90">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="90"][/p]
        [p]How could anyone do this to you! you wonder. What kind of a man is Dr. Nair? He is the monster – not you. If only you could get hold of that evil scientist.[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]'' you roar. If you've become a monster you may as well make the best of it! You smash your shoulder against the heavy door of your bedroom. The wall shudders and shakes. Plaster falls from the ceiling. The oak planks groan and crack. You smash a great fist against the wall and punch right through it![/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]'' You raise a leg and smash the door and its supporting timbers into the hall, splitting two-by-four beams as if they were twigs.[/p]
        [p]``It's loose!'' a voice screams.[/p]
        [p]Dr. Nair runs out of a room at the end of the hall. ``I warned you we couldn't hold it,'' he yells at the other man, who has already run out of sight.[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]'' You charge after him![/p]
        [p]Dr. Nair bolts and races down the stairs. You're not far behind. By now you must be stronger than any man on earth, but you're no faster a runner than most. By the time you've reached the courtyard, Dr. Nair and two other men are jumping into the blue Mercedes. The engine starts. You grab the bumper and lift the back of the car off the ground. The engine roars. The car has front-wheel drive and it goes into motion. You try to get a better grip but the car races ahead, leaving you clutching the bumper in your claws. You run outside the gate in time to see the Mercedes disappear around the corner.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="10" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="91">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="92">
    <text>
        [p]An hour and a half later the plane lands at an airstrip on a small Caribbean island. It's immediately surrounded by armed men. For a moment you think they may be policemen, but you soon learn that they are in the private army of Buck Meyerstraub, who practically runs this tiny third-world country.[/p]
        [p]You're packed into a limo and driven up a winding, roughly paved road to Meyerstraub's mountaintop villa. The guards bring you before the infamous crime boss, who's sitting in a reclining leather chair in a room crammed with expensive furniture and paintings. A huge window overlooks the jungle-clad slopes and valley below. In the distance is the whitecapped sea.[/p]
        [p]Meyerstraub, overweight and pink-faced, gapes at you as you walk into the room. Two men with machine guns follow a few steps behind.[/p]
        [p]The master criminal laughs and rubs his hands.[/p]
        [p]``Very good, boys,'' he says to the guards. ``This one will do just fine.''[/p]
        [p]``What do you want of me?'' you demand.[/p]
        [p]Meyerstraub laughs. ``Can't you guess, Monster, or are you too vain to guess?'' He leans forward; he's so close, you're tempted to lunge at him. ``I want to use you to scare people. In my business it's not enough to threaten people and even kill them occasionally. To run a crime empire you have to keep people afraid of you – and you're going to help me do that.''[/p]
        [p]You shake your monstrous head as you realize you've been delivered into the hands of a madman. But there's nothing you can do – there are automatic weapons pointing at you from both sides. You'll just have to play along with this man until you have a chance to subdue him or to escape.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="15" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="93">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="94">
    <text>
        [p]The lumber camp you're sent to is called Twin Lakes Camp. It's in British Columbia, Canada, far from civilization. You're flown out there in a special plane under tight security.[/p]
        [p]The lumberjacks in the camp were warned that you were coming, of course, and a few of them speak to you in a friendly fashion, though they mostly keep at a considerable distance. But one of the biggest and roughest – a man named Mike Fenwick – jeers at you. ``Are you as stupid as you're ugly?'' he yells.[/p]
        [p]This angers you so, that you pick up a big ax. You know enough not to threaten him with it, much less attack him. With a little flick of the wrist you heave it through the air at a big fir tree about a hundred feet away. The blade cuts into the bark. The handle quivers a moment, but the ax is firmly planted in the tree.[/p]
        [p]``Not a bad arm,'' someone says.[/p]
        [p]``Better watch your tongue, Fenwick,'' someone else calls from the mess hall.[/p]
        [p]Fenwick looks at you with hatred in his eyes. You can tell he'd like to get back at you in some way. [/p]
    </text>
    <next id="37" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="95">
    <text>
        [p]He winces but continues with his smooth talk. ``You're so good, I'm going to put you in charge of all my security forces.''[/p]
        [p]You pick Meyerstraub up and hold him with one great shaggy arm so you can free your other hand. You step toward the two guards. They back away – their faces read ``fear.'' One of them starts to bolt.[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH! Stay![/em]'' He freezes in his tracks. With your free paw you pick up their weapons.[/p]
        [p]Meyerstraub, suspended sideways in the air, whines, ``I'll make you rich. I'll pay you ten thousand dollars a month, ten thousand dollars a week! And a bonus, a big bonus.''[/p]
        [p]The last few words hardly come out as you squeeze the crime boss harder. You may be a monster, but you're not going to work for a monstrous criminal, that's for sure – not to mention that you couldn't trust this slinky character to pay you a nickel of what he's promising. Your only goal is to get off this island and back to the States, and if possible, to deliver Meyerstraub to the authorities.[/p]
        [p]Unfortunately that's not going to be so easy. You've got Meyerstraub as a hostage, but you'll have to get past a small army of security men and persuade someone to fly you to the mainland. Maybe you should play along with him. Then sooner or later you'll find a better way to escape.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="32" pos="1">If you tell Meyerstraub you'll accept his offer</next>
    <next id="104" pos="2">If you turn down Meyerstraub's offer</next>
  </p>
  <p id="96">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="96"][/p]
        [p]``[em]Chh, chh, cheeeeek[/em],'' you say.[/p]
        [p]``I'm afraid my technique didn't work,'' says Dr. Firenze. ``I'm deeply sorry.''[/p]
        [p]``At least you don't look like a monster anymore,'' says Amanda. ``You're real cute.''[/p]
        [p]``I'm glad to see you looking so healthy and, in your own way, normal,'' says Mrs. Vandergraft.[/p]
        [p]``Yes, you do look fine – and so agile,'' her husband adds with a smile.[/p]
        [p]``[em]Chh, chh, cheeeeek[/em],'' you respond.[/p]
        [p]But when Dr. Firenze looks at you, his face is grave. ``Now I'm afraid you have only two choices left,'' he says. ``The jungle – or the zoo.''[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="97">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="98">
    <text>
        [p]``Okay. It's a deal,'' you tell Meyerstraub.[/p]
        [p]``Good, good.'' His voice oozes charm. ``I think you'll find this very rewarding – the best work a monster could get.''[/p]
        [p]You say nothing, desperately hoping that you'll find a way to get off this rotten island.[/p]
        [p]``All right then,'' Meyerstraub says, ``here's the plan. The man who's giving me trouble is named Vargas. He's headquartered in Key West and runs his business there with a small fleet of boats all disguised as shrimp trawlers. He's been infiltrating my organization – threatening to assault my island. He's gummed up my business. Once I control his organization, I'll be able to run things right.''[/p]
        [p]He pauses to light a cigarette. ``As I told you,'' he says after taking a long drag, ``Vargas has refused to step into line. That's why I'm arranging for you to be his nightmare.''[/p]
        [p]``Okay,'' you say. ``Let's get on with the plan.''[/p]
        [p]Meyerstraub rubs the arm of his chair. ``We're going to fly you to Key West tomorrow. And we'll see that you get access to Vargas's bedroom. Your job is easy. You don't hurt him or even touch him. You just roar, and then when he wakes up, you scare him plenty. If he jumps in his bed and hits the ceiling, that will be just about right – understood?''[/p]
        [p]``Yeah.''[/p]
        [p]``Good. If he reaches for a gun, just grab it and twist off the barrel. Can you do that?''[/p]
        [p]``I think so.''[/p]
        [p]``Good. Then give him one more roar. Make him quake. Then throw him on the floor. Throw the bed covers on him. Then toss my calling card on the bed and beat it out. That's all you have to do.''[/p]
        [p]``I gotcha,'' you say.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="21" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="99">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="100">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="101">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="101"][/p]
        [p]As you near the top of the rise, you stop to rest behind a big oak tree. You're out of breath. Strong as you are, you're not in the best physical shape, because you've been locked up in that little room and not getting enough exercise.[/p]
        [p]You're beginning to relax a little when you hear furious barking. Two big German shepherds are running straight at you![/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]'' you roar.[/p]
        [p]They keep coming. One of them leaps high, at your throat. You catch him in midair and cast him aside.[/p]
        [p]The second dog hesitates.[/p]
        [p]You advance, arms over your head, your claws waving over the attacker. ``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]''[/p]
        [p]The dog lies down, cringing. The other comes toward you, whimpering, with his tail between his legs.[/p]
        [p]``Good dogs.'' You pat each of them. They wag their tails.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="16" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="102">
    <text>
        [p]``Look,'' the mayor says soothingly, ``you're not going to be locked up in jail, or anything like that. It's to your advantage to cooperate. We will take care of you and provide for you.''[/p]
        [p]You're feeling angry, and you almost let out a roar that would knock these men out of their socks, but that wouldn't be in your best interest just now, so you sit still.[/p]
        [p]``One thing you could do,'' the mayor continues, ``is live in a lumber camp. You're strong. You could do a lot there and still have time to relax. There's TV, video, and plenty of good food. But you'd have to promise to stay on the farm.''[/p]
        [p]You don't feel like jumping up and down at this idea; you remain silent and just keep listening as the mayor continues.[/p]
        [p]``There's another hope for you,'' he says, ``but it's rather risky. There's an experimental genetic unit at Federal Hospital. The director there, Dr. Firenze, is almost as much of a genius as Dr. Nair, but Firenze isn't a mad scientist. He's a dedicated doctor, and he thinks there's a chance he can restore you to the healthy, normal person you were. But I have to warn you, the experiment might fail, and if it does, the consequences could be fatal.''[/p]
        [p]You're getting numb thinking about this, and you're startled when the mayor's voice booms out. ``Well?''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="94" pos="1">If you decide to go live in a lumber camp</next>
    <next id="24" pos="2">If you agree to submit to the genetic experiment</next>
  </p>
  <p id="103">
    <text>
        [p]During the months ahead you learn the ways of the grizzly bears. You live as they do: hunting small game, stealing honey from bees, fishing for salmon in the fast-flowing streams. Sometimes you eat the leftovers of campers, though you try to lead your group as far from human habitation as you can. You love the freedom of wandering fearlessly wherever you like, of being so strong and tough that neither rain nor cold, insects or other animals, bother you. You grow stronger and more agile as the months go by. The grizzlies, though they are generally solitary animals, seem to have grown as fond of you as you have of them.[/p]
        [p]But the days get shorter, the nights longer and colder. First come frosty mornings. Then snow. The bears begin digging dens in rocky niches or under the stumps of huge fallen trees. For a while you're puzzled, but then you understand. They are preparing to hibernate. You're as big and tough as the strongest bear, but you can't hibernate. Your monster body doesn't work that way. In that respect, you're more like a human than like a bear.[/p]
        [p]Sadly, you realize you will have to leave the bears and once again try to make the best of it in human company. Maybe that's just as well, you think.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="46" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="104">
    <text>
        [p]You look down at Meyerstraub, the crime king, He's squirming under your arm. ``Do you think I'd trust you?''[/p]
        [p]``You've got to,'' he wails. ``You'll never get out of here alive.''[/p]
        [p]``And neither will you,'' you say, ``if you try and stop me.''[/p]
        [p]``Look, okay What is it you want?''[/p]
        [p]``Have a plane ready on the airstrip to take the two of us to the States. And tell your security men that if I see one weapon before we take off – or if one shot is fired – you'll die.''[/p]
        [p]``Okay. Sure, sure, Monster.'' Meyerstraub tries to sound cool. He's past the panic stage, and you can tell that his criminal mind is at work again, scheming to turn the tables in his favor.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="110" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="105">
    <text>
        [p]Meyerstraub lies in the aisle. He's pale and sweating but unhurt. Miraculously, nothing vital was hit. The plane accelerates and finally takes off. Another burst of gunfire goes wild. You see bullets falling short as the jet speeds away.[/p]
        [p][em]Phew![/em]  You pull a blanket down from the overhead rack and press it against your wound to stop the flow of blood.[/p]
        [p]Suddenly Meyerstraub is pointing a pistol at you – he must have hidden it on board. ``You're going to jump out of this plane, Monster!''[/p]
        [p]``Look – Behind you!'' you yell.[/p]
        [p]It's the oldest trick in the book, but it works. Meyerstraub starts to look behind him. He catches on and snaps his eyes back on you, but your paw comes down on his hand, and knocks the gun away.[/p]
        [p]The crime king cringes on the floor.[/p]
        [p]You stick your monstrous head inside the cockpit. Shaking, the pilot looks back at you.[/p]
        [p]You growl slightly and the pilot returns to the controls. A moment later you're on the radio alerting the FBI. ``I'm bringing in Meyerstraub,'' you tell them.[/p]
        [p]Now you can sit back and relax. You'll soon be dealing with the police again, but this time they should be pretty friendly. After all, you're bringing in the biggest crime boss of them all.[/p]
        [p]As they tell you later when you land, ``You're the greatest, Monster.''[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="106">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="106"][/p]
        [p]Once you reach the street it's bedlam – people scream and point at you. Others run. Horns honk. Down the block, someone yells at a policeman.[/p]
        [p]You eye a truck that's stopped at a red light. You run to it, pull open the back door, and jump in. The van is half filled with boxes of electronic equipment. The addresses on the labels show that the boxes are bound for Florida. You move forward so people won't see you as the truck climbs the ramp to the Interstate – the driver never even notices you.[/p]
        [p]You're headed for Florida. Of course there will be just as many problems there as there are here. You know you'll never get any peace living with people. You'll just have to take to the wilderness. In Florida, that means the vast, watery region around Lake Okeechobee. Your future now looks pretty certain: You're going to be a swamp monster![/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="107">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="108">
    <text>
        [p]You dodge out of the way, grab a huge log, and hold it over your head. Fenwick shuts down his chain saw and runs. He scrambles up a ridge and then turns to face you. You haven't moved a step.[/p]
        [p]``I missed you this time, but I'll get you,'' he yells over his shoulder. ``Sooner or later, I'll get you!''[/p]
        [p]He disappears over the ridge, leaving you standing there stunned. For the first time you have lost all hope that you will ever lead a normal life.[/p]
        [p]The sun has already dropped behind the mountains to the west. You're certainly ready to quit – you've done about ten times more work than anyone else today. With a heavy heart you start back to camp.[/p]
        [p]You're in no hurry to get back, so you follow the footpath that reaches camp by a roundabout way. Just as you reach a bend in the trail, you're startled by a noise. A huge male grizzly bear rears up in your path. He lets out a roar that splits your ears.[/p]
        [p]Maybe you interrupted his meal. Maybe he's just ornery. But he clearly doesn't want you to pass. A low growl builds in his throat – he seems ready to attack. A wave of fear sweeps over you. Then you remember: [em]You are a monster![/em][/p]
    </text>
    <next id="28" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="109">
    <text>
        [p]You have to hunch over to fit in the cabana. There you wait anxiously, wondering whether Amanda's parents will be as friendly as she has been to you. You just hope no one will open the cabana door. You couldn't not be frightening, even if you tried.[/p]
        [p]The minutes pass. You begin to wonder whether you should stay in the cabana – for all you know, Amanda's father has called the police by now. Then you hear sounds outside.[/p]
        [p]``Come on out.'' It's Amanda's cheery voice.[/p]
        [p]You throw open the door and blink your eyes in the sunshine. Standing on the terrace are Amanda's parents, the butler, the cook and the maid. You hang your head, sure that they will all scream, or worse, call the police. Mrs. Vandergraft throws her hand up and lets forth a little gasp. The maid and the cook grab each other for support. The butler backs up so fast, you're afraid he'll fall in the pool.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="114" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="110">
    <text>
        [p]While you keep his body firmly in your grip, he uses his public-address system to order the plane readied and all security men to stand clear and keep their weapons out of sight.[/p]
        [p]The pilot phones in that he'll have the plane ready in ten minutes. Meyerstraub's chauffeur will drive you to the airstrip in the same limo that brought you to his villa.[/p]
        [p]Now comes the dangerous part. Though you have Meyerstraub firmly under your arm, there's the danger that a sharpshooter could pick you off with a carefully aimed bullet. Another thing is, you can't be sure that one of Meyerstraub's henchmen wouldn't be happy to see you break the crime king's neck. There's always a lot of jealousy and infighting in a criminal organization like this. You'll just have to take the chance, you realize.[/p]
        [p]Swiftly you stride out the door to the waiting limo. Meyerstraub is still tucked under your arm, wrapped halfway around your waist like a sash.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="42" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="111">
    <text>
        [p]Very quietly you step over to the phone that's farthest from Vargas's bed. Keeping one eye on the sleeping form. you dial the police.[/p]
        [p]When they answer, you whisper, ``I'm being held hostage in the bedroom of Guillermo Vargas. Thirty Sea Pine Drive, by two armed men working for Buck Meyerstraub.''[/p]
        [p]``Hang on,'' the police dispatcher says, ``we'll have the place surrounded.''[/p]
        [p]While the dispatcher is giving instructions, you watch Vargas stirring restlessly in his bed.[/p]
        [p]``Is Vargas there?'' the dispatcher asks.[/p]
        [p]``Yes, but he's asleep.'' you whisper.[/p]
        [p]``Be careful.''[/p]
        [p]``Right.''[/p]
        [p]``Who are you, by the way?''[/p]
        [p]``It's a long story, but I'm very big and ugly, so tell your men not to shoot when they come in the bedroom.''[/p]
        [p]``As long as you come out with your hands up, no one will shoot.''[/p]
        [p]``They're paws.'' you say. Suddenly there's a scream. Vargas has woken up and seen you![/p]
        [p]``Gotta go.'' you say into the phone.[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]'' You leap on the bed, pinning Vargas's arm just before his hand closes on the .280 Magnum stashed under a pillow.[/p]
        [p]``Don't hurt me,'' he whimpers.[/p]
        [p]``Don't worry,'' you say, ``You're going to jail. not to the hospital.''[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="34" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="112">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="113">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="113"][/p]
        [p]The phone rings. The agent takes the call. ``It's for you,'' he says a moment later, ``but I'll warn you, I'm going to listen in on the other line.''[/p]
        [p]The phone call is from Watkins, who's out on bail. ``You've just gotten a big new movie deal,'' he says, ``from France. They're making a new film of the famous classic. [em]Beauty and the Beast.[/em]  Guess which part they want you for?''[/p]
        [p]``How much will they pay?'' you demand.[/p]
        [p]``Twenty million francs – that's one hundred and fifty thousand dollars!''[/p]
        [p]``Sounds good to me,'' you say, glancing at the FBI agent.[/p]
        [p]``Sounds good to me too,'' the FBI man says. ``We'll pay your way over there just to get you and Watkins out of the country for a while.''[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH,[/em]'' you roar appreciatively. You haven't felt so happy in a long time. With a little luck you're going to [em]enjoy[/em]  being a monster![/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="114">
    <text>
        [p class="inlineImage" data-img="114"][/p]
        [p]Amanda's father, however, steps forward and holds out his hand. ``Charles Vandergraft's the name.''[/p]
        [p]Amazed at how nice he is, you gently shake his hand with your paw.[/p]
        [p]``You certainly are a monster all right,'' he says, ``but Amanda has convinced me you're a good monster, so I'm willing to have you stay here a while as our guest.''[/p]
        [p]Amanda introduces you to the others. ``Hargraves, the butler, will show you to your room,'' she says. ``After you've rested awhile, perhaps you'll join us for lunch.''[/p]
        [p]The room Amanda leads you to is a luxurious suite with velvet curtains, oriental rugs, beautiful paintings on the wall, a TV, VCR, stereo, and a bookcase filled with lots of good books. You can hardly believe your good luck.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="58" pos="1" />
  </p>
  <p id="115">
    <empty />
  </p>
  <p id="116">
    <text>
        [p]You stand erect at the foot of Vargas's bed. your shaggy arms held high, your long, pointed claws extended.[/p]
        [p]``[em]ARRRAGH![/em]''[/p]
        [p]The sleeping form rises. The blurry eyes open. Vargas stares at you in terror. He gropes under a pillow for his gun. You bring one great clawed paw down on his arm. Then you roll him on the floor and hurl the bed covers on top of him. While Vargas is still struggling to untangle himself, you toss Meyerstraub's calling card on the bed. Then you back out the door. You want to disappear fast so Vargas won't know whether you were real or just a nightmare.[/p]
        [p]It's all very easy. Nothing to it. The only trouble is, you back into Vargas's personal bodyguard, one Meyerstraub didn't know about when he arranged to bribe the security men at the front gate. The bodyguard doesn't wait to ask questions. He lets you have it with his .280 Magnum.[/p]
        [p class="end"]The End[/p]
    </text>
    <victory />
  </p>
</content>
