<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content xmlns="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu http://zagor.hu/xsd/raw.xsd">
  <p id="back_cover">
    <next id="background" />
  </p>
  <p id="background" display="Background">
    <text>
        [p]More and more people are perishing in London's Great Plague. As the streets rumble nightly with the wheels of the death carts, Colonel Blood is hatching an evil and daring plot against the State. And he doesn't want [strong]you[/strong] interfering. Can you find out what Blood is up to, avoid being captured by his men and warn the guards of the Tower of Londin in time? You'll need a strong nerve since you'll have to spend time in the crime-ridden streets of London's slums and may have to pass a night with the dead body collectors.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="1"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="1">
    <text>
        [p]It was now late August in the year 1665 and more than two months since the plague had come to the city of London. Many had died already but more, it seemed, died each day. Every day, newly painted red crosses would appear on the doors of houses which had been visited by the plague. Each night, the carts would pass through the streets taking away the dead for burial.[/p]
        [p]Tonight, it was not the carts that had woken me, but the cry of the night watch calling, “Past two of the clock and a fine night.” As I turned over in bed, I heard my father stirring in the next room.[/p]
        [p]I saw the light of his candle beneath my door as he passed and heard his footfall on the stair. Guessing what might be afoot, I crept from my bed and, not daring to light my candle, crossed the dark passage to an empty room which looked over the yard at the back of the house.[/p]
        [p]I could see my father unbolting the door that led from the yard to the alley beyond. Gently, I eased up the latch and pushed open the window.[/p]
        [p]There were footsteps in the alley, the yard door opened and I heard whispered words. Into the yard, and into the light of the candle, stepped a woman whom I knew by the name of Mistress Slightly. She was followed by a giant of a man who carried across his shoulders a great, limp bundle, roughly wrapped in sacking.[/p]
        [p]They followed my father across the yard to a door that was always kept locked. It led to a part of the house which I was forbidden to enter. All three went through the door and vanished from sight. Moments later, the man and the woman came out again; the man was no longer carrying the bundle. They left the yard and I heard them hurrying off down the alley.[/p]
        [p]In the night breeze which blew through the open window, there came the sudden choking smell of fumes of burning sulphur. My father came back into the yard, holding his handkerchief to his mouth and nose. He locked the door and crossed the yard to replace the bolts in the door to the alley.[/p]
        [p]I knew that is was time to go back to my bed.[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="2"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="2">
    <text>
		[p]When I woke again, the sun was shining. From the window of my bedchamber, I could see Molly, our one remaining servant, as she crossed the street with her pitcher to buy from the milk maid. Some young apprentices were running down the street, one shouting to the others that they would be late for their work. I knew that it must be near six of the clock.[/p]
		[p]I dressed and hurried down the stair. My father was already at table and I saw that he had eaten little of his cold mutton and oysters. His face looked grey and drawn and I guessed that he had worked all through the night.[/p]
		[p]I drank my daily glass of “Sir Walter Raleigh's Cordial”, a medicine which was to protect me from the plague, and Molly brought me warm gruel and a dish of fresh milk. My father spoke little and I thought that there was more that worried him than simple lack of sleep.[/p]
		[p]Many of the physicians, the clergy and the wealthier merchants had left London with the coming of the plague. Where we lived, in the parish of Cripplegate, just outside of the city wall, my father was now the only remaining physician.[/p]
		[p]Two of our servants had left us to look after sick relatives. They had been prevented from returning by the law which demanded that where there was plague in a house, all the household must be locked in until the plague had passed.[/p]
		[p]My father had allowed me to remain in London, but not to help him in his work. I knew that what had arrived during the night was the body of a plague victim and that the burning sulphur was to purify the corpse before beginning the work of dissection. My father's apprentice, Richard Tindale, had died of the plague after helping in such work and my father took the risk only because he believed that it might help in finding some cure for the dread disease.[/p]
		[p]Seeing that I had finished my milk and gruel, my father asked if I remembered his friend Master John Evelyn. I said that I did.[/p]
		[p]“Then I have an errand for you,” he said. “This letter must de delivered to Master Evelyn today, and without fail, for I am sore in need of his advice.”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="3"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="3">
    <text>
		[p]I knew that the house of Master Evelyn was in Friday Street by the church of St Paul. I had been there with my father, but only by coach. My father had already left the house so I asked Molly how best I might reach it on foot.[/p]
		[p]“Tis a place easy enough to reach,” she said, “but your father should have known there be guards upon the streets in those parts and will let none pass by without they have the proper paper.”[/p]
		[p]She could see that I did not understand.[/p]
		[p]“Well,” she explained, “there is not every part of London that is as sore afflicted by the plague as be Cripplegate. Friday Street be in the parish of St John where there is not, as yet, one who has died on it. That being so, they have placed guards upon the streets who will let none past, save they have a paper to say that there is no plague in the place from which they have come.”[/p]
		[p]“But,” I said, “I must deliver this letter.”[/p]
		[p]Molly thought.[/p]
		[p]“The churchwardens do give plague passes,” she said, “but they would give none in Cripplegate. There be the Justice of the Peace. Him knowing your father, he might give you such a pass.”[/p]
		[p]I too knew the Justice of the Peace – Sir Hugo Donkey. They said that he was quite mad, more so when he was drunk than sober. He was not often sober.[/p]
		[p]“There be another way,” said Molly, “though I should not be telling you. There be those who do sell false passes for money. My friend, Mistress Gwynn, she do sell oranges by the new theatre in Drury Lane. She did buy a pass from Mistress Slightly upon payment of five shillings.”[/p]
		[p]Mistress Slightly lived off Hog Lane, in a place pf narrow, filthy streets, known as “The Rookery”. It was said that more of its citizens had been hung on Tyburn Tree than had ever died in their beds![/p]
		[p]It seemed that my choice was between a madman and a rogue, but if I were to deliver the letter …[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="5">… then it was either Sir Hugo Donkey.</next>
    <next id="9">Or The Rookery'.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="4">
    <text>
		[p]I shouted back, for it was the only way to talk across the great distance that separated us. I told him, Sir Walter Raleigh's Cordial.[/p]
		[p]“Cannot stomach it,” he replied. “Gripes me belly; but tell me about this letter.”[/p]
		[p]I told him that I had a letter to deliver to St John's, but that I had been told I would need a plague pass to enter the parish.[/p]
		[p]“You are told rightly,” he said, “but I fear that I cannot give you such a pass.”[/p]
		[p]It seemed that our businnes was at an end. I thanked him for his kindness in seeing me, picked up my letter and was about to leave, when the door opened and the footman entered. He crossed the room and whispered something in Sir Hugo's ear.[/p]
		[p]I had begun to leave, when Sir Hugo called me back.[/p]
		[p]“I will have your letter delivered for you,” he said. “As an officer of the law, I have a warrant which allows me, or my agent, to pass freely about the city. I have a messenger waiting below to carry a message for me to Newgate. He will deliver your letter.”[/p]
		[p]The offer sounded generous, but I was sure that something was wrong. It was the sudden way in which Sir Hugo had changed his mind, almost as if he had been told to make the offer. If the messenger was the man whom I had seen as I waited in the hallway, then I liked the offer even less.[/p]
		[p]I thought, quickly. I told Sir Hugo that my father had insisted that no-one but myself should deliver the letter. I asked if I might accompany his messenger.[/p]
		[p]If it was possible for Sir Hugo's face to go any redder, then I believe that it did. He seemed quite angry, saying that I had taken enough of his time already. If I did not wish to accept his offer to have the letter delivered, then I should waste his time no further and take my problems elsewhere.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="8">I liked neither Sir Hugo nor his messenger, but perhaps I should accept his offer?</next>
    <next id="6">I knew the alternative – to seek the help of someone who I could trust no more than Sir Hugo – Mistress Slinghtly!</next>
  </p>
  <p id="5">
    <text>
		[p]Sir Hugo Donkey lived in a grand house overlooking the churchyard of St Giles, Cripplegate, and only a short distance from where I lived with my father.[/p]
		[p]Apart from the tolling of church bells for the burials which took place by day as well as by night, the streets were strangely quiet. Many shops were closed, weeds grew around the doors of deserted houses, and each day I missed more of the familiar cries of those who sold their wares about the streets. Because my father tended the sick, those who knew me would cross the street rather than come near me.[/p]
		[p]The door of Sir Hugo's house was answered by a footman. I gave my name and stated my business. I was kept waiting in the hallway. I saw that another man waited there a man of most strange and unpleasant appearance. Dressed in black, as had been the fashion of the Puritans, his face was deeply marked by the pox and a livid scar ran from above his right eye down to the line of his jaw.[/p]
		[p]The footman returned, giving me a sprig of strong smelling rue to hold in my hand and some myrrh which I was to place in my mouth. He then took me up the staircase to a large and finely furnished room where, despite the warmth of the day, a huge log fire burned in the hearth and the air was sharp with the smell of resin.[/p]
		[p]Seated by the fire was Sir Hugo Donkey. He was a man of great size. His belly, which looked to be bursting from the gold brocade of his waistcoat, rested almost upon the knees of his breeches. He had gout in one foot, which was bandaged and rested upon a footstool. He was bald and without wig. His face was red and puffed and sweated freely. He mopped it constantly with a white handkerchief.[/p]
		[p]With a podgy hand, he raised a stick and pointed to a chair furthest from him across the room. I seated myself, placing my letter upon a table with some other papers. Suddenly, Sir Hugo picked up a brace of pistols and fired both of them into the air! I must have started, visibly, in my seat.[/p]
		[p]“The plague,” he shouted. “The powder does help to rid the air of poisons. What does your father favour?”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="4"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="6">
    <text>
		[p]Having told Sir Hugo that I did not wish to offend him, but that I must obey my father's wishes, I left his house. The man in black was no longer in the hallway as I left. The rue I returned to the footman. The myrrh I had swallowed, leaving an unpleasant taste in my mouth.[/p]
		[p]The shortest way to Hog Lane was by way of Holborn. I stopped by a fruit seller and bought myself an orange to take the taste of the myrrh from my mouth. As I paid for the fruit, I saw the man in black. He was some distance behind me, but walking in my direction. I remembered that Sir Hugo had said that he was going to Newgate.[/p]
		[p]At Pye Corner, I stopped and looked behind me again. The man was till there. Had he been going to Newgate, he would have left Holborn some distance back. I could not be certain that he was following me, but I crossed the street and went down one of the narrow alleys, thinking I'd lose him. It was I who became lost! When I reached a wider street again I saw that I was in Cheapside, not far from Friday Street, but walking in quite the opposite direction to where I wanted to go. I turned round to retrace my steps, only to see the man in black appear from one of the alleys.[/p]
		[p]A little way down Cheapside, a great bonfire was burning in the centre of the street. I had heard that many such fires had been lit in London to drive the poison of the plague from the air. The fire was making so much smoke that it was impossible to see the street beyond it. I ran for the smoke and, once certain that I was lost from sight, ran around the back of the fire and into the first open doorway.[/p]
		[p]I had never drunk coffee, but I knew the smell of it and saw that I had run into one of the London coffee houses. Men sat around large wooden tables and there was a lot of laughter and argument. In one wall a fire burned with a cauldron of water boiling upon it. In front of the fire were pots of many shapes and sizes which contained the coffee. Two boys passed among the tables filling dishes from the steaming pots.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="7"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="7">
    <text>
		[p]The argument between two of the men nearest to me suddenly became heated. Voices were raised and one flung his coffee into the face of the other. I had thought that a fight might break out and that I would be caught in the middle of it, when a youngish man took me by the arm and pulled me into a quiet corner.[/p]
		[p]“And why would you be in this place?” he asked. “Is it that you wish to discuss the war with the Dutch; or perhaps the state of the nation's finances?”[/p]
		[p]There was a twinkle in his eye as he said it. I told him neither; I said I thought I was being, followed and had come in to escape my pursuer.[/p]
		[p]“You do not look like a thief or murderer,” he said. “Why would anyone wish to pursue you?”[/p]
		[p]I felt I could trust the man and told him my story.[/p]
		[p]“Then your worries are over,” he said. “Master Evelyn is also a friend of mine and I will take you to his house.”[/p]
		[p]“You have a plague pass?” I asked him.[/p]
		[p]“No,” he said, “but like your friend Sir Hugo Donkey, I also possess a warrant giving me free passage. My name is Pepys – Samuel Pepys. I look after the King's Navy.”[/p]
		[p]When we returned to the street, I could see nothing of the man in black. Master Pepys walked with me to Friday Street and the house of Master Evelyn and there, I delivered my letter.[/p]
		[p]Master Evelyn, learning who had sent it and being told of my father's words that he was “sore in need of advice”, asked me to wait until he had read it, should there be a need for an immediate reply.[/p]
		[p]He broke the seal on the letter and read it; then read it again. He looked at me, clearly puzzled.[/p]
		[p]“You are certain that your father intended this for me?” he asked.[/p]
		[p]I said that I was. He asked if I could read. I said that I could, very well. He gave me the letter. It was from a firm of shippers at Puddle Wharf confirming the delivery of two African lions and thirty ostrich birds.[/p]
		[p]I knew what had happened. I had picked up the wrong letter from Sir Hugo's table! What should I do?[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="12">Return to Sir Hugo?</next>
    <next id="10">Or first tell my father what I had done?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="8">
    <text>
		[p]Having decided to accept Sir Hugo's offer, I left the house, returning the rue to the footman as I left. The myrrh I had swallowed, though I still had the unpleasant taste of it within my mouth.[/p]
		[p]I saw that there was an orange seller on the corner of the street and went to buy myself some fruit, hoping that it might rid me of the taste of the myrrh. It was while I was paying her that I saw the man in black, who I had seen at Sir Hugo's, pass by on the other side of the street.[/p]
		[p]He turned into Holborn, which I thought odd, for it was not the quickest way to either Newgate or St John's. I thought that I might follow him.[/p]
		[p]The man walked at a great pace, so that now and again, I had to break into a run to keep him within sight. My thought was to follow him to the place where he must leave Holborn if he was going to Newgate.[/p]
		[p]The man did not turn off the street. Already we were past Pye Corner and had crossed the river Fleet. Within another ten minutes, we had reached St Giles in the Fields and I could see the clock and steeple of the church.[/p]
		[p]The man was making for Hog Lane. I dared not stay too close in case the man saw me, but the streets were so empty, I thought there was little chance of losing him. I had not reckoned upon Hog Lane. There, I found myself in a great crowd which had gathered outside the two taverns which stood next door to each other. The men had brought out their tankards of ale to watch two women who were fighting in the street. They fought with clenched fists, like boxers, for each woman held a half crown in each hand, the first to drop her money being the loser. Because they could not scratch each other's eyes or tear their hair, such fights could last for a long time. I pushed my way through the crowd, but I knew that I had lost the man I was following. I also thought that I had lost my father's letter.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="10">Should I return home and tell him what had occurred?</next>
    <next id="11">He might write another letter, but I should still need a pass to deliver it. Being near The Rookery, should I seek out Mistress Slightly?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="9">
    <text>
		[p]Hog Lane lay in the parish of another St Giles – St Giles in the Fields. The quickest way from my father's house was to cut through Smithfield Market onto Holborn which would take me all the way to Hog Lane.[/p]
		[p]Apart from the tolling of church bells for the burials which took place by day as well as by night, the streets were strangely quiet. Many shops were closed and weeds were growing on the steps of houses deserted since the coming of the plague. There were few of the familiar cries of those who had once sold their wares around the streets. Because my father tended sick people, friends would cross the street rather than come near me.[/p]
		[p]It was market day, but even Smithfield Market was almost deserted. However, I was suddenly surrounded by a group of young ragamuffins, chanting that they were “The Black Guard”. For a half penny, they offered to say the Lord's Prayer backwards, or recite the points of the compass. I thought it was worth the half penny to be rid of them.[/p]
		[p]I reached Hog Lane to find a crowd of men and women drinking outside the two taverns. One tavern was offering a cock fight. Not to be. outdone, the other tavern boasted a female boxer from Billingsgate who would give ten pounds to any woman who could beat her in fair fight.[/p]
		[p]Standing in the crowd was a man whom I recognised. His black clothes made him stand out from the rest and I could see the scar which ran from above his right eye down to the line of his jaw. I had seen the man several times before; usually either leaving or entering the house of Sir Hugo Donkey.[/p]
		[p]Suddenly, he was gone. I had no idea of his business there, but mine was to find Mistress Slightly. I put my hand into my pocket to see that my letter was safe. It had gone! It could only have been taken by those children who had crowded around me in Smithfield – “The Black Guard”.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="10">I could return home.</next>
    <next id="11">If my father wrote another letter, I would still need a pass to deliver it. I was in Hog Lane. Should I seek out Mistress Slightly now</next>
  </p>
  <p id="10">
    <text>
		[p]I had reached the corner of White Cross Street and was almost back at my fahter's house, when I saw a coach being driven towards me at a great speed. Only because I threw myself against the wall, did I escape being trampled upon by the horses, or crushed beneath the wheels.[/p]
		[p]The coach had no mark upon it, the windows were closed by curtains and I could not see the coachman's face. His hat was pulled tight down on his head and the collar of his coat turned up about his ears as if it had been a winter's day.[/p]
		[p]I was not hurt, but much shaken. When I reached the door of our house, it was open. Molly ran into the hallway and, on seeing me, burst into a flood of tears. So great was her sobbing and wailing that I could make nothing of what she was trying to tell me.[/p]
		[p]I helped her to the kitchen, where she promptly fainted. It was only after I had burned goose feathers beneath her nose and forced her to drink two glasses of my father's brandy wine, that she was able to speak again.[/p]
		[p]She had been to the market to buy a capon and fresh vegetables. Three men were at the house when she returned. They had told her that my father had been taken with the plague and was to be taken to the pest house. She had asked to see him, but they had refused and locked her in the kitchen.[/p]
		[p]She had heard the sound of a struggle and of my father shouting. She had seen two of the men light a fire in the yard and burn some things on it. They had been brought from that part of the house which was usually locked and where we were forbidden to go.[/p]
		[p]When the men had left the yard, Molly had climbed out of the kitchen window into the yard and had come back into the house by way of the yard door which was not locked. The men had gone, as had my father. She said she had seen them leave in a coach.[/p]
		[p]I had no doubt that it was the same coach which had almost run me down. I also knew enough about the plague to know that my father could not have shown the signs of it in the few hours since breakfast that morning. My father had been kidnapped![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="14"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="11">
    <text>
		[p]The Rookery was a much worse place than I had imagined. I kept close to the walls, fearing that a chamber pot might be emptied on me from one of the upper windows of the houses which hung out over the street. In many places my shoes sank into the filth and rotting food on the ground, there being neither cats nor dogs to act as scavengers. In the belief that they might spread the plague, two pence had been paid for every dog and a penny for every cat slaughtered.[/p]
		[p]A boy about seven or eight years old was sitting upon a barrel in the street smoking the largest pipe I had ever seen. I asked him if he knew Mistress Slightly. He said that he did, that she lived above the soap boiler's yard and that he would take me there for a penny. I agreed.[/p]
		[p]He showed me his pipe, telling me that his father went about the streets at night collecting the dead. He said that is was a real “plague pipe”, having been made extra large to protect those who either carried or buried the victims of the plague.[/p]
		[p]To the stench of the filth rotting in the streets, there was suddenly added the smell of rancid fat. J knew that we must be a near to the soap boiler's yard. The boy led me through a narrow entrance.[/p]
		[p]The sides of the yard were stacked with barrels of tallow and sacks of wood ash and lime. In the centre, several large, metal vats bubbled away over coal fires, though no-one seemed to be tending them.[/p]
		[p]The boy explained that the soap boiler would not be far away; that he was much troubled with his innards through tasting the soap to test whether it was ready. We crossed the yard and entered a building where I followed the boy up a dark, narrow stair.[/p]
		[p]At the top of the stair, he knocked upon a door and, there being no answer, pushed it open. The room was dark, had little furniture and smelled as bad as the street outside. The boy said that this was where Mistress Slightly lived and that I should wait. I crossed to the window to open it, hoping to rid the place of some of its smell. From the window I could see down into the yard. Floating on top of one of the huge, bubbling vats, was a pair of shoes![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="15"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="12">
    <text>
		[p]Master Pepys said that he would walk with me for a part of the way. He told me that he was going to his wigmaker in Cheapside to buy himself a new wig – partly, he said, in celebration of not yet having been touched by the plague, and partly because wigs were being offered at greatly reduced prices. I asked if this was because so many people had left the city.[/p]
		[p]“That,” he said, “and because many are asking themselves where the hair is coming from which is used in the making of the wigs. It is one thing wearing dead men's hair. It is another when it may be the plague that they died from.”[/p]
		[p]I asked if that did not worry him.[/p]
		[p]“Greatly,” he replied. “I shall buy my wig, but – I shall not wear it until I think that any plague poison is gone from it.”[/p]
		[p]I left Master Pepys in Cheapside and made my way back to the house of Sir Hugo Donkey in Jewin Street. As I entered Jewin Street, I saw the man in black at the other end of the street. He was standing in the road talking with someone I did not recognise. He was still there when I reached Sir Hugo's house and knocked upon the door.[/p]
		[p]The footman who answered it was not the man I had seen before. I told him that I had been there earlier in the day and that I might have picked the wrong letter from Sir Hugo's table.[/p]
		[p]He said that he knew nothing of it. Sir Hugo had gone out in his carriage and might not return until evening. The other footman was also out on an errand. I asked if I might be allowed to look for the letter I had left, but he refused, saying that he could let no-one into the house until Sir Hugo returned.[/p]
		[p]I thought about the man in black. If I had taken the wrong letter, this might be the reason that he had followed me. I looked along the street to where I had seen him, but the street was now empty.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="10">I could return to my father's house.</next>
    <next id="11">He might write another letter but, this time, I would not have the assistance of Master Pepys to deliver it. I would still need a plague pass. Should I visit Mistress Slightly first?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="13">
    <text>
		[p]I pointed to the chimney and told the boy to lead the way. Ne climbed like a monkey, but it was wide with plenty of hand and footholds so that a chimney sweeper's boy might clean it. Being in the upper part of the house, it was not too long, and we were on the roof before I heard a knocking upon the door of the room below.[/p]
		[p]I heard the door open, footsteps enter the room and the voice of the man in black.[/p]
		[p]“I am forgetting,” he said, “that there is no need of knocking. We know that the mistress of this place is taking a bath in the yard below.”[/p]
		[p]There was laughter, and then the voice of the man who was called “Colonel”.[/p]
		[p]“From what I hear of this Mistress Slightly,” he said, “she has had a cleaner end than she might have deserved.”[/p]
		[p]There was more laughter and again the voice of the Colonel.[/p]
		[p]“Enough of the joke. What of the others?”[/p]
		[p]The man in black answered.[/p]
		[p]“Thy physician has been taken from his house and the body he was dissecting destroyed. He has been taken to a place where he will not be found. There was only a servant in the house and she thinks that he is gone to the pest house with the plague. The soap boiler knows nothing which can harm us. He would not go to the law and he cannot speak.”[/p]
		[p]“What of the child?” asked the Colonel.[/p]
		[p]“I have men in every place where the physician's child might go. I had thought that it might be here, but we will have the child within the day. Jacob will stay by the yard when we are gone.”[/p]
		[p]It was with horror that I realised that they were talking about my father and myself! What had become of my father? They left the room, and moments later, I saw them pass down the street. The third man was not with them. This must be Jacob who was to “stay by the yard”. We could not stay seated upon the roof like two black crows. I asked the boy how we might now get down.[/p]
		[p]“We cannot,” he said, “save by the way we reached it; and that way is now guarded!”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="16"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="14">
    <text>
		[p]Molly was still too upset to be of much help to me. I had to think for myself. The coach in which my father had been taken must now be long gone. There were many pest houses where some who had the plague were taken. My father could be in any of these, or he might have been taken to some quite different place.[/p]
		[p]Molly had said that a fire had been lit in the yard. The first thing that I must do was to be sure that it did not spread and burn down the house about us.[/p]
		[p]When I went into the yard, the fire was still blazing, though it was far enough from the house to be of no danger. I wondered why it had been lit and what had been burned upon it. I did not have to seek far for the answer. As I walked around it I saw, amongst the ashes at its edge, what remained of a charred human foot!.[/p]
		[p]I had not realised that Molly had joined me in the yard until I heard her scream behind me.[/p]
		[p]“The Lord have mercy!” she shrieked. “They have burned the master!”[/p]
		[p]I told her that I was sure that they had not. I looked towards the door which led to the forbidden part of the house. It stood open.[/p]
		[p]“The body of a plague victim was delivered here last night. That is what is on the fire.”[/p]
		[p]I walked towards the open door. Molly hesitated.[/p]
		[p]“Come,” I said. “You must know what my father did in here as well as I.”[/p]
		[p]“I've dreamed on it,” she replied, “but it was never my wish to see it.”[/p]
		[p]She followed me through the door. There was a large table of wood with blood stains upon it, but there was no body. The shelves and benches which surrounded the room were still filled with bottles and vessels and metal instruments of frightening appearance. Little seemed to have been disturbed except that it looked as if books and furniture had been used to light the fire in the yard. Whoever had come to the house, part of their purpose had been to destroy the body.[/p]
		[p]I had to find my father, but first, I needed to seek help.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="17">I thought of two places; my father's friend, Master Evelyn.</next>
    <next id="18">Or the woman who had brought the body in the night, Mistress Slightly.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="15">
    <text>
		[p]The shoes looked so ridiculous, bobbing on the surface of the frothing liquid, that I was about to laugh at the sight. Then, to my great horror, I saw something else rise to the surface. Though the flesh upon it had been eaten away in part by the boiling, caustic liquid, it was still recognisable as a human hand![/p]
		[p]Just as I was going to speak of it to the boy who was with me, three men entered the yard. One was the man in black with the scar upon his face. The other two, I did not know. One was a big man of rough appearance. The third had a face as rascally as the other two, but was well dressed in fashionable clothes. From the open window, I couldn't hear much of the conversation which was going on between them, but I did hear the man in black address the man in fashionable clothes as “Colonel”.[/p]
		[p]I called the boy over to the window and asked if he knew any of them. He shook his head and said that the soap boiler was not one of the three.[/p]
		[p]They moved towards the door by which we ; had entered the building. I had to think what to do. I knew that there was a body in one of the boiling vats. I also knew that the man in black was, in some way, connected with Sir Hugo Donkey, who was a Justice of the Peace. There might be no better person to whom I could report what I had seen. I did not like the look of any of the men, but the well-dressed man had been called “Colonel” and though of unpleasant appearance, sounded to be well spoken.[/p]
		[p]I hesitated because if I drew their attention I should also have to explain my own presence here. I asked the boy if there was any other way out of the building.[/p]
		[p]“There be the chimney,” he replied. “Man who had this room before Mistress Slightly, he was a Quaker preacher. If they came to arrest him for his preaching, he did often leave by the chimney.”[/p]
		[p]I asked what had happened to him.[/p]
		[p]“ He be in Newgate Prison” was the reply. “They did come for him one day when the fire was alight. He did give himself up after being much scorched about his lower parts.”[/p]
		[p]I could hear footsteps on the stair.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="20">Should I wait and speak with them?</next>
    <next id="13">Or follow the example of the preacher and take to the chimney?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="16">
    <text>
		[p]I had to discover what had happened to my father. The boy was so young that I was not certain that he would understand, but I told him all that I knew and explained that my father and I might be in great danger.[/p]
		[p]“We must wait,” he said. He pointed to the clock on the steeple of St Giles. “When it has passed nine of the clock and the large hand points to the bottom, the man who stands by the yard will leave.”[/p]
		[p]I asked him how he could know that.[/p]
		[p]“It is the time of curfew,” he said, “when those who are locked in their houses for the plague can come upont the streets. There will be those among them who do have the plague upon them. The man will not wait by the yard for fear of meeting them.”[/p]
		[p]I thought that the boy could be right, but it was many hours 'till curfew. I looked along the rooftop. There was another chimney stack not far from where we sat. The boy saw me looking and shook his head.[/p]
		[p]“There be plague in that house,” he said. “The windows below be nailed shut and there be a guard upon the door.”[/p]
		[p]I turned to ask if he was quite sure that there was no way we could climb down, when I saw that the boy had begun to crawl along the ridge of the roof to the end which looked down over the soap boiler's yard.[/p]
		[p]I saw him throw something down, then flatten himself on the roof. A moment later, he crawled back towards me.[/p]
		[p]“If you wants to take your chance,” he said, “there's a way that both of us can get down.”[/p]
		[p]The plan was a simple one. I would climb back down the chimney, go down the stair, and wait at the door which led to the yard. The boy would go to the end of the roof and throw tiles at the metal vats. The man guarding the entrance to the yard would come to see what was happening. I must wait my chance to slip from the yard. I asked the boy how he would escape.[/p]
		[p]“I'll be a chimney sweeper's boy,” he said, “what has come down the wrong chimney. Nobody is looking for me and nobody will stop me.”[/p]
		[p]I knew that the risk was greater than it sounded. I must not be caught.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="21">Should I take the risk?</next>
    <next id="19">Or wait for curfew?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="17">
    <text>
		[p]I did not have a pass to reach the house where Master Evelyn lived, but now the matter was desperate. I took some of my father's money, hoping that I might bribe one of the guards upon the streets or, at least, have one of them take a message to Master Evelyn's house.[/p]
		[p]Thinking it might be safer, I left my father's house by the door in the yard which led to the alley. I had gone no more than a few steps down the alley, when I was siezed roughly from behind. I struggled, but it was of no use. The man who held me forced some liquid from a small bottle down my throat. I felt a weakness come over my limbs, my head began to swim, and I remembered no more.[/p]
		[p]When I came to my senses, I was lying on the floor of a strange room with little furniture in it. I tried the door, but it was locked. I went to the window. I was looking down into a yard. Barrels and sacks were stacked around it and, in the centre, great metal vats boiled and bubbled upon coal fires. I knew that it was a soap boiler's yard and was wondering where it might be when I heard a voice.[/p]
		[p]“Up here!”[/p]
		[p]The room was empty. The voice seemed to come from the chimney! I crossed the room, stepped into the empty hearth and looked up. Framed in a square of light above me, I could see the dirty face of a young boy.[/p]
		[p]“Come up,” he said. “It's easy. There are plenty of hand and footholds.”[/p]
		[p]I thought that I had little choice. It was not so easy as the boy had said, but I reached the top and he helped me out onto the roof.[/p]
		[p]“I was in the room when they brought you here,” the boy told me. “I had come seeking Mistress Slightly who lived in the room below.”[/p]
		[p]I noticed that he said “lived”.[/p]
		[p]“She was less fortunate than you,” the boy said. “The ones who brought you here; they cut her throat and put her body into one of the vats in the yard below.”[/p]
		[p]“Is there another way we can get down from here?” I asked.[/p]
		[p]The boy shook his head.[/p]
		[p]“I could open the lock of the door below, but they have left a man to guard the entrance to the yard.”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="16"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="18">
    <text>
		[p]Hog Lane was no great distance from my father's house. When I got there, the place was crowded. There were two taverns in the lane and, being a hot day, many were drinking their ale in the street outside. I asked several if they knew of Mistress Slightly, but none did. Most said that they were strangers who had come only for the cock fighting in one of the taverns. I must ask around in the Rookery itself.[/p]
		[p]It was a worse place than I could have imagined. The streets were dark, the upper parts of the houses overhanging the cobbles and almost meeting the houses on the other side. Foul smelling filth rotted on the ground, the gutter which ran down the centre of the cobbles having become completely blocked.[/p]
		[p]At the corner of an alley, a boy of no more than seven or eight, sat upon a barrel, smoking quite the largest pipe that I had ever seen. He said that it was his father's; that his father was one of those who led a cart about the streets at night, collecting the dead. The pipe was a “plague pipe”, made large to hold more baccy and so give better protection against the plague.[/p]
		[p]The boy knew Mistress Slightly. She lived above the soap boiler's yard. For a penny, he would take me to her.[/p]
		[p]We reached the yard through a narrow entrance. Barrels of tallow and sacks of wood ash and lime lined the walls. In the centre, great metal vats of boiling liquid frothed and bubbled over coal fires. The place smelled of smoke and rancid fat.[/p]
		[p]There was no sight of the soap boiler. The boy led me across the yard to a door which opened onto a steep, narrow stair. I followed him up. At the top was a second door upon which he knocked lightly. There being no answer, the boy pushed it open.[/p]
		[p]The room beyond was small and had little furniture in it. By the small window that looked out over the yard stood three men. They were turned away from me, but I recognised one as the man in black. The second was a big, rough fellow. The third was fashionably dressed and I heard the rough man address him as “Colonel”.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="20"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="19">
    <text>
		[p]Two hours passed and there was a movoment on the roof of the house opposite. From the other side of the roof, a man appeared, a giant of a man – a man whom I had seen before when he had carried the body into my father's yard in the dead of night![/p]
		[p]The man sat, straddled upon the ridge of the roof and I saw that he was pulling up behind him a great plank of timber. He eased himself down the side of the roof towards us. Holding the plank by one end, as if it weighed no more than a feather, he lowered it so that it formed a bridge from the roof upon which we sat. The boy stood up.[/p]
		[p]“Come on,” he said. “You wanted to be off this roof. You're not afeared of height?”[/p]
		[p]I said that I wasn't, but the boy could see that I still hesitated. He suddenly smiled.[/p]
		[p]“It is the man!” he said. “He will not harm you. That is my friend the soap boiler. He is called Angel.”[/p]
		[p]I followed the boy across the plank. Angel helped me to the ridge of the other roof, gave an odd grunt, and pointed. I could see the top of a ladder. The boy and I climbed down it to the yard behind while Angel recovered the plank from the roof.[/p]
		[p]“He cannot speak,” said the boy, “not since he was hanged at Tyburn. Someone else confessed to the crime while he was hanging there. They cut him down, but now he has no voice.”[/p]
		[p]Angel had now joined us in the yard. He made signs to the boy which I could see that the boy understood. From the boy's questions, I knew that I was part of what was being said between them. The boy turned to me.[/p]
		[p]“Angel does not know what is afoot, but he knows the man who is behind it all. He has had many names, but now calls himself Colonel Blood. You are in much danger. Blood, pays well and has many spies. You must leave here, but it would not be safe until after dark. Angel will hide you.”[/p]
		[p]Angel led me out of the yard to a place not far away. We stopped beside a house in one of the narrow alleys. Angel looked up and down the alley to be certain that no-one was about who might have seen us, pushed open the door, and led me inside.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="27"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="20">
    <text>
		[p]The man in black was the first to see me. “This,” he said, “is the physician's child.” The man whom he had called “Colonel” asked, “Who is the other?”[/p]
		[p]The boy answered for himself.[/p]
		[p]“I was given a penny to show where Mistress Slightly might be. This be where she do live.”[/p]
		[p]“Then you have earned your penny,” said the Colonel. “Now be off with you.”[/p]
		[p]The boy left. The Colonel turned to me.[/p]
		[p]“I regret,” he said, “that you may not see Mistress Slightly. She is in the yard below, taking a hot bath – so hot that I fear she may have been overcome by it.”[/p]
		[p]The other two laughed. I could picture the boiling vats of soap and felt sick at the thought of it.[/p]
		[p]“I mean you no harm,” the Colonel said, “but there are reasons to keep you out of the way for a little while. My friends here will take good care of you.”[/p]
		[p]I bluffed.[/p]
		[p]“If you know who I am,” I said, “then you know that my father is a man of some importance; and a friend of Sir Hugo Donkey, the Justice of the Peace.”[/p]
		[p]That brought still more laughter.[/p]
		[p]“Your father,” said the Colonel, “has also been removed to a safe place. He is well and unharmed. If you want him to stay that way then you will give us no bother.”[/p]
		[p]He turned to the other two.[/p]
		[p]“What of the soap boiler?” he asked.[/p]
		[p]“He knows nothing,” answered the man in black, “and if he did, we know that he cannot speak of it. He will not go to the law.”[/p]
		[p]“Very well,” said the Colonel. “Our business here is finished. Let us be gone.”[/p]
		[p]He led the way down the stair, the man in black following. The third man took me by the shoulder and pushed me after them.[/p]
		[p]As I stepped into the yard, I saw the boy. He was standing by the entrance. In front of him stood a giant of a man – the same man who had brought the body to my father's house in the dead of night.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="24"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="21">
    <text>
		[p]As the boy had hoped, the sound of the tiles striking the metal vats brought the man who stood guard, into the yard. The plan would have worked if he had not seen me as I made my run for the entrance.[/p]
		[p]The man was big, but moved quickly, in an instant, he had cut off my way of escape. I was about to turn and run back the way I had come, when I saw that he had stopped and was looking towards the entrance.[/p]
		[p]A second man had appeared in the yard; a giant of a man – a man who I had seen once before when he carried a body into my father's house in the dead of night![/p]
		[p]The man who had been about to sieze me drew a knife from his doublet and moved towards the newcomer. I watched the giant pick up one of the barrels of tallow which were stacked around the walls. He flung it at the man with the knife. The barrel knocked him to the ground, breaking about him and covering him with tallow, soft from the heat of the day. The giant moved nearer. The man lifted himself from the ground and made a lunge at the giant with his knife. The knife clattered onto the stones. The giant had lifted him into the air, as if he were no more than a small child, and hurled him across the yard. The man fell on the fire which burned beneath one of the boiling vats. The tallow in which he was covered burst into flame. Screaming, he rose from the fire, blazing like a human torch until, in his blind panic, he pulled the vat of boiling liquid down upon himself. The screaming stopped. There was only the hiss and splutter of the liquid upon the dying fire.[/p]
		[p]I backed away in terror. The boy's voice called to me from the roof.[/p]
		[p]“He will not harm you. This is my friend, the soap boiler. He is called Angel. He cannot speak, but give him your hand.”[/p]
		[p]The boy joined us in the yard. Angel may have had no voice, but it seemed that he could speak in signs and that the boy could understand him.[/p]
		[p]“Angel does not know what is afoot,” said the boy, “but he knows the man who is behind it all. He is known by the name of Colonel Blood. You must leave here, but it will not be safe until after dark. Angel will hide you until then.”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="27"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="22">
    <text>
		[p]The boy went off and Angel led me out of The Rookery as far as Hog's Lane. I did not yet know how I might get past the guards in the streets but I knew that I must reach Master Evelyn.[/p]
		[p]We were stopped from entering the Lane by a crowd which had gathered about a man whose clothes made him look like an actor. His breeches and boots were of fine leather. His shirt was frilled. His doublet and cloak were of velvet and trimmed with braid. Upon one arm, and dressed in a red velvet jacket, was a small monkey. On the ground beside him was a brass bound box filled with all manner of bottles and boxes. He was holding up one such bottle before the crowd and addressing them in dramatic tones which well matched his actor's dress.[/p]
		[p]“It was to this elixir that Methuselah attributed his reaching the great age of seven hundred and twenty years.”[/p]
		[p]“But will it cure corns on the feet?” shouted someone in the crowd.[/p]
		[p]I was waiting to hear what the man would answer when he looked in our direction and, seeing Angel towering above the crowd, stepped towards him.[/p]
		[p]“Here is a man,” he said, “who has long had faith in my medicines. Look at the great size to which he has grown upon them!”[/p]
		[p]He thrust a bottle into Angel's hand.[/p]
		[p]“Take this,” he said. “It is what you ordered for the disorder caused by the blood. By the blood,” he repeated. “There is much of it about in this place.”[/p]
		[p]I saw two men moving towards us from the crowd. The man with the monkey stepped in front of them, taking each by the arm.[/p]
		[p]“Stay gentlemen and I will show you a small miracle.”[/p]
		[p]The crowd moved around them wanting to see what was about to happen, and preventing the men from moving. Angel took me by the arm and hurried me back the way that we had come. I too had understood the message. Blood's men were about and looking for me.[/p]
		[p]Angel looked about him to be sure that we were not followed, pushed me through the doorway of one of the houses and led me to a back room not overlooked from the street.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="27"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="23">
    <text>
		[p]Eyes turned upon the man with the monkey. “We do not yet know,” he said, “what it is that this Blood is plotting. That he expects it to be most profitable, we may judge from his seeming to be spending much money upon it. He has been to a cart maker and had three carts made. They are like plague carts in appearance, but one is made much stronger, as if to hold a great weight, and two will float upon water.”[/p]
		[p]This last information brought a gasp of astonishment.[/p]
		[p]“We do know,” Doctor Hermeticus continued, “that a body plays some part in the plot; a body which was not meant to be found, but buried as another victim of the plague. Blood seeks all those who saw, or might know something of this body: Mistress Slightly, the physician, and now the child. He cannot know that Angel carried the body for some way and saw something of it. It was a man of perhaps forty years, dark skinned and with some clothing upon him, which might have been silk and was foreign in its appearance. That is all we know – except there are now many looking for this child whom they are certain is about this place.”[/p]
		[p]I had already said that I wished to reach my father's friend. Master Evelyn. That was possible, but not certain. It had been found that Master Evelyn was not at his house in Friday Street. He could be at his lodging in the Tower of London where he was a Commissioner of the Mint. It would lake another day to make certain. If Master Evelyn was at the Tower, I could be taken there secretly the next night, with the plague carts.[/p]
		[p]There was another choice. Doctor Hermeticus had a friend in the City of Oxford. There, I would be safe and I could leave that night with the tobacco smugglers. I had thought tobacco was grown in the Americas and smuggled through France. It seemed that this tobacco, though sold as “Virginia”, was grown no further away than Gloucestershire. Oxford was a stop on the smugglers' road.[/p]
		[p]The choice was mine.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="28">I could leave that night for Oxford.</next>
    <next id="25">I would rather wait and be taken to Master Evelyn, but if he could not be found I would be stuck here because the smugglers would not return for several days.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="24">
    <text>
		[p]The Colonel turned to the big man who held me and barked out his order.[/p]
		[p]“Jacob! Take him!”[/p]
		[p]Jacob moved towards the entrance. The man in black held me by the arm. The giant of a man had not moved. I saw Jacob pull a knife from his doublet. He lunged at the giant with it.[/p]
		[p]In the next instant, Jacob was no longer on the ground. The giant had lifted him from his feet and flung him across the yard. His body struck one of the boiling vats. I saw it topple and empty its scalding contents upon the man beneath it. His screams were terrible to hear![/p]
		[p]The giant moved forward into the yard. The Colonel drew his sword. Suddenly, the screaming stopped. The man in black released my arm and fled from the yard. The Colonel stepped forward, his sword held before him. The giant lifted a barrel of tallow. His aim was deadly. The sword spun from the Colonel's hand, and the barrel burst open as it struck him and threw him to the ground. He tried to get to his feet, but could not for the greasy tallow which was caked upon his shoes. The giant picked him up with one hand, carried him, cursing and struggling to the entrance, and flung him into the street. He did not return. The giant now moved towards me. “Give him your hand!” shouted the boy. “He cannot speak, but he will not harm you. This is my friend, the soap boiler. His name is Angel.”[/p]
		[p]I took the huge hand in mine and made my thanks. The man smiled and made a strange grunt in his throat.[/p]
		[p]“He has not spoken since he was hanged at Tyburn,” said the boy. “Someone else confessed to the crime while he was hanging there. They cut him down while he was still alive, but now he has no voice.”[/p]
		[p]Angel pulled down a rough cloth which was tied about his neck. Beneath it was the purple weal of a rope mark which circled his throat from ear to ear.[/p]
		[p]“You must go from here,” said the boy. “The man with the sword is known in these parts. He has had many names, but now calls himself Colonel Blood. If you have friends, Angel will see you on your way. If you want to wait 'till dark, we will hide you.”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="22">Should I leave?</next>
    <next id="27">Or should I stay here?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="25">
    <text>
		[p]The woman who sold fish by the Tower of London, knew one of the keepers of the animal menagerie which was kept in the Lion Barbican at the entrance to the Tower. Both he, and the Yeoman Warder of the Middle Tower – the gateway beyond it – were certain that Master Evelyn was staying there at his lodging.[/p]
		[p]A rough cloak of sacking was found for me, complete with a hood to go over my head. I was tall for my age and would look no different to the others who walked with the carts. At a little after two of the clock there was a tapping at the street door of the house where I had been hidden. The cart stood outside with three men around it. They looked like myself though, from the height of one, I knew that is was Angel. Master Stout gave me a bell to ring as we moved through the alleys. I had only to ring my bell and keep close by the cart. I was given a large pipe of tobacco and told to keep it in my mouth like the others, even if I could not bring myself to smoke it.[/p]
		[p]We moved slowly, I ringing the bell. Master Stout calling the familiar cry of “Bring out your dead.” Often, we would stop to pick up a body which had been left on the street, or to wait while one was carried from a house to the cart.[/p]
		[p]We had left The Rookery and were nearing the edge of the parish of St Giles, where Angel would take me on, alone. We had stopped to take yet another body from the street, when the man who had gone to lift it a called to Master Stout, “This one is alive!”[/p]
		[p]I saw Master Stout go over to where the man lay, holding his horn lantern above him to give light. There were whispered words. The man was lifted to his feet and Master Stout came back to me.[/p]
		[p]“The man is a Quaker,” he said, “a preacher who lived in the house of Mistress Slightly before he was taken to Newgate Prison for his preaching. He has been pursued and is much exhausted, but says that those who were in Newgate and Ludgate for their preaching have been taken to a ship, the [em]Black Eagle[/em], at Greenwich. He says that there is a physician among them. The Quaker escaped before they boarded the ship, but says that the ship is well guarded.”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="32">Should I go on with Angel?</next>
    <next id="31">Or was my business now at Greenwich?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="26">
    <text>
		[p]It was some long time before the horseman moved off. I stayed in the water until many minutes had passed and I still could hear no sound. I climbed out of the water and I returned to the gates of Syon House. There was no-one about. Of the smugglers, the soldiers, or the donkeys, there was no sign. I didn't know this part of the countryside at all. If I was to get back to The Rookery. I must try to return by the way that we had come.[/p]
		[p]By dawn, I had reached Kensigngton. I knew that if I went on by the same road it would be full day light before I reached The Rookery. With Colonel Blood's men still watching for me, I must wait until dark and find some other place to spend the day.[/p]
		[p]I came to a road which turned off to the north and asked a man who was starting work in a nearby field where it would lead me. He told me the gravel pits upon the Oxford road. I asked if the pits were still worked and he told me not these several years. It sounded a good place to spend the day.[/p]
		[p]I found fresh water at a spring, though I had no food. I spent much of the day sleeping so that my mind might not dwell upon my hunger. At dark, I set off for The Rookery.[/p]
		[p]Perhaps it was my clothes and my dirty appearance which allowed me to walk through The Rookery unnoticed and to find the house of Master Stout.[/p]
		[p]I was not the only unexpected guest in the house. The other was a Quaker; a preacher who had once lived in the house of Mistress Slightly, before he was taken to Newgate Prison for his preaching. He had arrived after I had left on the previous night, much exhausted. He had explained that those who were in Newgate and Ludgate for their preaching had been moved to a prison ship, the [em]Black Eagle[/em], at Greenwich. He had excapéd as they were being taken aboard. He had also said that there was a man among them who claimed to be a physician. The preacher, though recovering, was still weak and Hermeticus had given him a strong draught which would make him sleep until morning.[/p]
		[p]Master Evelyn was at the Tower.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="32">I could leave with the plague carts that night and Angel would see me to the Tower.</next>
    <next id="31">If I wished to speak to the preacher, I must wait until morning.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="27">
    <text>
		[p]It was now dark. There would be few people out in the streets save those from the houses where there was plague. Locked in through the day, they were now allowed to venture out. Soon, the carts would begin their nightly round, collecting the dead, some of whom would have been thrown upon the streets, just as they had died. It was probably such a body that Mistress Slightly had brought to my father's house.[/p]
		[p]Several people had now gathered in the small room where I had been hidden through the day, and a stranger company I could never expect to meet. Some I knew. Some, I did not. There was the boy who had helped me, and his father. Angel was there. There was the man who sold medicines in Hog Lane with his monkey perched upon his shoulder. There was a woman who sold fish by the Tower of London, and an ink seller from Cheapside. The boy had told me who they all were, but it was too many to remember.[/p]
		[p]I was not included in the talking. The boy and I sat in a corner, drinking ale and sharing a cold mutton pie.[/p]
		[p]When the taling stopped, I was called to the centre of the room. The boy's father was to be spokesman for the rest. I now knew him as Master William Stout; the boy as Peter.[/p]
		[p]“It has been decided,” said Master Stout, “that we should help you. If you be thinking that it is not natural for the likes of us to be helping the likes of you, I will be telling you the why of it.”[/p]
		[p]He cleared his throat and I could tell that he was not used to making long speeches.[/p]
		[p]“The one reason is that we have no liking for the one who calls himself Blood; and the less so after he done away with Mistress Slightly –” He looked at Angel, “– and spoiled a day's boiling of soap. There are some as might not agree, but there's many here who the Mistress has helped when times were hard.”[/p]
		[p]There was a general murmur of approval.[/p]
		[p]“The other reason is that your father was one who stayed when most of his kind have fled the city. I now call upon Doctor Hermeticus to give an account of what we be knowing.”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="23"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="28">
    <text>
		[p]I was found some clothes which would make me look more like one of the smugglers and had just finished changing into them when the smugglers arrived.[/p]
		[p]There was only time to introduce me to their leader, a Master Nathaniel Crump of the town of Winchcombe. They were eager to be off. They dared travel only at night and hoped to be halfway to the city of Oxford by dawn. I joined the four men and six donkeys which waited in the street.[/p]
		[p]The main road to Oxford led out of London past the Tyburn gibbet, but it was rumoured that mounted patrols of soldiers had been seen on that road several times in the past few days. Master Crump had decided that we should go by a different road, further to the south. We would return to the main Oxford road, but no until we were several miles out of London.[/p]
		[p]The donkeys were carrying no loads and I had been allowed to ride one of them. We had been on our way for a full two hours and were passing the gates to the grounds Syon House, when we heard the sound of horses. A rising moon gave enough light to see that it was a troop of cavalry. With no time to get the donkeys off the road, we left the animals and ran.[/p]
		[p]The gates of Syon House were open and I made for the grounds, hoping to lose myself in the trees. I had not run far, when I found myself on the banks of a river and realised that it was the Thames. I was a poor swimmer. The river was wide and, if the currents were fast, I had no chance of reaching the other side. I could hear the sound of a horseman coming through the trees. I lowered myself into the water amongst the reeds.[/p]
		[p]The water was cold, but I guessed that if I stayed still the horseman would not see me and would give up the search. When the horsemen had gone, I could try to make my own way back to The Rookery.[/p]
		[p]I had another choice. I had broken no law. If I gave myself up to the soldiers – and if they believed my story – this might be another way of reaching Master Evelyn.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="26">Should I wait?</next>
    <next id="30">Or should I give myself up?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="29">
    <text>
		[p]Master Evelyn might not return to the Tower until the following day. I would stay at his lodging and sleep there but, since he had no servants in the Tower, I would eat with the Yeoman Warder and his wife in the “Tower at the Gate”, near to the Lieutenant's house.[/p]
		[p]They had a daughter a little older than myself and she took me to some places which I had not seen with Master Evelyn on the previous day. These included the dungeons below the White Tower which had housed many famous prisoners. I ended the morning helping to feed the lions and tigers in the cages outside the Lieutenant's house and returned to my lodging to wash before my midday meal.[/p]
		[p]It was then that I heard a tapping upon my window. As it was a place to which it was impossible to climb, I thought it must be a bird; but the tapping came again and I caught a flash of red upon the window ledge. I opened the window. A monkey sprang into my arm. Pinned to its red jacket was a paper. I removed the pin and read what was upon the paper.[/p]
		[p]“Your father is aboard [em]Black Eagle[/em]. Have plan to rescue him. Angel will wait for you at Queen's Stair on Tower Wharf at sunset. Hermeticus.”[/p]
		[p]The monkey was gone the way it had come. I looked below but could not pick out Hermeticus in the crowd which was gathered about the cages. That evening, having eaten, I returned to my lodging for a cloak and stout shoes, and was hurrying towards the gates before they were closed at sunset.[/p]
		[p]I was almost at the Tower at the Gate when I heard voices behind me. I turned to see a group of men standing by the caged animals. They had not been there when I had passed the cages moments before. It was as if they had appeared from nowhere! They were moving towards me. Something told me to step back quickly into the shadows. The men passed me, making not for the gate, but entering Mint Street.[/p]
		[p]Suddenly, another man came running past. Though the light was fading, I was certain that it was the man with the scar; the man in black! He followed the others. I had little time. The gates would be closing.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="37">Should I meet Angel?</next>
    <next id="35">Or follow the man in black?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="30">
    <text>
		[p]I had one piece of good fortune. The horseman who had followed me to the river bank was the lieutenant in command of the troop of cavalry. He must have known from my age and voice that I was not one of the usual tobacco smugglers but, when I mentioned the name of Colonel Blood, he stopped me in my story.[/p]
		[p]“Come,” he said. “Mount up behind me. There is someone not far from here who will want to hear all that you have to tell.”[/p]
		[p]The troop was reassembled and I noticed that all of the smugglers seemed to have avoided capture. We rode south, a distance of some three miles, stopping at the gateway of a house of great size. I asked where we were and was told, the Palace of Hampton Court. After some words of explanation from the lieutenant, I was handed over to a man whom I took to be a servant. I was given a fine bedchamber for the night and promised that a change of clothes would be found for me.[/p]
		[p]In the morning they brought me some clothes; they didn't fit too well, but at least they were clean. I was then taken into the gardens to meet a man named Master Chiffinch.[/p]
		[p]He talked to me as we walked through the gardens. He spoke to me kindly enough, though asked such a great many questions, that I was glad when he seemed satisfied that I had told him all I knew.[/p]
		[p]“Blood is a man well known to us,” he told me, “as daring as he is ruthless. Always, he has escaped us and i would dearly wish to know what latest scheme he has afoot. As for your father's friend, Master Evelyn, he is at the Tower. I left him there, only last evening. I return there myself, tonight. We will travel by boat and reach the Tower in the morning. I would take some rest before we set out on the journey.”[/p]
		[p]As we had walked through the gardens, I had noticed a man, tall, lean faced, of dark complexion and with black curly hair. He was practising with a ball and mallet, the aim, it seemed, to strike the ball through a ring hung above the ground. I asked Master Chiffinch what game the man played.[/p]
		[p]“It is called 'Pall Mall'” he replied, “and the 'man' is Charles II, King of England.”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="32"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="31">
    <text>
		[p]The preacher described the man whom he thought to be a physician. It was an exact description of my father. The preacher said that the man seemed either drunk or drugged. He had said that he was from neither Newgate nor Ludgate, that he was a physician and had been brought there againts his will. The preacher had escaped as they were being put aboard the ship.[/p]
		[p]I asked whether the guards would release my father when he told them who he was and how he had come there. I was told they would not. There were some among the prisoners who thought that they were the king of England. They would think my father but another of the madmen.[/p]
		[p]I spent the next day at the house of Master Stout while a plan was made to rescue my father. I left The Rookery after dark, following one of the plague carts as far as Drury Lane. There, Angel and Doctor Hermeticus went on with me to a place on the river called Temple Stairs.[/p]
		[p]A boat awaited us, and a boatman, who would row us down river to Greenwich. Already aboard the boat, arid stowed in the bow, was a large barrel of ale.[/p]
		[p]The boatman knew just where the [em]Black Eagle[/em] was moored. Het took us to a landing higher up river, but near enough to make out the dark shape of the ship against the night sky. Angel lifted the barrel from the boat and carried it up the stair to the quay. When Hermeticus and I had joined him, he began to roll it towards the \i Black Eagle\i0 . When we were almost at the ship, Hermeticus picked upon the entrance to a dark alley and told me to wait there until he and Angel returned.[/p]
		[p]“Watch this,” he said, “and you will see a piece of play acting which would put to shame anything they might put upon the stage in the theatre at Drury Lane.”[/p]
		[p]Angel went on rolling the barrel towards the ship's gang plank. A little before he had reached it, Hermeticus went running after him, and shouting.[/p]
		[p]“You are a thief, sir! Yon barrel of ale is mine and I did win it fair with the dice!”[/p]
		[p]Angel stopped and Hermeticus threw himself upon him. Though Angel could have killed Hermeticus with one hand, he let himself fall to the ground. The play had begun![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="34"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="32">
    <text>
		[p]We reached the Tower at dawn and I wa taken to the lodging of Master Evelyn which was near to the entrance and a part of the house of Sir John Robinson, the Lieutenant of the Tower. There, I was told to wait.[/p]
		[p]Though it was early in the morning, there seemed much activity. Master Evelyn, Sir John Robinson and Master Chiffinch. who I was told was secretary to the King, were seeing to the arrival of some nev animals for the menagerie. I later learned that there were two African lions and thirty ostrich birds; a present to King Charles from the Moroccan Ambassador. The Ambassador had insisted that the ostriches could not be kept in the travelling cages and, to house them in the menagerie, four lions, including the two newly arrived, and three tigers had been placed in the travelling cages outside the Lieutenant's house until new arrangements could be made.[/p]
		[p]When Master Evelyn returned, he was not in good humour. The Ambassador had been to the Tower no less than four times in the last three days. Apart from the problems which his animals had brought, he had wanted to be shown every corner of the Tower. As one of the Commissioners of the Mint, Master Evelyn had had to take him around those buildings, where he had asked endless questions; even visiting the living quarters of the Mint staff. The only thing which Master Evelyn could say in his favour was that he spoke the most excellent English. It was now time to tell my story.[/p]
		[p]Master Evelyn was most kind. He promised me that matters would be put in hand, at once, to find my father. As for myself, I should remain under his personal protection. Later that day, he would show me round the Tower.[/p]
		[p]The Tower menagerie was situated at the entrance to the Tower. I had visited that with my father. I had never before been inside the – Tower itself. I knew that the King had apartments within the Tower his coronation procession had begun there – but I thought of it most as a place where famous prisoners were kept. I had not dreamed that so much went on within its walls or that such a great number of people both worked and lived there.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="33"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="33">
    <text>
		[p]I was shown the royal apartments, the great arsenal and the garrison quarters. I was taken to the Martin Tower where Master Edwards, the deputy keeper, showed me the crown jewels which were stored there, and allowed me to hold the crown of St Edward in my hands.[/p]
		[p]From there, we went to the Mint. It was not just a building, but a whole street, known as Mint Street, housed between the inner and outer walls of the Tower. The buildings against the inner wall included the Mint itself where gold and silver bullion were made into coins. Against the outer wall were the houses of the mint staff, some shops, and even a blacksmithy. Much building work was going on among the houses and several were empty. Master Evelyn explained that the King had ordered the Mint to be greatly enlarged and fitted with new machinery.[/p]
		[p]It would have been a more exciting day, but for my worry about my father, though I slept well that night, even with the roar of lions and snarl of tigers outside my window. The next morning, Master Evelyn announced that he must return to his house in St John's.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="36">He said that I could go with him.</next>
    <next id="29">Or wait in the Tower for his return.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="34">
    <text>
		[p]Though Angel had no voice, Hermeticus did enough shouting for both men. The mock battle went on, ending with Hermeticus chasing Angel from the quay. The noise had brought the guards to the rail of the ship and I could hear their laughter as they watched Hermeticus chase the giant into the darkness. The barrel still lay by the ship.[/p]
		[p]Minutes later, I heard Hermeticus's voice whisper behind me.[/p]
		[p]“Now we wait for them to come from the ship and take the barrel. The night is hot and they know that the barrel is filled with ale.”[/p]
		[p]“You hope to make them drunk with the ale?” I asked.[/p]
		[p]“More than that,” answered Hermeticus. “I have added something to the ale. Having drunk it, they will be certain that they are poisoned; and then what think you will they do?”[/p]
		[p]I saw the plan. They would fetch the man from below deck who said that he was a physician![/p]
		[p]The barrel was taken aboard. An hour later cries and groans could be heard on the deck. I heard someone shout, “I die. Fetch the one who says he is a physician!” Angel moved towards the ship. I saw him mount the gang plank. There was more shouting and two splashes in the water. Angel reappeared, running down the plank and carrying someone upon his shoulder. A shot rang out, but Angel ran on. Hermeticus took my arm and hurried me back to the stairs where the boat which had brought us was still waiting. A moment later, Angel was on the stair and lowering my father into the boat. The shot had passed through the flesh of his leg which was bleeding a great deal.[/p]
		[p]There was much to tell as we rowed back to the city. The body of the man which had been brought to my father's house had been shot. Sewn within some clothing on the body were some papers which showed it to be that of the Moroccan Ambassador. My father was drugged when he had been taken from his house, but he had heard enough to know that what was afoot involved Sir Hugo Donkey and a man called Blood, and was to happen within the Tower of London. Which way should I advise them?[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="38">My father was for going straight to the Tower.</next>
    <next id="40">Hermeticus thought that he should first return to his house to dress his wound.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="35">
    <text>
		[p]I followed through one of the two archways which formed the way into Mint Street. Whatever was afoot, it must be in Mint Street itself. There was an exit at the farther end, but this had been completely closed until the completion of the new building work. There was no way in or out of the street except by the way I had come.[/p]
		[p]There was still enough light to see right along the street. The men had gone, but the man in black who had followed them was just entering one of the deserted buildings against the outer wall, just opposite to the building of the Mint itself. I followed.[/p]
		[p]The man had closed the door behind him but it was only latched, not locked. I lifted the latch gently and eased the door a little way open, so that I could see inside.[/p]
		[p]There was almost nothing left of the bilding except its outer walls. The floors had been removed and much of the roof, for I could see the darkening sky above me. A wood scaffolding had been erected across one end, from the outer to the inner wall and was the full height of the building. It could be climbed by a series of ladders. Ropes and pulleys hung from it and I supposed it to be the means of lowering the roof timbers as they were being removed. The place was lit by several lanterns hung about the scaffolding; but I could see no men![/p]
		[p]Then, I heard a voice somewhere above me.[/p]
		[p]“All is ready to begin. Colonel Blood asks if you have secured the door to the street. We want no visitors!”[/p]
		[p]I had thought that the man in black would de up to no good. Now I knew that Colonel Blood was here, I could be certain of it. I heard the reply.[/p]
		[p]“The door is latched. They are not the kind of visitors who can unlatch doors but, if it will please the Colonel, I will put the bar upon it.”[/p]
		[p]I did not understand the odd remark about visitors, but now I heard footsteps on the ladders above me. I looked around.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="39">I saw a place to hide.</next>
    <next id="42">But, if I wanted to raise the alarm, now might be my only chance to leave.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="36">
    <text>
		[p]Mister Evelyn's house in Friday Street was much the same size as our own, though he still had all of his servants, a manservant, a cook and two maids. He told me that he had business in several parts of the city that day and might not return to his house until late that evening. He was certain that I would be safe in the house until his return. He showed me two loaded pistols which were kept in a drawer of his desk. His manservant had been a sergeant in the army of Charles I and knew well how to use them.[/p]
		[p]The day passed slowly. Master Evelyn had many books, but I could not keep my mind upon them. My thoughts were still upon my father.[/p]
		[p]I sat at the window and watched the passers by in the street outside. An ink seller appeared, his small barrel and funnel upon his back, his goose quills in his hand and his cry of “Very fine writing ink, bright ink. Buy any ink. Will you buy any ink today?”[/p]
		[p]He stopped outside the house. No-one came out into the street, yet he seemed to stand there for a long time looking towards the windows of the house.[/p]
		[p]I was sure that I had seen the man before. I had often bought my father's ink and pens from such a seller, but this was not the man who I knew in Cripplegate. My mind turned to The Rookery. There had been an ink seller among those who had gathered with Master Stout and Angel and Doctor Hermeticus. The light had been dim, yet this could be the same man.[/p]
		[p]I went into the hallway and, making certain that none of the servants was about, I opened the street door. The ink seller walked quickly across to me. I had not spoken a word, when he said, “Yes. They are the finest of goose quills. You will find no better in the city. See how finely they will write. This was done with such a pen.”[/p]
		[p]He held up a piece of paper in front of me. On it was written, “Your father is aboard \i Black Eagle\i0 . Have plan to rescue him. Angel will wait for you at Paul's Wharf at sunset. This man will wait at the end of Friday Street to take you there. Hermeticus.”[/p]
		[p]The ink seller gave me two quills and was gone. Master Evelyn had not returned by evening. I left him a note and slipped quietly from the house.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="37"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="37">
    <text>
		[p]Angel was waiting for me on the wharf and a boat was moored below, in the river. A boatman rested upon his oars and Hermeticus was already seated in the stern, with what looked like a large barrel of ale beside him. Angel helped me into the boat and we began our journey down river to Greenwich.[/p]
		[p]Hermeticus said that the Quaker preacher was now much recovered and had been able to give a better description of the man whom he thought to be a physician. Hed had also remembered some other things which the man had said. It now seemed certain that it was indeed my father.[/p]
		[p]I had thought that the guards on the ship would release my father when they found who he was and how he had come to be there. Hermeticus didn't agree. The guards on the ship would know nothing of the prisoners except that they had come from Newgate and Ludgate gaols. There would be many among them who could be weak in the head and might claim to be anyone from John the Baptist to the King of England. They would think my father was just another of the madmen.[/p]
		[p]The boatman knew just where the \i Black Eagle \i0 was moored. He took us to a landing higher up the river, but near enough to make out the dark shape of the ship against the night sky. Angel lifted the barrel from the boat and carried it up the stair to the quay. When I and Hermeticus had joined him, he began to roll it towards the \i Black Eagle\i0 . When we were almost at the ship, Hermeticus picked upon the entrance to a dark alley and told me to wait there until he and Angel returned.[/p]
		[p]“Watch this,” he said, “and you will see a piece of play acting which would put shame to anything they might put upon the stage in the theatre at Drury Lane.”[/p]
		[p]Angel went on rolling the barrel towards the ship's gang plank. A little before he had reached it, Hermeticus went running after him, and shouting.[/p]
		[p]“You are a thief, sir! Yon barrel of ale is mine and I did win it fair with the dice!”[/p]
		[p]Angel stopped and Hermeticus threw himself upon him. Though Angel could have killed Hermeticus with one hand, he let himself fall to the ground. The play had begun![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="34"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="38">
    <text>
		[p]I knew that the gates of the Tower would be locked, but my father, certain that something would happen that night, was determined to go there and wake the guard.[/p]
		[p]With what little was to hand, Hermeticus had done a fine job on my father's leg. It still bled a little, but he felt that he could walk on it.[/p]
		[p]We landed at Tower Wharf and, with my father supported on either side by Angel and Hermeticus, set off towards the Tower entrance. My father was weaker than he would admit and had to stop to regain his breath. The moon was bright and we could see clearly right to the top of Tower Hill. As we waited, there horse-drawn carts suddenly appeared from the direction of Tower Street and headed off across the grass towards the Tower Moat. They looked like three plague carts, yet there was no reason why they should be travelling in that direction. They reached the moat and stopped there.[/p]
		[p]I knew that Blood had had three carts made, resembling plague carts, but of special design. Were these the carts? Hermeticus and I stayed with my father while Angel walked on to where the carts were standing.[/p]
		[p]We saw Angel reach the carts. There were two thuds, a splash and a muffled cry. I saw Angel signalling. He wanted us to join him.[/p]
		[p]One man floated on the water of the moat. Two others lay, senseless, on the ground. Angel mounted the first cart, signing to Hermeticus to take the second and my father and I, the third. We moved off with Angel leading the way.[/p]
		[p]We headed for Tower Street, turning up a small lane which brought us to the churchyard of All Hallows. Many plague carts were moving in and out of the churchyard. Angel stopped his cart amongst the ones which were empty and ready to leave. I saw what was in Angel's mind. The carts might be taken or left, either way, their real owner would not find them again that night![/p]
		[p]With difficulty, we helped my father back to the Tower where, after much knocking, we were admitted and taken to Sir John Robinson, Lieutenant of the Tower.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="44"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="39">
    <text>
		[p]I crouched down behind a pile of rubble. I saw the man in black pass me and go to the door. As he placed a bar of wood across it, there was a sound from the street outside – the road of a lion. It was answered by another, and then the hiss and snarl of a tiger. Someone had opened the cages![/p]
		[p]Whatever they were doing above me, they could be certain of not being disturbed. The soldiers of the Tower garrison might block the end of the street but I could see none venturing into it with lions and tigers on the loose. Those already living in the street would be barring themselves into their houses.[/p]
		[p]The man in black had returned to the scaffolding. From my hiding place, I could see little, but I could hear enough to build a picture in my mind.[/p]
		[p]Some kind of bridge was being slid out from the top of the scaffolding to the roof of the building opposite – the Mint! For some time, little seemed to happen and then, from the direction of the bridge, I recognised the sound of a small wheeled truck. It crossed the scaffolding to the outer wall. I heard the squeak of pulleys. The sounds were repeated as the truck moved back and forth from the bridge to the outer wall. I climbed the ladders but stayed below the platform across which the truck was moving. I heard a voice say, “No more. They are ready to move,” and then footsteps retreating back across the bridge.[/p]
		[p]When I was sure there was no-one above me I climbed onto the platform and crossed to the outer wall. In the moat below me, the moonlight shone upon two boats of curious shape. One was empty. In the other were two men about to lower muffled paddles into the water. A rope hung down the wall in front of me. The wall itself was in deep shadow and the men in the boat had their backs to me. I took my chance and slid down the rope into the water. As the boat began to move, I grasped its woodwork so that I would be towed through the water behind it.[/p]
		[p]I could now see the reason for its strange shape. It was not a boat, but a floating plague cart! I could make out a cart and horse waiting on the other side of the moat with two more horses tethered to it. I let go my hold and swam to the bank where I could see but not be seen.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="41"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="40">
    <text>
		[p]It was little more than four miles back to the city. We had covered half that distance and were passing by the Isle of Dogges when Hermeticus told the boatman to rest his oars so that he could listen. We heard the sound of another boat, with perhaps four or six oars, closing in behind us. We had only two oars. Angel exchanged places with the boatman. What Angel may have lacked in rowing skill he more than made up for in strength. The boat leapt forward, its bow lifting, the bow waves throwing spray upon us in the stern.[/p]
		[p]At Tower Wharf, we paused again. The boat was still behind us, but now its sound was more distant. We rowed on beneath London Bridge and to the steps at Queenhithe.[/p]
		[p]My father limped as far as Cheapside with Angel and Hermeticus supporting him on either side. Angel carried him upon his back for the rest of the way. We roused Molly from her bed and while she prepared food and drink, Hermeticus cleaned and dressed my father's wound. His time aboard the \i Black Eagle \i0 and the wound in his leg had sapped much of his strength and he could not be moved again that night.[/p]
		[p]At dawn, Hermeticus left and returned by coach with Master Evelyn. My father was taken to the Tower to see Sir John Robinson, the Lieutenant of the Tower.[/p]
		[p]Something strange had happened. The Lieutenant explained to my father that a man whom he had thought was the Moroccan Ambassador had delivered some animals for the Tower menagerie. Until other arrangements could be made, some lions and tigers had been housed in travelling cages outside the Lieutenant's house. In the night, someone had released them. The Tower garrison had trapped them in the street which contained the Mint until daylight, when they had either been recaptured or shot.[/p]
		[p]It looked as though a crime had been planned; but none had been committed. I remembered the boat which had followed us. Was it because of my father's escape that the crime had been stopped? Did they think that he knew too much? They were wrong! Not only did none of us know how the crime was to be committed, we didn't even know what the crime was to be! Those secrets still belonged to a man called Blood![/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="41">
    <text>
		[p]The boat had landed. The driver of the cart came over and secured it to the bank. The three men now began to unload something from the bottom of the boat into the cart. Whatever the objects, they were small and heavy, for the men carried them but one at a time. Then I caught the glint of the moon upon them. What was being loaded into the cart were bars of gold![/p]
		[p]I had to do something. The gates of the Tower would now be locked and it might take a long time to raise one of the Warders. I thought of Angel. It was now long past sunset and it was unlikely that he was still waiting by the stair. It would take little time to find out.[/p]
		[p]I eased myself along the bank until I thought it was safe to climb from the moat without being seen. I ran to the Tower Wharf. At first, I thought it was empty, but then I saw something dark on the ground by the Queen's Stair. It was Angel, soundly asleep. I woke him and told him what I had seen.[/p]
		[p]We hurried back towards the moat. As we passed the Tower entrance. Angel made signs to me to go to the gate and try to raise the alarm. Then, he left me, and hurried on into the darkness.[/p]
		[p]It took many minutes of banging upon the door of the Middle Tower before a light appeared and the door was opened. I told what was happening. The Warder left to fetch the garrison, telling me to wait by the gate. I soon became impatient and left to find out what had become of Angel.[/p]
		[p]The cart and the horses were still there, looking much as I had left them. The boat had gone and I could see no men, not even the driver of the cart. Nor could I see Angel.[/p]
		[p]A shout from the moat made me turn my gaze. What I took to be the second boat had begun to cross it. Like the first, it was being paddled across by two men, but a third was standing between them. It was he who was shouting, though I could not hear the words.[/p]
		[p]I sensed that something was wrong. As I watched it, the boat seemed to be getting lower in the water. It was sinking. Suddenly, it was gone, leaving three men thrashing about in the moat.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="43"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="42">
    <text>
		[p]I left the building and closed the door behind me. The side of the street where I stood was lit by moonlight. The other side was in shadow. I had begun to move away from the door when, from somewhere in the shadow, I heard a deep roar. It was answered by another farther up the street, and then by a snarling hiss from the opposite direction. Someone had opened the cages! The lions and tigers were roaming freely in the street![/p]
		[p]I tried to get back into the building. The door seemed to be barred or bolted. The roar came again; this time, it was nearer! I flattened myself against the wall and eased my way along it. I felt another doorway. I tried the door. It opened. I almost fell inside, dropping the latch behind me. Something very heavy struck the door upon the outside, but it held.[/p]
		[p]I was in another deserted building. Some light came through the upper windows anough to show that there was no way out except by the way I had come. The Tower garrison might block the end of the street but I could see no-one venturing into it in the dark. I knew that I was trapped until morning![/p]
		[p]I must, at last, have fallen asleep, for I was woken by shouting and by gun shots. It was morning. I unlatched the door and opened it a little. A dead lion lay outside and the street was filled with soldiers.[/p]
		[p]I was taken to Sir John Robinson, the Leiutenant of the Tower and there, I told my story. It was too late. During the night half a million pounds in gold bars had been taken from the Mint. There was no sign of how the Mint had been entered, no trace of the thieves and no clue to how the gold could have been removed from one of the most secure and best guarded buildings in England.[/p]
		[p]My father was rescued later that day. All that he knew was that he had been kidnapped because he had discovered that the body delivered to his house was that of the real Moroccan Ambassador. Who had posed as the Ambassador and brought the animals to the Tower, we could guess, but Colonel Thomas Blood had vanished from London together, it seemed, with Sir Hugo Donkey.[/p]
		[p]Only one clue was found. When the empty lion cages were moved, secret compartments were found beneath them large enough to have hidden several men.[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="43">
    <text>
		[p]One of the three began to swim for the bank. I could see that the other two could not swim, but the swimmer took no heed of their cries and came on for the bank. By the time he had reached it, there was nothing left behind him but ripples and silence.[/p]
		[p]I saw him pull himself from the water and run for the cart. Seeing no driver, he untethered the two horses and jumped upon the cart. I heard the crack of a whip and saw the cart heading off towards Tower Street.[/p]
		[p]I could hear the sound of men and horses behind me from the direction of the Tower. I was certain that they were too late. If the man driving the cart was Colonel Blood, then by now he was into the maze of narrow alleys already filled by other plague carts and all looking much alike.[/p]
		[p]A hand touched my shoulder. Angel was standing beside me and beckoning me to follow him. We made our way to Tower Street, turning off into a narrow lane which let to the churchyard of All Hallows where many plague carts were entering and leaving the churchyard. We stopped by one standing near to the gate. Angel pulled back the sacking which covered it. The bottom of the cart was filled with gold bars. On them, lay the senseless body of a man who must have been the driver.[/p]
		[p]I had come to understand Angel's language of signs. While the first boat had returned across the moat, Angel had dealt with the driver and exchanged the carts. He had then swum the moat and, with a knife, had made a small hole between the planks under the second boat as it was being loaded. He had then swumback and waited. Then what was in the cart which Blood had driven off? Angel twice held up ten fingers, put his arms stiffly to his sides and closed his eyes. All that Blood had stolen was the bodies of twenty plague victims![/p]
		[p]My father was rescued that day. He had been kidnapped only because he had seen the body of the real Moroccan Ambassador. Several men were arrested in the Tower, but Sir Hugo Donkey managed to flee the country.[/p]
		[p]With the coming of a cold December, the plague left London, never to return. Colonel Blood did return to London and the Tower, six years later, and almost succeeded in stealing the crown jewels, but that is another story.[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="44">
    <text>
		[p]We were surprised to find Sir John awake and dressed. He listened carefully to our story. He explained to my father that a man whom he believed to be the Moroccan Ambassador had delivered some animals to the Tower menagerie. Until other arrangements could be made, some lions and tigers had been housed in travelling cages outside the Lietunant's house. In the night, someone had released them. The Tower garrison had trapped them in Mint Street, but dared not enter the street itself until daylight. That was the reason Sir John was awake and dressed.[/p]
		[p]From what Sir John had now learned, it looked as if an attempt was going to be made to rob the Mint. The robbery could already have happened, but Sir John was determined that none of the robbers would succeed in leaving the Tower. Extra guards were posted outside, and around the moat as we waited for dawn.[/p]
		[p]At dawn, the soldiers moved into Mint Street. Two lions and a tiger were caught in nets. The rest were shot. The Mint appeared untouched, but a search for the robbers was begun.[/p]
		[p]It was as the search went on that Hermeticus, looking from the window of the Lieutenant's house, noticed that the animal cages had gone, though they had still been there when we arrived. It was at that moment that the Warder of the Middle Tower appeared, looking for the Lieutenant. He knew about the cages. They had been taken out through the gates a half hour before. There had been three men with them; one carrying a pass signed by the Lieutenant.[/p]
		[p]As I expected, the Lieutenant knew nothing about the cages or the pass! Nor was it the end of the story. Later that day, the cages were found abandoned, near Tower Street. Each one was discovered to contain a secret compartment beneath it – large enough to hold six men.[/p]
		[p]My father was safely returned and, perhaps, I had played some small part in preventing the robbery, but my feeling was of disappointment. How would the carts have been used? How could the robbers have worked in a street full of deadly wild animals? Those remained secrets perhaps known only to the man who called himself Colonel Blood.[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
</content>