<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content xmlns="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://gamebooks.zagor.hu http://zagor.hu/xsd/raw.xsd">
  <p id="back_cover">
    <next id="background" />
  </p>
  <p id="background" display="Background">
    <text>
        [p]Sherlock Holmes is away investigating a crime. YOu accidentally discover that someone in London is meanwhile weaving a complex plot against him. How good a detective are [strong]you[/strong]? As good as Holmes? You'll need your wits about you to unravel this dangerous plot before it's too late…[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="1"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="1">
    <text>
        [p]My father was a colonel in the Indian Army. When I was nine, I was sent to boarding school and my mother joined my father in India. For the rest of my schooldays, I saw little of either of my parents. I used to spend the school holidays with an aunt in Maidstone. She was a kind woman, but elderly, and very old fashioned. She approved of books, but not of the crime stories which were my favourite reading. She regarded these as unhealthy and not altogether respectable![/p]
        [p]When she thought that I was old enough, my aunt could sometimes be persuaded to allow me to spend a few days alone in London. My parents owned a flat in Northumberland Square which they used on their very occasional visits to this country. There I would stay, looking after myself and spending my time at the Old Bailey, listening to court cases from the public gallery.[/p]
        [p]Completely by chance I discovered one day that my aunt's maid, Eliza, was the niece of a lady called Mrs Hudson; the same Mrs Hudson who was the landlady of Mr Sherlock Holmes, the famous detective. Mrs Hudson owned a first floor flat at 221b Baker Street. Holmes rented rooms there, which he shared with his friend and colleague, Dr John Watson.[/p]
        [p]Baker Street was no distance from Northumberland Square. Using the excuse of bringing her news of her niece, I had called upon Mrs Hudson and made myself known to her. Indeed, it became my habit to call upon her each time that I visited London. We had, in fact, become quite good friends and I looked forward to the visits — even though I had not so far achieved my original purpose of meeting her lodger.[/p]
        [p]Always, when I had called, Holmes had been busy with a client or away investigating a case. This visit looked no different. Mrs Hudson was alone in the house. Dr Watson had gone to Devonshire to stay with a Sir Henry Baskerville at Baskerville Hall. Mr Holmes was also out of town. Mrs Hudson didn't know where, but she expected him to be gone for several days. I was sitting in Mrs Hudson's kitchen while she brewed some tea.[/p]
        [p]“As you are obviously going out to visit your sick friend,” I said, “I must not stay too long.”[/p]
    </text>
    <next id="2"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="2">
    <text>
		[p]Mrs Hudson must have been well used to Mr Holmes' remarkable powers of deduction but, coming from me, my remark obviously surprised her.[/p]
		[p]“How could you possibly know,” she asked, “that one of my friends is ill? Do you know Mrs Baxter?”[/p]
		[p]“No,” I answered, “but I would say she is a housekeeper, living nearby and alone in the house. She is recovering from her illness, but still not well enough to leave her bed.”[/p]
		[p]Mrs Hudson's jaw dropped. I had to laugh.[/p]
		[p]“It is really very simple,” I told her. “On the table in front of me is a key and a basket covered with a napkin. My nose tells me that the basket contains a hot, freshly baked meat pie; not the food for someone seriously ill. It has rained several times today. If you were taking the basket any distance you would have provided better protection against the weather. The key means that you must let yourself in and so your friend is bedridden and alone. The key is for a type of lock used for a rear or basement door. If your friend were the owner of the house, it would be a front door key.”[/p]
		[p]“Bless me!” she said, bringing the teapot to the table. “I didn't think it possible that there could ever be two people like Mr Holmes – and you so young! But you're right about Mrs Baxter. Very poorly she is; recovering from the pleurisy. It's the nursing she needs. I do what I can, but I can't be away from the house for too long.”[/p]
		[p]“Why not?” I asked.[/p]
		[p]“It's Mr Holmes, you see. If he's away, he likes to think that there's somebody here in case there's important messages. Of course, I do go out, but I'd never be away for the whole day.”[/p]
		[p]“Look,” I said. “I've nothing important to do. If you think you can trust me, I'll spend as much of each day here as I can and take any messages. You can look after Mrs Baxter and I can catch up on some reading that I want to do.”[/p]
		[p]I knew she wouldn't like the idea. I also knew it was the simple solution to her problem. And that was how I became the temporary, acting, unpaid caretaker of number 221b Baker Street, residence of Mr Sherlock Holmes.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="3"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="3">
    <text>
		[p]I was at Baker Street early the next morning and in time to meet the postman making his first delivery. Mrs Hudson was waiting to leave. She had started to do some cleaning in Holmes' rooms but had decided that the dusting must wait. She gave me the key to the house and to Holmes' rooms. She told me to leave his post on his desk, but not to interfere with his things. He wouldn't like it. Then she left. I had put Holmes' and Watson's post on the desk and had decided that “looking” would not be the same as “interfering”, when the front doorbell rang. It was not a tradesman. The persistent ringing suggested someone in a state of great agitation.[/p]
		[p]A young, well-dressed woman was standing on the doorstep. She did, indeed, appear both agitated and distressed. She didn't speak, but pushed past me into the hallway and began to mount the stairs. I called after her that if it was Mr Holmes she wanted to see, she was out of luck for he was not at home. Perhaps not hearing me, because she was upset and had her mind on other things, she continued to mount the stairs. I followed. She was into Holmes' living room before I could reach her. “Where is he?” she demanded. “Where is Mr Sherlock Holmes?”[/p]
		[p]I said I had been trying to tell her that he was not at home; that he might be away for several days. “I must see him,” she said. “It is a matter of life and death!” She paused. “I must leave a message. You must see mat he gets it the moment he returns.” I said that I would find her a pen and paper. “There will be no need,” she replied and produced from her bag an envelope which she laid on the desk. “My name is Sylvia Marquis. I am staying in London at the Northumberland Hotel.”[/p]
		[p]With that, she turned on her heel, left the room and hurried down the stairs. I watched her leave. There was something very strange about both the lady and her behaviour. I looked at the envelope she had placed on the desk. It was sealed with red wax, the seal bearing a large and ornate letter “M”.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="7">I asked myself whether Holmes would have followed her.</next>
    <next id="5">Or whether the envelope would have provided him with sufficient answers.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="4">
    <text>
		[p]I was certain that the envelope was to be the first in a chain of events. The most obvious thing to happen next would be a second caller in connection with that same letter. If I was right in my guess that someone wanted to take advantage of Holmes' absence, then my second caller must appear very soon.[/p]
		[p]At a little after nine, the front door bell rang. The caller was not the young woman who had brought the envelope, but a man in late middle age. A suit, cape and hat of heavy tweed suggested someone who normally lived in the country and whose occupation took him out in all weathers. He wore eye glasses and had a short, neatly trimmed beard; his beard and hair were dark with traces of grey. His voice was cultured.[/p]
		[p]“I must apologise,” he said, “for the lateness of the hour, but it is essential I see Mr Holmes.”[/p]
		[p]I explained that Holmes was out of town.[/p]
		[p]“Perhaps you can help. Do you know whether a young woman called here at some time today – perhaps giving her name as Sylvia Marquis?”[/p]
		[p]I said that she had, but had not seen Mr Holmes.[/p]
		[p]“Did she visit his rooms?” my visitor asked.[/p]
		[p]I said “Yes, but only to deliver an envelope.”[/p]
		[p]“If it was only a letter,” he replied, “then we have no worries.” He paused. “Forgive me. I am Dr Oliver Broadbent of Garforth in Surrey. Miss Marquis is one of my patients. You look too young to remember the case but, some years ago, Mr Holmes was the cause of sending her father to the gallows for murder. There was no doubt of his guilt but, recently, Miss Marquis has become disturbed in her mind. I believe her to be set upon revenge for her father's death and I'm sure her target is Mr Holmes. My great fear is that what she delivered was not a letter, but a bomb!”[/p]
		[p]I told him that I was sure he was wrong, but that if it would ease his mind, I would show him Mr Holmes' room where Miss Marquis had been – and the envelope.[/p]
		[p]He seemed satisfied about the envelope, but then suggested that we might inspect the room more carefully for any suspicious package or parcel. I was about to agree when he was taken with a sudden and, it seemed, uncontrollable spasm of coughing. “A chest infection,” he gasped. “Some water …” Did he just want me out of the room?[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="8">Should I go?</next>
    <next id="6">Or insist on his coming with me?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="5">
    <text>
		[p]It was the very existence of the envelope that had made me think the lady's behaviour strange. Here was a young woman, apparently very upset, who had arrived with, it seemed, no doubt in her mind that she was about to see Mr Holmes. Yet she had had the foresight to prepare whatever was in the envelope.[/p]
		[p]I picked up Holmes' hand lens from the desk and examined the envelope more carefully. The paper was expensive. Such envelopes would cost at least halfa crown a packet. There was nothing written on it; not even Mr Holmes' name – a curious oversight.[/p]
		[p]It had not been prepared as a last minute thought before leaving her hotel. It was not hotel stationery, which would have had the name of the hotel printed upon the envelope. The lady might carry her own writing case, but not the type of seal which had been used to impress the wax. It was not a ring seal, but something very much larger; only suitable for a desk and not an object one would carry in one's luggage.[/p]
		[p]There are more ways of reading the contents of an envelope than by opening it. I went over to the bench where Holmes kept his chemicals and soaked my handkerchief in some alcohol. I rubbed it over the envelope. The paper became instantly transparent, but only to reveal that the envelope had an inner lining of dark paper; a feature normally found only in continental stationery.[/p]
		[p]The lady had described her business, as “a matter of life and death”, yet she had not reacted as I would have expected to the news that Mr Holmes was away. Instead, she had left a carefully prepared envelope, the contents of which would not be read for some time. I was certain that the envelope was intended to serve some purpose other than that of leaving a message; if indeed it contained anything at all![/p]
		[p]At five that evening, Mrs Hudson returned to say that her friend, Mrs Baxter, had taken “a turn for the worse” and that she would have to spend the night with her. She left me a key to let myself in next morning. I used the key to let myself back into Baker Street at around eight o'clock that same night. I was expecting a visitor.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="4"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="6">
    <text>
		[p]“I'm sorry,” I told him, “but I'm sure that Mr Holmes would not want me to leave a stranger alone in his rooms. If you will come to the kitchen with me, I'll gladly give you some water.”[/p]
		[p]I expected him to protest, or perhaps to become indignant at the suggestion that he was not to be I trusted. He did neither.[/p]
		[p]“Of course,” he said and, between spasms of coughing, added, “You are quite right. I should not want any stranger to be left alone amongst my private papers. If you will lead the way, then I'll follow.”[/p]
		[p]I walked to the door with my visitor close behind me. From the corner of my eye, I saw that he had removed a handkerchief from his pocket; I assumed to place over his mouth, for he was still coughing, I had not expected it to be placed over my mouth![/p]
		[p]I had time to recognise the sickly smell of chloroform before my head was filled by a throbbing hum and everything went black.[/p]
		[p]When I came to my senses again, I felt slightly sick and there was a foul taste in my mouth. I saw that I was lying on the floor at the top of the stairs. The lights were still burning, but the house was j silent. I had little doubt that my visitor had done what he had come to do and was probably long gone.[/p]
		[p]I used the stair rail to help myself to my feet, then | stood there long enough for my head to clear and to be certain that I could walk without falling over.[/p]
		[p]I first looked into Holmes' room. It was empty i and, at least on first sight, everything looked much as I had last seen it. I had every intention of making a thorough examination, but not until after I had checked the rest of the house.[/p]
		[p]I did the complete rounds, but nothing seemed to be out of place. I very much doubted whether my visitor had been in any other part of the house. Whatever the real purpose for his visit, I felt sure that it lay in Holmes' living room. It is almost impossible to do anything without leaving behind some tiny clue. I could only hope that I might match the skill of Sherlock Holmes in finding it![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="10"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="7">
    <text>
		[p]The lady calling herself Sylvia Marquis had left the house only moments before. If she was returning on foot to the Northumberland Hotel, then she would still be in sight. She was not.[/p]
		[p]A muffin man with his bell in his hand had stopped on the other side of the street to rearrange the contents of his tray of muffins which he normally carried on his head. I ran across to him.[/p]
		[p]“Excuse me,” I said. “Did you, by any chance, see a young woman leave the house opposite a few moments ago?”[/p]
		[p]“Yes,” he answered. “Left in a cab.”[/p]
		[p]“You mean she hailed a cab?”[/p]
		[p]“No,” he said. “Reckon she had one waiting for her. There's been one standing down the street these ten minutes and she goes straight to it and gets in.”[/p]
		[p]If Sylvia Marquis had really expected to meet and spend some time with Mr Holmes, she would not have kept a cab waiting. I went to the Northumberland Hotel.[/p]
		[p]“Yes” there was a Miss Sylvia Marquis registered at the hotel, but her key was on the board. She was not in her room. I wanted to know more. My parents' flat was almost next to the hotel. Having passed the hotel frequently, I had come to know George, the doorman. I told him what I wanted to know. I offered him some money, but he wanted nothing tor himself – a couple of bob for the bell boy would do. He said I should give him ten minutes.[/p]
		[p]I went back to the flat, and returned to the hotel fifteen minutes later. Miss Marquis did have a room, paid for in advance. She had registered the day before but the chambermaid had said that the room hadn't been used and there was no luggage. The room was booked for ten days.[/p]
		[p]I had a lew things to do for myself. I really should have gone back to the flat, to check on whether I needed to buy any food and make certain that I had enough clean laundry. I hadn't forgotten the mysterious envelope which was still lying on Holmes' desk at Baker Street. I had to decide which was more important;[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="9">My own small personal needs.</next>
    <next id="5">Or that envelope.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="8">
    <text>
		[p]I decided that if there was some secret purpose in his visit, then I must give him his opportunity. Only in that way could I hope to find out what it might be. I said that I would fetch water from the kitchen.[/p]
		[p]I gave him plenty of time before returning with the water. His coughing appeared to have stopped, but he drank the water. He told me that he had already looked carefully about the room and could see nothing suspicious by way of a package or parcel. I asked him about the envelope. He felt sure that that was not his concern. He had only wished to be satisfied that one of his patients had not put Mr Holmes' life in danger. With that, he left, saying that he would write to Holmes warning him about Miss Marquis.[/p]
		[p]I looked on Holmes' bookshelves and saw that he had a Medical Directory. It listed two Dr Broadbents, but neither was called Oliver and neither practised in Garforth. That was no surprise. Whatever my visitor's real name, there were only three possible reasons for his visit: to look at something, to take something, or to leave something. I was most grateful that Mrs Hudson had cleaned out the fire but not dusted. Everything was covered by a thin layer of white ash. Anything that had been added, touched or moved would show tell-tale marks. I Spent three hours examining the room. There were no marks on the shelves of books or files, except weher I had removed the Medical Directory. There were some marks on the bottles of chemicals, but I had been there myself. I finished at the desk – and nearly missed what I was looking for![/p]
		[p]On the desk was a note pad. Several of its pages bore scribbled notes in Holmes' handwriting. There was no dust beneath it but, when I looked at it through the hand lens, I saw that there was no dust on top of it either![/p]
		[p]It was now half past midnight. I felt that I should go back to Northumberland Square. As I had examined the bookshelves, I had noticed what looked like an index of Holmes' cases. I took down the volume L–N. There was a Marquis Case; and there was a Sylvia Marquis! The murder had taken place in Garforth.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="11">I knew mat Mrs Hudson expected me to return in the morning.</next>
    <next id="13">But did this discovery make a trip to Garforth more important?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="9">
    <text>
		[p]I did most of my shopping in the Strand – a place jostling with people, hansom cabs and horse-drawn omnibuses. It was near midday. Feeling hungry, but anxious to return to Baker Street, I went into Lyons' Tea Rooms whose quick service had earned its waitresses the name of “Nippies”. After an unlikely meal of Welsh Rarebit and eclairs, I hailed a cab, dropped my shopping at Northumberland Square and went on to Baker Street.[/p]
		[p]Mrs Hudson had already returned, partly to leave me some food and partly to tell me that Mrs Baxter had taken “a turn for the worse”, and she might have to stay there overnight. I told her not to worry. I had a key to Baker Street. I would have to go out occasionally, but I would spend as much of my time there as I could from early morning to mid evening. Mrs Hudson seemed flustered and not just about her friend's illness, I thought. “Have you had any visitors?” I asked, casually.[/p]
		[p]“Yes,” she answered, “a Dr Oliver Broadbent; I think he said from Garforth in Surrey. Did a young woman call here after I left this morning?”[/p]
		[p]I said “Yes”, and that she had left a sealed envelope.[/p]
		[p]“Then perhaps,” said Mrs Hudson, “he was telling the truth. He said that this young woman was his patient and not right in her mind; that Mr Holmes had been the means of her father being tried and hung for murder and he thought that she might be wanting to have some sort of revenge. He thought that she might have left a bomb in Mr Holmes' rooms!”[/p]
		[p]“Did you let him see the rooms?” I asked.[/p]
		[p]“Well, yes. What else could I do?”[/p]
		[p]“And did you stay with him?” I queried.[/p]
		[p]“With me knowing there might be a bomb!” she exclaimed. “I did not. I waited outside.”[/p]
		[p]“And then?” I saked.[/p]
		[p]“He came out and said he'd found nothing. He said he would be writing to Mr Holmes – and then he left.”[/p]
		[p]I asked what he looked like.[/p]
		[p]“I've no memory for faces,” said Mrs Hudson. “He was tallish, late middle aged, black hair going grey – and a beard. Wore glasses.”[/p]
		[p]I could hardly wait for Mrs Hudson's departure! I had to know what had really happened in Holmes' rooms.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="10"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="10">
    <text>
		[p]I had half expected that the envelope left by Sylvia Marquis might have gone; but it had not. It was still on the desk with its seal unbroken. Whoever the man really was, there were only three possible reasons for his visit: to look at something, to take something, or to leave something.[/p]
		[p]I was grateful that Mrs Hudson had cleaned out the fire, but had not done any dusting. Everything was covered by a thin layer of fine white ash. Anything that had been added, touched or moved would bear the tell-tale marks. I started on the shelves of books and files and, almost at once, noticed that Holmes had a Medical Directory. I took it down and looked up the name Broadbent. There were two listed; neither called Oliver and neither practising at Garforth. That was no surprise! Apart from where I had removed the directory, there were no other marks on the shelves.[/p]
		[p]There were a few marks around Holmes' bottles of chemicals, but I remembered I had been there myself. I finished my examination at the desk – and very nearly missed what I had been looking for![/p]
		[p]On the desk was a note pad. Several of its pages bore scribbled notes in Holmes' handwriting. There was no dust beneath it but, when I examined it through Holmes' hand lens, I saw that there was no dust on top of it either![/p]
		[p]My examination of the room had taken longer than I thought and it was getting very late. I should be returning to Northumberland Square. I wanted to do one more thing. On Holmes' bookshelves, I had seen what looked like an index to his cases. I took down the volume L–N. There had been no Dr Broadbent in the Medical Directory. I wanted to be sure that there was no Marquis Case among Holmes' list of cases – but there was; and there was a Sylvia Marquis. The murder had been committed in Garforth![/p]
		[p]This case was becoming a very strange and curious mixture of obvious invention and possible fact. Holmes, of course, would have worked out some of the mystery by this time. I had not![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="11">I knew that Mrs Hudson was expecting me to return to Baker Street in the morning.</next>
    <next id="13">But did my discovery about the Marquis Case make a trip to Garforth more important?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="11">
    <text>
		[p]On my return to Baker Street, I spent some time examining the note pad on Holmes' desk. If it had just been picked up, there would have been marks on the dust which covered it – but the surface was quite clean. The pad had been taken away and then returned – taken by “Sylvia Marquis” and returned by “Dr Brodbent”? That would explain the purpose of the two visits; but what made the note pad so important?[/p]
		[p]I felt guilty about reading Holmes' private notes, but I had a strong feeling that something very sinister was afoot. Someone's life might hang upon my finding the right answers to the mystery.[/p]
		[p]The contents of the note pad told me nothing. It was only a collection of addresses, appointments and reminders. Some pages had been torn out. It could be that I was not going to find anything, because it had already been removed![/p]
		[p]Mrs Hudson returned to the flat at four o'clock. She wasn't going out again until next morning becuase Mrs Baxter was improving again. I could leave as soon as I liked. I showed her where I had left the post and told her that there had been no more visitors.[/p]
		[p]“My!” she exclaimed. “Mr Holmes is honoured!” She was looking at the desk and at the sealed envelope which I had left separate from the rest. “That letter,” she went on, “is from Mr Holmes' brother, Mycroft. Mr Holmes has always said that Mycroft is too lazy to write to anyone.”[/p]
		[p]“Are you certain it's from Mycroft?” I asked.[/p]
		[p]“Certain sure,” she answered. “It's the seal. I've seen it once before; and Mr Holmes, he has one just like it, except his has got an 'S'.”[/p]
		[p]I said that I must go; but not before I had found a chance, secretly, to slip Holmes' note pad into my coat. I left the house, thinking that it might be the time to seek out Mycroft Holmes.[/p]
		[p]Two urchins were playing on the pavement with a hoop from a barrel. It rolled up to my feet and one of them ran up to me to retrieve it.[/p]
		[p]“Follow us,” he whispered, and added, “– and not so as everybody can see as you're doin' it.”[/p]
		[p]With that, they moved off slowly. I had heard of poeple being lured into dark alleys and robbed.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="15">I didn't know whether to follow them.</next>
    <next id="12">Or walk away.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="12">
    <text>
		[p]I turned my mind to Mycroft Holmes. I was sure that the envelope delivered by Miss Marquis had not come from him, but why had it been made to appear so? Having read all of Dr Watson's accounts of Holmes' cases in the Strand Magazine, I knew something of Mycroft's habits. For instance, I knew that he returned from his office in Whitehall to his lodgings in Pall Mall at the same time each evening. I also knew what he looked like from an illustration published in the [em]Illustrated London News[/em]. A short wait on the corner of Pall Mall, and my patience was rewarded. A large, rather stout and unimportant-looking man was approaching. “Excuse my impertinence,” I began, “but are you Mr Mycroft Holmes, brother of Mr Sherlock Holmes?”[/p]
		[p]“I am,” he replied, rather curtly.[/p]
		[p]“The story is too long to tell on the street,” I told him, “but I have reason to think that your brother is in some danger and he cannot be reached at present.”[/p]
		[p]“My brother,” Mycroft replied, “sees fit to invite danger and, for reasons that I dont't understand, would appear to thrive upon it.”[/p]
		[p]He had started to walk on. I played my trump card.[/p]
		[p]“I don't know what the danger is, but I am fairly certain that you are also involved in it. A letter has been delivered to Baker Street which would appear to have come from you. I don't believe that you have sent any such letter.”[/p]
		[p]Mycroft stopped walking.[/p]
		[p]“Very well,” he said, grudgingly. “You had better tell your story. My club is nearer than my lodging. You can tell it to me here.”[/p]
		[p]We sat alone in the library of the Diogenes Club while I told all that I knew. Mycroft listened in silence. When I had finished, he remained silent for some minutes.[/p]
		[p]“Yes!” he said, suddenly. “That's it! It is clearly the only logical solution.” He looked at me. “You have my brother's note pad with you?”[/p]
		[p]I said that I had and handed it to him. He took it without a word.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="20"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="13">
    <text>
		[p]Before leaving Baker Street, I consulted Holmes' copy of Bradshaw's Railway Guide. The mainline service from Victoria Station would take me to Pendle Junction and there I could change trains for Garforth Halt. It should be possible to make such enquiries as I needed and return to London in little more than three hours.[/p]
		[p]The next morning, I was at Baker Street in time to receive the first post and to leave a note for Mrs Hudson, should she return, saying that I hoped to be back by early afternoon. I then took a cab to Victoria arriving with ten minutes to buy my ticket and board the train.[/p]
		[p]Garforth was a fairly small but sprawling village. The station porter directed me to the doctor's house – a walk of only a quarter of a mile. I was lucky to find that the doctor had just finished morning surgery and had not yet set out on his rounds. I had invented a story about Miss Marquis having tried to contact Mr Holmes and my having failed to note her address. I had remembered only that she lived in Garforth and had hoped to correct my stupid oversight before Mr Holmes' return.[/p]
		[p]As I expected, the doctor was nothing like the man who had called at Baker Street calling himself Broadbent. This man was short and plump. He had a broad Scots accent and a name to go with it – John Campbell. Then came my first surprise.[/p]
		[p]“Yes,” he said, “I do know Miss Marquis, though she is my partner's patient; that's Oliver Broadbent, a young man who has recently joined me. He's on holiday at this moment – in my part of the world, in Scotland. But that is of no matter. I can tell you where Sylvia Marquis lives – at Apple Tree Farm with her aunt and uncle. You can see the chimneys of the house. I'll show you when we get to the front gate.”[/p]
		[p]I found Apple Tree Farm, but I could get no answer at the door of the farmhouse. I walked across the yard towards the barns and outbuildings. I tried some of the doors. Most were locked, but I found one which was not. I had pushed it open to see if anyone was inside, when I was given a sudden push from behind which sent me sprawling onto the floor.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="14"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="14">
    <text>
		[p]I was still on the floor when I heard the door being closed behind me and the sound of a bolt being shot home. I got to my feet. The only light in the place came from around the ill-fitting door and a small window caked with years of grime. I tried the door, but as I feared it was fastened on the outside.[/p]
		[p]I turned to inspect the rest of my prison in tune to see something large and white coming at me through the half darkness. I sprang to one side but, whatever it was, caught me on one hip, flinging me against the wall. There was an angry squeal. My companion was a full grown boar, big enough and strong enough to kill a man![/p]
		[p]I put out my hand to steady myself. My fingers touched something loose resting against the wall. It was a piece of old timber. The boar had turned and was coming again. I grasped the timber and aimed for its snout. The squeal told me that the blow had gone home, but it hadn't stopped the boar. Now more angry than before, it was charging again. With no time to wield the timber again, I flung myself out of its path. I felt my feet slide and, as I crashed to the floor, I thought that this was the end. In the next seconds, the boar would be onto me, trampling and tearing with hoofs and teeth.[/p]
		[p]I must have knocked myself unconscious. When I opened my eyes I was still on the floor. I could neither see nor hear the boar and the place looked suddenly lighter. I sat up. The light was coming from a large hole in the wall. It told its own story. The timber walls were half rotten with age. As I had sprung aside, the half ton of charging pig had gone clean through it![/p]
		[p]Making certain that the boar was not waiting for me outside, I crawled through the hole. For the moment, I had lost interest in meeting any of the other occupants of Apple Tree Farm. I made straight for the road and headed back towards the statioq.[/p]
		[p]What had just happened had been no accident. I couldn't have been expected at the farm. Had someone followed me from London – and would they follow me back?[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="16">Should I make a point of making myself very visible on the station platform?</next>
    <next id="18">Or stay out of sight, boarding the train at the last possible second?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="15">
    <text>
		[p]The two urchins were still playing with the hoop, but moving down the street at a speed which made it easy to follow at a natural walking pace. We had turned several corners when, suddenly, they disappeared through an archway. I stopped at the archway; above it was the sign, “Carters Yard”. There was no sign of the urchins, but, as I had come this far, I turned in under the arch.[/p]
		[p]As the name had suggested, I found myself in a yard. There were several carts, some stables, piles of sacks and hay, and a good deai of rubbish. “You a friend of Mr Sherlock 'Olmes?”[/p]
		[p]I turned to see the two boys standing right next to me. I said, “Yes”. It was easier than explaining the whole truth.[/p]
		[p]“I'm Fred,” said the boy. “This 'ere's Charlie.” Fred was dressed in a tattered shirt and waistcoat, trousers that had been cut down from something much larger, a pair of down at heel boots, and a cap. Charlie was not so well off, lacking waistcoat, boots and cap. “Somefin”, said Fred, “is hup – ain't it?”[/p]
		[p]Before I could think of a reply, I realised that the yard was full of children; of various ages, but all of them looking rather like Fred and Charlie.[/p]
		[p]“Us,” Fred went on, indicating the assembled company, “– we is the Baker Street Irregulars.”[/p]
		[p]I recognised the title. I remembered reading Dr Watson's account of two of Holmes' famous cases, “A Study in Scarlet” and “The Crooked Man”. Holmes had used some local street urchins to gather information in places where anyone else would be noticed, but where no-one spares a glance for a ragged child. I realised that I might have suddenly acquired my own private detective force! “Yes,” I said. “I'm sure mat something is up, but what makes you think so?”[/p]
		[p]“Comin's,” said Fred.[/p]
		[p]“And goin's,” added Charlie.[/p]
		[p]“That,” Fred went on, “the 'ouse bein' watched – and you bein' foller'd.”[/p]
		[p]“You seem to know a good deal more than I do,” I told them. Fred drew himself up to his full three foot six.[/p]
		[p]“We would,” he replied, “– 'cause you ain't got the experience what we 'ave.”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="19"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="16">
    <text>
		[p]There was no one on the station platform when I arrived. Just as the train was pulling in, a man did appear. He was tall, thin, elderly and white haired. He looked innocent enough and got into a compartment some distance from my own.[/p]
		[p]My encounter with the boar had done no good to my clothes. I managed to remove most of the straw and mud. I smelled of farmyard and opened the carriage window in the hopes that the smell would blow away before I reached London.[/p]
		[p]I had to think of my next move. Though I felt rather guilty about doing it, I had “borrowed” Holmes' note pad from hisk desk. The only way that I could account for the absence of dust on it was that it had been taken by “Sylvia Marquis” and returned by “Dr Broadbent”. I had to know why. I had the note pad with me, but now did not seem the time to examine it carefully. Of one thing, I was sure. Someone very clever was behind whatever was going on; someone who had gone to the trouble of making their story stand up, at least to casual enquiry. There was a Marquis Case. There was a Sylvia Marquis and even a Dr Broadbent who “happened” to be away from home. If it had not been that the real Dr Broadbent was too newly qualified to be in the Medical Directory, I might not even have visited Garforth.[/p]
		[p]When I got off the train at Victoria, the white haired man left the station after me. If he was following me, I would make it too easy for him if I took a cab. I started to walk. Twice, I spotted him, still behind me. Though it was out of my way, I cut off by the Buckingham Palace gardens. The next time I looked, I still hadn't lost him. I turned a corner into Pall Mall and slipped into the first doorway. It was too open to give me much cover. I boldly walked in through the doors in front of me.[/p]
		[p]I was in the hallway of what looked like a club. The porter had spotted me and asked my business. A sign over the porter's desk said, “Diogenes Club”. My luck was in. I knew that Mycroft Holmes, Sherlock's older brother, was a founder member of this club.[/p]
		[p]Praying that he was out, I said that I wanted to leave a message for Mr Mycroft Holmes.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="17"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="17">
    <text>
		[p]Mycroft was out. I asked for paper and an envelope. They were handed to me by the porter. The envelope was identical to the one lying on Holmes' desk with the seal. Could it be “M” for Mycroft? I commented on the excellent quality of the paper.[/p]
		[p]“Made exclusively for this club,” the porter replied.[/p]
		[p]I wrote some meaningless words on the paper, sealed it up and gave it back to the porter. Not only could I be certain that I'd lost my pursuer, but I'd learned something about the envelope. It was meant to appear to have come from Mycroft Holmes![/p]
		[p]I was wrong about one thing! As I was returning to Baker Street through the back alleys, I saw the white headed man again — not too far behind me. I was giving up all hope of losing him when, as I passed an archway, a hand grabbed me on either side and" pulled me in.[/p]
		[p]My “assailants” were two small boys. One placed his finger to his lips and beckoned me on. I was in a yard. There were several carts, some stables and piles of sacks and hay. There were also several other children.[/p]
		[p]“I'm Fred,” said one of the two boys, “and this 'ere is Charlie.”[/p]
		[p]Both were poorly dressed. Fred had a cap and boots. Charlie had neither.[/p]
		[p]“Us,” Fred went on, indicating the assembled company, “– we is the Baker Street Irregulars.”[/p]
		[p]I recognised the title. These were the local street urchins whom Holmes had used to gather information in some of his most famous cases.[/p]
		[p]“You is a friend of Mr Sherlock 'Olmes?” Fred asked.[/p]
		[p]Though not quite true, I said “Yes”.[/p]
		[p]“And somefin' is hup – ain't it?”[/p]
		[p]I asked what made them think so.[/p]
		[p]“Comin's”, said Fred.[/p]
		[p]“And goin's,” added Charlie.[/p]
		[p]“That,” Fred went on, “the' ouse bein' watched – and you bein' foller'd.”[/p]
		[p]“You seem to know a good deal more then I do,” I told them. Fred drew himself up to his full three foot, six inches.[/p]
		[p]“We would,” he replied, “– 'cause you ain't got the experience what we 'ave.”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="19"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="18">
    <text>
		[p]Before I reached the station, I left the road and crossed some fields. I stopped several times to make certain that no-one was following. The railway line ran through a cutting before it reached the station. The cutting was quite deep, but the sides were grassy and not too steep, so that it was easy to make my way towards the station well away from the gaze of any watching eyes.[/p]
		[p]I now had the station in sight, and the bushes at the top edge of the cutting provided a perfect hiding place.[/p]
		[p]From there, I could see anyone who arrived at the station entrance. I could see the train arrive and judge when it was about to leave, so I could leave my hiding place at the last possible moment to board it.[/p]
		[p]The scheme worked perfectly and I did appear to be the only person who had boarded the train. It was not until I was settled in my compartment that I realised my encounter with the boar had done no good to my appearance. There was straw in my hair and mud on my clothes. As the mud dried, I was able to rub most of it off. I still smelled strongly of farmyard. I opened the carriage window and hoped that the smell would have blown away before I reached London.[/p]
		[p]I began to think about my next move. Of one thing, I was certain. Someone very clever was behind whatever was going on; someone who had gone to the trouble of making their story stand up, at least, to casual enquiry.[/p]
		[p]There was a Marquis Case and there was a Sylvia Marquis. I had no doubt that, had I stayed longer at Apple Tree Farm, I should have discovered that Sylvia Marquis was away from home – like the real Dr Broadbent. Whoever had planned it had made only one slip. The real Dr Broadbent was too newly qualified to be in the Medical Directory. Had his name appeared there, I might not have visited Garforth.[/p]
		[p]When I reached Victoria, I took a cab to Northumberland Square, changed my clothes and wasted no time in setting off once more for Baker Street.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="11"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="19">
    <text>
		[p]I asked them to tell me more – about who had been following me.[/p]
		[p]“A man,” said Fred, “– tall, thin, sort of high fore'ead and sunken eyes.”[/p]
		[p]“A fattish man,” said Charlie, “with black hair and a beard.”[/p]
		[p]“You mean there is more than one,” I said.[/p]
		[p]Fred shook his head.[/p]
		[p]“No,” he replied. “Same man; different disguises. Good, 'e is – not as good ad Mr 'Olmes.”[/p]
		[p]“If he's that good,” I questioned, “then how can you be sure that it's the same man?”[/p]
		[p]“Hands!” replied Fred, proudly. “That's what Mr 'Olmes learned us. Look at their 'ands, says 'e. 'Ands is 'ard to change.”[/p]
		[p]By now, it would no longer have surprised me if they could also tell me who this man was.[/p]
		[p]“Not 'oo,” Charlie volunteered, “but where. We done a bit 'o follerin' too. 'As an' ouse in Regent Crescent by the park with all them hanimals. Don't reckon on 'is usin' it for long though.”[/p]
		[p]Fred decided that that needed some explanation. “Most of the rooms is empty – no curtains. Them as isn't ain't got much in the way of furniture.”[/p]
		[p]Sherlock Holmes would have been very proud of his “Baker Street Irregulars”. I told them a little more about what had been going on; enough for them to agree that Mr Holmes' life might even be in some danger. It was obvious that they not only admired Sherlock Holmes but looked upon him as a good friend. I had only to tell them how they might help and it would be done. I explained that I didn't think that I would be able to pay as much money as they might have expected from Holmes. “We don't want no pay,” Fred told me. He looked at the others. There was a general nod of agreement. Then he added, “Only necessary hexpenses.” I gave them my address in Northumberland Square and suggested that, for the moment, the most useful thing they could do was to keep an eye on Baker Street and the house in Regent Crescent near the Regent's Park Zoo. I had two choices;[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="21">To await developments.</next>
    <next id="12">Or to seek out Mycroft Holmes.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="20">
    <text>
		[p]He flipped through the pad quite quickly not, it seemed, spending much time in reading what was written on its pages. Several times, he tilted it towards the light and then put it down.[/p]
		[p]“Clever,” he said, “very clever.” He turned to me. “And you say that Sherlock is out of town and has told no-one where he is?”[/p]
		[p]I nodded.[/p]
		[p]“Then there is only one thing missing – the corpse!”[/p]
		[p]I stared at him – probably rather stupidly.[/p]
		[p]“The murder,” he added, “if murder it is, will not yet have taken place. It is too soon.”[/p]
		[p]“I'm sorry,” I said, “but you will have to explain it to me in more simple terms.”[/p]
		[p]“I can't,” he replied, “– for two very good reasons. I might be able to put it into terms simple enough for Sherlock to follow – my brother is a man of quite high intelligence. I could not hope to do so for you. But there is another reason. This is a matter which involves state secrets.”[/p]
		[p]I felt a little hurt at Mycroft's low opinion of my intelligence. My only consolation was that he didn't seem to have a much higher opinion of his brother.[/p]
		[p]“So what should I do?” I asked.[/p]
		[p]“Nothing,” was the reply. “I will do all that is necessary. For a youngster, you have done quite well, but you are in more danger than anyone. Return at once to your aunt in Maidstone and do not return to Baker Street. I will do any explaining necessary to Mrs Hudson.”[/p]
		[p]I was left with no choices. I returned to Maidstone that night.[/p]
		[p]I did watch the newspapers carefully. In the next few days, there were four murders and three mysterious deaths in London, but nothing to connect any of them with Sherlock Holmes. The unfinished article by Dr Watson which I saw many years later gave me no more real clues to the mystery.[/p]
		[p]I did see Mrs Hudson again, though less often as the years went by. I never met the great Sherlock Holmes. As for the “Unsolved Case”, that is how it still remains.[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="21">
    <text>
		[p]Mrs Hudson had returned to Baker Street and would be there until the next morning. I could spend some time, undisturbed, at the flat in Northumberland Square. The flat was almost next to the Northumberland Hotel, so I took the opportunity to have a word with my friend George, the hotel doorman. Sylvia Marquis was still registered at the hotel, but she was not occupying the room which she had paid for. He knew because of the gossip this had caused amongst the hotel staff.[/p]
		[p]Back in the flat, I made myself a light meal and settled down to look again at Holmes' note pad. If there was some clue, I couldn't see it among any of the various notes which were written there.[/p]
		[p]Then I noticed that the paper was quite thin and that because Holmes wrote in firm hand and with a hard pencil, the impression of the writing on each sheet had been transferred to the next. Although some sheets had been torn out, there might still be evidence of what had been written on them.[/p]
		[p]Again, I found nothing. It was only as I was staring, hopelessly, at the open pad that I saw that the impression of one word on the back of a sheet stood out much more clearly than the rest. I went through the backs of every sheet. In several places, one word, or even part of a word, stood out from the rest. I copied each of these onto a sheet of paper. What I got was “more is money own. He for moved must re making Br be demands”.[/p]
		[p]I could see at once that if someone had torn a clean sheet from the pad, inserted it in turn below the other sheets and, with a hard point, had traced over the letters and words in the right order, they could have left the impression of a message on that sheet. More than that, it would appear to be a copy of something written in Holmes' own hand. Because it was only an impression, it would be harder for a handwriting expert to tell that is was a forgery![/p]
		[p]I had the words, but how had they been put together? What did they say? The “re” would only fit onto “moved” or “making”. “Br” was not initials, but would fit onto “own”. “He” looked like the beginning of a sentence. I worked on it for some time without success. I thought that I might do better after a night's sleep.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="22"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="22">
    <text>
		[p]The next morning, I had just prepared myself a breakfast of boiled eggs and toast when there was a knock at the door of the flat. It was Fred.[/p]
		[p]“I come to report,” he announced.[/p]
		[p]I asked him in and offered him some breakfast. He ate everything in sight at a speed which would have made it impossible for him to talk while he was doing it. I waited until he was finished – which was not very long![/p]
		[p]“Well?” I asked.[/p]
		[p]Fred wiped his mouth on a ragged sleeve.[/p]
		[p]“Charlie and Jim,” he said. They's been at Regent Crescent all of the night. “Bout six o'clock this mornin' there's a van arrives and, after that, a cart.”[/p]
		[p]“And do you know what was in them?” I asked.[/p]
		[p]“The van,” Fred said, “was full of ice; big blocks of ice, and lots of 'em. They was taken into the 'ouse.”[/p]
		[p]“And the cart?”[/p]
		[p]“I ain't so sure,” Fred answered. “Sacks, they was, with white stuff in them – 'cause some of it 'ad slipped out onto the road. Charlie got a quick taste of it. Says it was salt.”[/p]
		[p]If it was salt and ice, then something at Regent Crescent was being kept frozen and, with that sort of quantity, something quite big![/p]
		[p]I asked Fred what he thought the chances were of getting into the house. He shook his head.[/p]
		[p]“Not much,” he said. “Too many people about and too open. Might do it at night, but I'd still say it's risky.”[/p]
		[p]I should see the house for myself. I should also keep my promise to Mrs Hudson to return to Baker Street. If I did look at the house first, I could then spend the day at Baker Street working out a method of getting in and I could spend more time on the cryptic message from the note pad. I had one other idea. Why did Sylvia Marquis still have a room at the Northumberland Hotel which she obviously wasn't using? Since she was supposed to be there, I wondered what would happen if I left a letter there for her. Would someone appear to collect it?[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="24">Should I go to the house first?</next>
    <next id="26">Or should I leave a letter at Northumberland Hotel?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="23">
    <text>
		[p]The passenger in a hansom cab sits in the covered section at the front, nearest to the horse. The driver sits outside, perched high up on the back, the reins passing over the roof of the cab itself. Above the passenger is a small trapdoor, set in the roof, through which the driver and passenger can communicate.[/p]
		[p]The trap was shut. I knocked on it to attract the driver's attention. There was no response – but I heard the whip being cracked to urge the horse on to an even greater pace.[/p]
		[p]We were travelling down the Marylebone Road. Not too far ahead of us, at the roadside, was a row of stalls and barrows of a group of street traders. I had passed mem on foot more than once and knew that they sold everything from cockles to cabbages. I also knew that when the traffic on the road was heavy, which it was today, the stalls caused a bit of a bottle neck. With any luck, the cab would have to slow down as it passed them.[/p]
		[p]I banked on cabbages giving me the softest landing and timed my jump to perfection; not that the barrow owner appreciated that![/p]
		[p]I picked myself up in time to see the cab vanishing down the road. Several bystanders had gathered around me and I had to assure them that the “bloodstains” on my clothes were not blood, but beetroot. Having established that I was not hurt, the owner of the barrow became less than polite. He had begun to tot up a dozen cabbages at a penny each, a box of lettuces at twopence a head, a score of penny beetroot … I offered him a sovereign, and he grudgingly accepted it.[/p]
		[p]I had lost Sylvia Marquis, but had confirmed one thing. I was still being watched – but not at this moment. No-one could have anticipated what had just happened.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="25">This could be the ideal time to take a look at the house in Regent Crescent though the squashed beetroot had done nothing to improve my appearance – especially for a visit to one of the more fashionable parts of London.</next>
    <next id="24">My alternative was to go back to Northumberland Square and clean myself up first.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="24">
    <text>
		[p]Fred had left me a rough plan of Regent Crescent showing the position of the house and the place from which they were watching it.[/p]
		[p]There were usually a few empty cabs standing about in Northumberland Square but, when I left the flat, I walked out of the Square and went on until I saw a solitary cab at the roadside and no others in sight. I jumped into the cab, told the driver my destination and asked him to get me there as quickly as possible. That way, if anyone was following me, I had made the chase difficult for them — I hoped, impossible. The cab put me down near the entrance to Regent Crescent and, following Fred's plan, I began to walk.[/p]
		[p]They had chosen a good place to watch from; it was an overgrown shrubbery in the grounds of an empty house almost opposite to that occupied by the “enemy”. It was there that I found two boys who had relieved Charlie and Jim. They introduced themselves as Albert and Edward.[/p]
		[p]They told me that there had been no movement in the house opposite for at least two hours. I asked if there was any way that I might get nearer to the house. They said that Fred and Charlie had done it. The danger spot was getting past the gateway. If I could slip past it, unseen, there were enough trees and bushes down one side of the dreve to give me cover all the way to the back of the house.[/p]
		[p]I said that I would go as far as the gateway. They could see the front of the house. If all looked clear, they were to give me a signal.[/p]
		[p]I got the signal, slipped through the gateway and into the bushes. I made my way to a point where I could get a good view of the back of the house, still without being seen. As I had expected, there were stables and a carriage house. The door of the carriage house was part open. Something inside was catching the light – something red, shiney and metallic. I risked moving closer. I was looking at the very latest French Gardner-Serpollet steam carriage![/p]
		[p]I wanted to see more.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="30">Should I chance going into the carriage house?</next>
    <next id="27">Or be satisfied with what I had seen until I had planned my next visit?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="25">
    <text>
		[p]The cab which I had so recently left could, by now, be half a mile away. But I couldn't be sure that it wouldn't return, or that I would recognise it if it did. One London cab looks very like another, and there were plenty of them about on the busy street.[/p]
		[p]If I was going to Regent Crescent, then I had to go by way of the quieter streets. That way, I was also less likely to meet people who would stare at my beetroot-stained clothing or, worse, offer me help thinking that I had been in an accident. The truth might be difficult to explain![/p]
		[p]Fred had drawn me a rough plan of the Crescent and I knew where to find both the house and the point from which it was being watched. Taking great care to see that I was not being followed, I reached the observation post.[/p]
		[p]They had chosen a good place to watch from; it was an overgrown shrubbery in the grounds of an empty house almost opposite to that occupied by the “enemy”. It was there that I found the two boys who had relieved Charlie and Jim. Having introduced themselves as Albert and Edward, they told me that there had been no movement in the house opposite for two hours. Knowing that Fred and Charlie had done it, I asked how I might get nearer. They said that the danger spot was the gateway. If I could slip past it, unseen, there were enough trees and bushes down one side of the drive to give me cover all the way to the back of the house.[/p]
		[p]I said that I would go as far as the gateway. If all looked clear, then they were to give me a signal. I got the signal, slipped through the gateway and into the bushes. I made my way to a point where I could get a good view of the back of the house, still without being seen.[/p]
		[p]As I had expected, there were stables and a carriage house. The door of the carriage house was part open and something inside was catching the light. Whatever it was, was red, shiney and metallic. I risked moving closer. What I was looking at was the very latest in horseless carriages – a French Gardner-Serpollet steam carriage! I had to see what other surprises the carriage house might hold![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="30"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="26">
    <text>
		[p]I asked Fred to wait and, seeing what he had done to my breakfast, suggested that he might help himself to anything he liked to take to Charlie and Jim who had done the night watch at Regent Crescent.[/p]
		[p]Meanwhile, I wrote what looked like an innocent note to Miss Marquis, saying only that Mr Sherlock Holmes had still not returned to Baker street, but that he would receive the envelope she had left immediately upon his return. I sealed it in an envelope and asked Fred to deliver it to George with a message from me. With Fred's appearance, I knew he would not be allowed inside the hotel. Fred left with the letter and practically all the rest of the food in the house.[/p]
		[p]I followed fifteen minutes later. Having found Miss Marquis's room number from George, I was pleased to see, as I entered the hotel reception area, that my letter – for which I had used a bright blue envelope – was in the pigeon hole for Miss Marquis's room number. I sat down in the hotel lounge where I could see the reception desk, ordered some hot milk and biscuits, and waited.[/p]
		[p]It was an hour later that Sylvia Marquis herself appeared at the desk and collected her letter. She didn't open it, but left the hotel again. I reached the doors in time to see her getting into a hansom cab. Another cab was standing, empty, behind it. I ran across the road, jumped into the second cab and told the driver to follow the one which had just moved off.[/p]
		[p]I was beginning to congratulate myself on having thought of a clever scheme, when two things began to worry me. “Follow that cab!” was the sort of remark that should have brought some bit of cockney wit from the driver. He had said nothing. We were travelling at a fair trot and, though I looked out from the cab, I could see nothing of the one which we were supposed to be following. Had my scheme gone wrong and was I the one who had fallen into a trap?[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="23">I could jump from the moving cab. At this speed, I risked being hurt, or even killed!</next>
    <next id="28">I was safer to stay where I was. Yet if my fears were right, the danger would come later; when we reached the end of the journey!</next>
  </p>
  <p id="27">
    <text>
		[p]Having seen all that I needed to at the house at Regent Crescent, I told Albert and Edward where I could be found for the rest of the day – either at Baker Street or Northumberland Square, and left them a message for Fred.[/p]
		[p]Back at Baker Street, my first priority was to work out a careful plan for my next visit to Regent Crescent. This time, I intended to get inside the house! Having done that, I also wanted to spend more time working out the cryptic message which appeared to have been forged with the aid of Holmes' note pad. I had hardly started upon that task, when I heard a key being turned in the front door. Mrs Hudson had returned earlier than I had expected her.[/p]
		[p]Though Mrs Hudson pretended to know nothing of Mr Holmes business, or to understand anything of his methods, I suspected that she was a woman of sharper wits than she would have people believe. Holmes' room had still not been dusted. When it was, I did not want to have left any evidence that I had broken my promise “not to interfere” with any of Holmes' things. I had returned the note pad to the desk. I took a quick look about me to see if there was anything that I had missed. I suddenly spotted the Medical Directory which I had taken from the shelves. I had left it lying on the table. I picked it up and started towards the shelves, only to hear Mrs Hudson's footfall on the stairs. I slipped out of Holmes' room and back to Mrs Hudson's kitchen. I hid the Medical Directory in my coat, intending to return it when I got the opportunity.[/p]
		[p]Mrs Hudson was home for the day. It seemed that Mrs Baxter was really getting better, and I could see that, shortly, I would have no excuse to spend time at Baker Street. Perhaps it didn't matter much. It looked as though the action was moving elsewhere![/p]
		[p]I arrived at Regent Crescent at few minutes before midnight and joined Fred and Charlie who were now manning the observation post. There was someone, in the house opposite, but all the lights had gone out at about eleven. The occupants should be asleep.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="29"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="28">
    <text>
		[p]The passenger in a hansom cab sits in the covered section at the front, nearest to the horse. The driver sits outside, perched high up on the back, the reins passing over the roof of the cab itself. Above the passenger is a small trapdoor, set in the roof, through which the driver and passenger communicate.[/p]
		[p]The trap was shut. I knocked on it to attract the driver's attention. There was no response – but I heard the whip being cracked to urge the horse on to an even greater pace.[/p]
		[p]My fears had not been wrong and, already. I was regretting my decision not to seek the first opportunity to jump from the cab. I had just lost one chance at Marylebone Road where the cab had had to slow down as it passed a line of stalls and barrows of street traders. Now, we had turned into a quieter street which skirted Regent's Park. It confirmed my suspicion that we were heading for the house in Regent Crescent. It also told me that there would be little chance of the driver slackening his speed again before we reached it![/p]
		[p]There might be one small hope! The cab would have to slow down as it turned into Regent Crescent and, again, as it turned into the drive of the house. I already knew from Fred's description that there must be some stabling and a carriage house at the back of the house. I guessed that the cab would not stop in the road, or at the front of the house. They would not want a struggling passenger being removed from it to be seen in public view![/p]
		[p]My hopes were soon dashed. As we approached the Crescent, the trapdoor above my head was lifted. I looked up to see the barrel of a Webley revolver pointed at my head. The driver had still not spoken. There was no need![/p]
		[p]The cab eventually drew to a halt inside the carriage house. I followed a curt instruction to “Get out”, and found myself standing beside something which I should have been delighted to see so close up – in rather different circumstances. It was a horseless carriage; a beautiful, red, shining metallic monster which I recognised as the very latest French Gardner-Serpollet steam carriage.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="30"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="29">
    <text>
		[p]I had brought three “bull's eye” lanterns with me, one for each of us. I planned to enter the house through one of the windows at the back. Fred would come with me. He would stay by the shrubbery where he could see the window through which I planned both to enter and leave. He could see most of the back of the house and he would also see across the road to where Charlie remained hidden. If anything happened at the front of the house, Charlie was to signal with his lantern. Once inside the house, I knew that I was on my own, but I had no intention of being caught on the way in or out.[/p]
		[p]The window catch wass stiff, but I had brought a stout knife with me. I felt the catch slip back. The sash window slid up easily and fairly quietly. I climbed over the windowsill. I was in![/p]
		[p]Once inside, I uncovered my lantern and shone it around the room. I was in what was probably the dining room, though Fred had been right about there being very little furniture. There was only a table and three chairs. Over the back of one of the chairs was slung a man's suit. On the seat of the chair was a shirt, socks, a pair of boots – a complete set of man's clothing. All of it had been worn and some of it looked badly in need of laundering.[/p]
		[p]I felt in one of the jacket pockets and took out a piece of paper. It was a receipt made out to a Mr J. Brown for a pair of boots. At that instant, there was a tap at the window. I covered the lantern. It was Fred to tell me that a light had come on in the room above me. I could hear someone moving on the floor above.[/p]
		[p]“Come on!” urged Fred, in something louder than a stage whisper. “You doesn't want to be caught – and I don't neither!”[/p]
		[p]I could hear the footsteps again, overhead, and then the sound of a door closing. I wanted to see what else was in the pockets of the suit. Whoever was above might already be on the way downstairs.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="32">Were the other contents of the jacket important enough to risk being caught for?</next>
    <next id="34">Or should I take Fred's advice and get out?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="30">
    <text>
		[p]I didn't need to turn around to know that the pressure that I could feel in the centre of my back was from the barrel of a revolver.[/p]
		[p]“There's a door in front of you,” said the voice behind me. “Walk through it and just keep on walking 'till I tell you – and slowly.”[/p]
		[p]It was not the time to argue. We passed through the kitchens at the back of the house and into the front hallway. We stopped at a door under the main staircase.[/p]
		[p]“Face the door – closer! And don't move!”[/p]
		[p]I couldn't see the man with the gun, but I could still hear. I knew that one of the things he was doing was lighting an oil lamp which I had seen on a side table by the door.[/p]
		[p]“Now open the door and walk down the stairs.”[/p]
		[p]The oil lamp didn't give too much light, but the flight of stone steps in front of me obviously led to some kind of basement. I reached the bottom.[/p]
		[p]“Lie on the ground, face down, hands behind you.”[/p]
		[p]My wrists and ankles were tied. Footsteps ascended the stairs. I heard the door being closed and locked.[/p]
		[p]I rolled over on the ground. The basement was not completely dark. There was a small window, high up on the wall. The place was intensely cold![/p]
		[p]I could just reach the cord around my ankles. I managed to untie it before my fingers became too numb. Using the wall, I slid myself to my feet. There was something large in the centre of the floor with bales of straw packed around it. I walked over to it and raised myself on my toes. I could see into the top of a tank filled with what looked like crushed ice and salt. Nearby, was more straw surrounding some whole blocks of ice and pieces of ice on the floor which had been broken to fill the tank.[/p]
		[p]I managed to kneel down and scoop up some of the broken ice. With my hands tied and my fingers already numb, it was not easy. I carried the ice to the top of the stairs and began to kick at the door.[/p]
		[p]When I heard someone coming, I dropped the broken ice on the top steps, ran to the bottom, and hid behind the tank. I saw the door open and the figure of a man in the doorway with a lamp held high. He reached the third or fourth step before losing his footing on the ice![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="31"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="31">
    <text>
		[p]He crashed, headlong, down the steps, landing heavily at the bottom. My plan had been to rush past him, up the steps, and lock the door behind me, before he could recover. I had not counted on the lamp! Hurtling from his hand as he fell, it had landed by the bales of straw. As it had broken upon impact, the straw had burst into flame. A wall of fire stood between me and the way out![/p]
		[p]There was a crash of glass behind me. I turned to see the face of Albert looking at me through the broken pane of the small window. The man was getting up from the floor, but because of the fire he could not reach me. Albert jumped down and untied my hands. Using some unburned bales of straw, as steps, we climbed out through the small window.[/p]
		[p]It was no time for caution! We were at the front of the house. We ran across the lawn and through the gateway. Moments later we had joined Edward, back in the shrubbery of the house opposite.[/p]
		[p]There was no chase. I guessed that the people in the house were more worried about the fire. Minutes passed. Smoke now began to pour from some of the open ground floor windows. Any doubts I'd had as to whether the fire was out of control vanished as I saw the red Serpollet with two men in it appear at the gateway and head off down the Crescent. I could hear the sound of galloping horses and the clang of a fire bell approahing from not far off. Someone had seen the fire and it was time for us to depart.[/p]
		[p]When I returned to Baker Street, Mrs Hudson had got there before me. She had found the door unlocked, though nothing appeared to be missing. I had a feeling that nothing more was going to happen. More by accident than by good detective work, I had put an end to whatever plot was afoot. Years later, when I saw Dr Watson's unfinished article, I hoped that it might contain some answers. It did not.[/p]
		[p]I like to think that I and the Baker Street Irregulars saved Sherlock Holmes from something very unpleasant. “What”, I can never know, for the case remains unsolved.[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="32">
    <text>
		[p]I had begun to go through the rest of the pockets of the man's suit, when I heard the click of a door opening. A man stood in the doorway, silhouetted against the gaslight in the hall. As he moved his hand, I could see the gun in it.[/p]
		[p]“Walk slowly towards me,” he said, backing into the hall. “Now, up the stairs; and remember that I'm close behind you.”[/p]
		[p]I didn't recognise the man. There was no-one else to be seen, but the gun was enough to make me do as I was told. We climbed to the second floor. I was pushed through an open doorway and I heard the door closed and locked behind me. There was just enough light from the night sky to make out most of my surroundings. The room was completely bare. The windows were heavily barred. It had probably once been a nursery. I thought of breaking the glass with one of my shoes, but the bars were too close together to climb out.[/p]
		[p]I could hear a lot of sudden activity going on. I heard something being driven around the back of the house. From the chug of its petrol engine, I knew it was not the Serpollet. Men's voices were raised, more than once it seemed, in anger. I heard the chug of the same engine again but this time the vehicle seemed to be driving off. Then there was silence.[/p]
		[p]There were light footsteps on the stairs, the key turned in the lock and the door opened. Someone stood, holding a lantern. It was Fred's voice that said, “Come on, if you want's to follow them!”[/p]
		[p]On the way downstairs, Fred explained that the house was empty. Three men had left in a Daimler – with what looked like a great deal of luggage.[/p]
		[p]“You said, 'follow them'?” I queried.[/p]
		[p]“That's right,” Fred replied, “– in the steam carriage. Faster than a Daimler, it is, Charlie's gettin' it started.”[/p]
		[p]“Wait a minute!” I exclaimed, as we went through the kitchens towards the carriage house, “How does Charlie come to know how to start a steam carriage?”[/p]
		[p]Fred gave me a quite old-fashioned look.[/p]
		[p]“Cause, I showed 'im 'ow, o' course!”[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="33"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="33">
    <text>
		[p]When we reached the carriage house, the engine of the Gardner-Serpollet was already running. I was impressed; so impressed that I hardly liked to tell Fred that he had forgotten one thing. We did not know where the Daimler was giong![/p]
		[p]“We does!” said Charlie, brightly.[/p]
		[p]“Well, sort of,” Fred added. “We hoped as you would know where it was. We 'eard one of 'em say as they'd not much time to get to Dartmoor.”[/p]
		[p]My heart sank. Dartmoor is a huge place. But, of course! Dr Watson had gone to Devonshire to a place called Baskerville Hall. I asked Charlie to look in the Serpollet to see if there were any road maps. He found one. The Baskerville estate was marked near to the edge of Dartmoor. It was next to a large area of bog called the Grimpen Mire. I told Fred and Charlie that I had found it, but that it must be two hundred miles west of London.[/p]
		[p]Fred's only reaction was to say that, in that case, we would need more fuel. There were paraffin oil lamps in the house. We could empty them and any more oil we could find into bottles or anything else that would hold it.[/p]
		[p]While we collected the oil, I took the chance to discover the answers to two questions. If the Daimler was going to Dartmoor why had they not taken the Serpollet which was a faster carriage – and how did Fred know so much about engines?[/p]
		[p]Fred answered the first. He had removed a vital part of the Serpollet engine before the men had tried to start it. Charlie explained that Fred had learned about engines from his uncle Bert. Uncle Bert was very good with engines. He had been driving a steam carriage as the “get away” vehicle for a bank robbery when the police had caught him – and that was why he was now in prison![/p]
		[p]There was no time to examine the whole house but, while looking for the oil lamps, I did notice that the man's clothing had gone from the dining room. I asked about water for the steam engine and was told we could get that from streams on the way. Everything was ready. Nobody had said anything about who was to drive the Serpollet. Both Fred and Charlie must have assumed that I could![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="40"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="34">
    <text>
		[p]In his anxiety to get me out, Fred almost pulled me, headfirst, through the window. It was as well that he did for, at the instant that I had closed it behind me, a light appeared in the room. Afraid that we might be seen in the gaslight which spilled from the uncurtained window into the yard, we hurried back to the shrubbery.[/p]
		[p]We reached it in time to see a flash of light from across the road. Charlie was signalling. That meant that, for the moment, we would be safer to stay hidden where we were.[/p]
		[p]Lights suddenly appeared at the entrance to the drive and turned towards the front of the house. Another horseless carriage had arrived. I recognised the shape. It was a petrol-engined carriage called a Daimler, like the one owned by the new king, Edward VII. His claret coloured model was well known on the streets of London.[/p]
		[p]I saw the light in the room I had just left, go out. My mind turned back to the suit of man's clothing and the receipt which I had found in the pocket, bearing the name J. Brown. I had not yet solved the cryptic message which had been compiled from Holmes' note pad, but I was sure that it concerned someone called Brown.[/p]
		[p]Though we could not actually see the front of the house, it was obvious from the sudden brightness in the front garden that lights had been lit in several of the rooms. It seemed that whoever had arrived in the Daimler represented an event of some importance. If this were so, then it was very likely that the occupants of the house were too busy with something else to be returning quickly to an empty room which contained nothing but some man's clothing.[/p]
		[p]I told Fred to stay where he was while I crept back to the window. I shone my lantern through the glass. The room was empty, the door was closed, and the suit was still where I had last seen it.[/p]
		[p]Despite all that had happened, I had, as yet, found little or no real clues to solving the mystery. One of the important answers could be lying over a chair back within feet of where I was standing.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="32">Should I go back in?</next>
    <next id="36">Or return to the shrubbery which was not only safe, but a good vantage point from which to observe what was happening?</next>
  </p>
  <p id="35">
    <text>
		[p]I got out the sheets of scrap paper on which I had been trying to decipher the message from the note pad. Suddenly, the words fell into place – “Brown is making more demands for money. He must be removed.” It fitted exactly with the message left under the body on the moor – which I was sure was another forgery. Put together, they would provide convincing evidence of Holmes' guilt of the “murder”.[/p]
		[p]It didn't help solve the other half of the problem. Holmes had to have been given a good reason for the blackmail and murder. I was certain that he was going to be found to be in possession of top secret naval documents, the ones stolen from Lord Holdhurst. The obvious place was Baker Street. I had to make a second search.[/p]
		[p]I still had Holmes' Medical Directory which I had not yet had the opportunity to return. It was as I picked it up that the truth hit me![/p]
		[p]I had searched Holmes' room thoroughly. I had also relied on the dust to tell me whether anything had been moved. When I had examined the bookshelves the dust had been disturbed in only one place; where I had removed the Medical Directory. Could it already have been disturbed before I removed it?[/p]
		[p]I opened the book. In the back cover was a pocket for inserting notes or updating information. In it was a folded paper. I didn't need any expert knowledge to see that I was holding a very new and advanced design for a steam turbine; the type of engine used His Majesty's most modern warships. It was a document for which any foreign power would pay a very great deal of money.[/p]
		[p]I had arranged for Fred to call at Northumberland Square at four o'clock. I gave him two pounds, told him to buy a large bag, fill it with groceries and deliver it to the residence of Lord Holdhurst. He would probably be sent away and told that he had come to the wrong address. All that he had to do was to ensure that the document containing the secret engine design was dropped somewhere in the house; even if it were only the kitchens.[/p]
		[p]As I expected, Fred accomplished the task. All that I could do now, was wait![/p]
	</text>
    <next id="42"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="36">
    <text>
		[p]I thought it safest for Fred to stay where he was while I moved along the shrubbery to look at the front of the house. I had just got there when I had to throw myself flat to avoid being caught in the lights of the Daimler. It had turned and was being driven around to the back of the house.[/p]
		[p]From that moment, things really began to happen, quickly. There was a deal of coming and going mostly at the back of the house, out of my sight. I could hear men's voices; on two occasions, they seemed to be raised in anger. I cursed myself for being in the wrong place, but I dared not move, knowing that if I was caught there could be a general search. I could risk my own safety, but not that of Fred or Charlie.[/p]
		[p]It must have been a half hour later when the Daimler appeared again, stopping almost in front of my hiding place. There were two men in it and it seemed to be carrying a lot of luggage. Then, all the lights in the house went out. I heard the front door close and a third man joined the other two in the Daimler. At once, it moved off, disappearing through the gateway in a cloud of exhaust smoke.[/p]
		[p]I found Fred where I had left him and told him to fetch Charlie. I was sure that the house was now empty and I was going back inside to take a good look around.[/p]
		[p]The first thing that I saw was that the clothing had gone from ther chair. The door from the dining room led into the hall. Across its bare boards was a trail of water. I guessed that in one direction it led to the back door of the house. I followed it back the other way to an open doorway beneath the main staircase. The light from my lantern showed a flight of stone steps to the basement.[/p]
		[p]The basement was large, but not empty. Near the foot of the stairs was a large, open water tank. It was three quarters filled with a mixture of broken ice and salt. I guessed that whatever had been frozen in it had now been removed.[/p]
		[p]Fred and Charlie were waiting for me outside.[/p]
		[p]“Somehow,” I said, “we've got to find that Daimler!”[/p]
		[p]“We've got a steam carriage,” Fred observed.[/p]
		[p]I had almost forgotten the Gardner-Serpollet. but I needed some clue as to where the Daimler was going.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="37"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="37">
    <text>
		[p]It was now one thirty in the morning. Mrs Hudson, wearing a dressing gown and with paper curlers in her hair, answered the front door of number 221b Baker Street. It was hard to tell which astonished her most; me on the doorstep, or the red steam carriage standing in the road with two urchins in the back seat.[/p]
		[p]“I'm not mad,” I told her. “I believe Mr Holmes is in danger. I know that you don't know where he is, but tell me more about why Dr Watson has gone to stay with Sir Henry Baskerville at Baskerville Hall.”[/p]
		[p]“You're sure that Mr Holmes is in danger?”[/p]
		[p]“As certain as I can be,” I answered.[/p]
		[p]“Well,” she said, “I don't never listen intentional, you understand, but there's some things I can't help but overhear. These Baskervilles; there's supposed to be a curse on the family – to do with some terrible phantom hound. I'm not a woman to be believing in such tales, but it would seem that there's several of them that has met with sudden and mysterious deaths. The last one, Sir Charles Baskerville – that's the one Sir Henry inherited the estate from – he died of a heart attack, but …”[/p]
		[p]She paused. I told her to go on.[/p]
		[p]“The doctor who came to see Mr Holmes, he said that the man had died from sheer fright – and there was footprints, he said, 'footprints of a gigantic hound'!”[/p]
		[p]“But what made Dr Watson go to Baskerville Hall with Sir Henry?” I asked.[/p]
		[p]“Mr Holmes did,” she replied. “I wouldn't have taken the story so serious, but Mr Holmes, he seemed to think that Sir Henry's life might be in danger.”[/p]
		[p]She had told me enough. If Holmes believed that Sir Henry Baskerville's life was in danger, then he would have good reason for thinking it. I was also sure that he would not have sent his friend Watson alone on a dangerous mission. If Watson was at Baskerville Hall, then Holmes was not far away. I asked Mrs Hudson if she knew exactly where the place was. She did not; only that she'd heard some name like Grippingmire.[/p]
		[p]I'd spent a holiday near Dartmoor. It wasn't “Grippingmire”, but the Grimpen Mire, a large and very dangerous bog. It must be two hundred miles away from London.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="40">The shortest route was by poor and narrow roads.</next>
    <next id="39">The better, main roads could add miles to the journey.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="38">
    <text>
		[p]“A wild dog,” I said, hoping that my voice carried nothing of the cold fear which I felt. I was remembering the phantom hound of the Baskervilles! The cry was not repeated and I turned my attention to the body. It was a man in his thirties. The flesh was cold, but he didn't look as though he'd been dead long. I recognised his clothes as those which I had seen at Regent Crescent. I began to go through the pockets. I had to turn him to get at one of the side pockets of the jacket. As I moved him, the body began to slip down into the bog. Fred rushed forward. I grabbed him, fearing that he too might end up in the Grimpen Mire. It was too late to save the man. The mud closed over his head and the body was gone.[/p]
		[p]On the ground where the body had been was a crumpled piece of paper. On it, in a badly written hand, were the words, “I reckon I done the job much too cheep. I nose wher yer is an when I comes I expecs another hundred – in gold Mister Omes. Sined J. Brown.”[/p]
		[p]I put the paper into my pocket. There was nothing more to do on the moor and I didn't want to join Fred's uncle Bert for stealing a steam carriage. I left the Serpollet on the outskirts of Exeter and we returned to London on the first train.[/p]
		[p]Someone wanted to make it appear that Holmes had killed the man on the moor because he was blackmailing him over “the job”. To convince anyone that Holmes would commit murder, “the job” would have to be something big – very big! Was this the connection with the envelope at Baker Street; the one with what looked like Mycroft's seal? Mycroft Holmes had access to top state secrets. I wondered if any had been stolen recently. I looked through my old copies of [em]The Times[/em] newspaper and found two interesting paragraphs.[/p]
		[p]Three weeks before, Lord Holdhurst had been robbed as he left the lodgings of Mr Mycroft Holmes. The thief had snatched his case which, the report added, “contained only documents”. Lord Holdhurst was responsible for the Admiralty. Had “the job” been the theft of top secret naval documents? If my theory was right, they were going to be found – at Baker Street.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="41">I'd already searched Baker Street. Was it worth my returning?</next>
    <next id="35">My only other clue was the unsolved message forged from Holmes' note pad.</next>
  </p>
  <p id="39">
    <text>
		[p]We were travelling through the night towards Dartmoor, often at speeds touching fifty miles an hour. I began to wonder how Fred knew so much about steam carriages. He said he had learned about them from his uncle Bert who was, at present, in prison for having unsuccessfully used one as the “get away” vehicle for a bank robbery. I was very grateful to uncle Bert. I had wondered why the men had taken the Daimler instead of the much faster Serpollet. Fred had removed a vital part of the engine while I had been hiding at the front of the house. Fred had also started the engine tor us and made certain that we carried enough paraffin oil for the journey – even though it had meant emptying every oil lamp in the house at Regent Crescent. The water, we could get from streams on the way.[/p]
		[p]Though I had never driven a horseless carriage of any kind, once I had mastered the tiller which steered the front wheels, it was no more difficult than steering a boat, though the ride was much more bumpy![/p]
		[p]We were now travelling along the road that skirted Dartmoor. I had forgotten how large a place it was and was beginning to wonder what were our real chances of finding the Daimler, when Charlie gave a shout from the back seat. The powerful beam of the carbide lamp at the front, cut through a thin, wet mist to illuminate one of the many tracks which led off onto the moor. In the wet ground were fresh tyre marks. But there were two sets! Had the Daimler been and gone?[/p]
		[p]We left the carriage, took the lanterns and followed me tracks on foot. After half a mile, they stopped, and I could see where the Daimler had been turned around. Why had the Daimler come to this wild spot? Was it to leave something behind – but what and where?[/p]
		[p]Dawn was just breaking. Through the mist, I could make out patches of deep green and see the first light in the sky reflected in pools of water. It was the Grimpen Mire! We moved towards it, spreading out and testing the ground at each step.[/p]
		[p]“There's a deadun' – lyin' half in the mud!”[/p]
		[p]The voice was Fred's. It was then we heard it – an unearthly cry, like the howl of a dog, but a sound that it was hard to imagine coming from any creature of this world.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="38"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="40">
    <text>
		[p]I had begun to wish that I had not chosen to take the shortest route to Dartmoor. The roads were even rougher and narrower than I'd expected. Though I had never before driven a horseless carriage, I had quickly mastered the handling of the tiller which steered the front wheels. While we were still on the good road which had carried us for some miles out of London, I had found the Serpollet to be capable of speeds nearing fifty miles an hour![/p]
		[p]Now, I was wishing that I had greater driving skills. With deep ruts and great potholes in the road, I was finding it very hard to keep the carriage out of the ditches on either side of us.[/p]
		[p]We were now approaching Salisbury and, for some short distance, the road had been straight and its surface in good condition. Though the carriage was bumpy on its solid rubber tyres, the engine was almost' silent and we could hear all of the night noises of the countryside. It was then that we heard the unmistakable chug of a petrol engine some distance ahead of us. It had to be the Daimler![/p]
		[p]At the next bend we saw its lights; and they must have seen the powerful beam of our carbide lamp. With three men in the Daimler, I had not planned to give chase – only to follow them. The lights in front vanished as the Daimler crossed the brow of a hill. We did not see it again until we reached the same spot. On the other side, the road was steep and winding and a shower of rain had made it still more treacherous. We could see the lights moving down the hill at great speed. Suddenly, they were gone. A second later there was a burst of orange flame.[/p]
		[p]In my anxiety to reach the spot, I too was travelling too fast. I put on the brake. The Serpollet slithered to a halt, but not before it had tilted over in the ditch, throwing me from the driving seat.[/p]
		[p]Fred, Charlie and myself were unhurt but, by now, the Daimler was a blazing wreck. No-one in it could have survived.[/p]
		[p]Dawn was breaking when I returned the Serpollet to the carriage house at Regent Crescent. I parted from Fred and Charlie, and went back to Northumberland Square.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="45"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="41">
    <text>
		[p]As I was walking from Northumberland Square to Baker Street, the jumbled words from Holmes' note pad, suddenly fell into place. They said, “Brown is making more demands for money. He must be removed.” This fitted exactly with the message that I'd found under the body on the moor – which I was equally sure was a forgery. Both were intended to make Holmes look guilty of murder![/p]
		[p]Put together with the robbing of Lord Holdhurst outside the lodgings of Mycroft Holmes, it only made me more certian that I was looking for a missing government secret document. For the plan to have succeeded, the document would have to be found in Holmes' possession. It had to have been hidden at Baker Street.[/p]
		[p]Mrs Hudson already knew that something strange was going on. I felt that I had to tell her, at least a bit more of the story. I really had little choice. Mrs Baxter was almost recovered and Mrs Hudson no longer needed my services. I would have no opportunity to search Holmes' rooms secretly. I could only do it with Mrs Hudson's agreement.[/p]
		[p]Having heard my story, she did agree — provided that she watched me doing it. I did not object to that.[/p]
		[p]One problem was that the document could be quite small and so could easily be hidden. The other problem was that there could be no more difficult place to search than Holmes' living room, with tobacco stuffed into the toe of an old slipper, cigars in the coal scuttle and old letters secured to the fireplace with a knife blade.[/p]
		[p]I found nothing. My hopes were raised at one point when I noticed an odd looking gap amongst some of the books on the shelves. Those same hopes were dashed when I realised what was missing – Holmes' Medical Directory, which I had intended to return and which I had now left at Northumberland Square. I thought it better not to mention that fact to Mrs Hudson.[/p]
		[p]There was almost nothing more that I could do now, but wait.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="44"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="42">
    <text>
		[p]It was agreed between myself, Mrs Hudson and the Baker Street Irregulars that our part in this mystery should remain a secret. That is why I haven take so long to recount it. The discovery of Dr Watson's unfinished article has also enabled me to add a few final details.[/p]
		[p]The plan was to discredit both Sherlock Holmes and his brother, Mycroft; perhaps even to send Holmes to the gallows![/p]
		[p]First, the secret designs for the new naval turbine were stolen. How and when, is unimportant, but the robbery was made to appear to have taken place as Lord Holdhurst left the lodgings of Mycroft Holmes. A further link with Mycroft was provided by the letter left by Miss Marquis, which appeared to have come from Mycroft.[/p]
		[p]Whoever had masterminded the plan, then obtained the body of a man who had eithet been murdered, or had met some violent, but accidental, death. The body had then been preserved by freezing it in salt and ice in a tank in the basement of the house at Regent Crescent. There, the body would stay until the time was right. It would be a time and place where Holmes could have no alibi for the murder of which he was to be accused. Unfrozen, the body would appear to be only recently dead. It would then be placed where its discovery would point to Holmes as the criminal.[/p]
		[p]The perfect opportunity arose when Holmes became involved in the famous case of “The Hound of the Baskervilles”. Fearing that Sir Henry Baskerville's life was in danger, Holmes had sent Watson to Baskerville Hall. Holmes had followed, not to the Hall, but to a nearby, deserted hut on the moor where he could wait and watch in secret. Someone else had discovered Holmes' plan and seen it as the right moment to plant all of the evidence for the “murder”.[/p]
		[p]When Holmes and Watson returned from Baskerville Hall, the police would receive an anonymous note, together with the message forged from Holmes' note pad – “Brown is making more demands for money. He must be removed.”[/p]
		[p]Holmes and Watson had, in fact, just returned to Baker Street, when they were visited by Inspector Lestrade of Scotland Yard.[/p]
	</text>
    <next id="43"></next>
  </p>
  <p id="43">
    <text>
		[p]The sealed letter had already been opened. When Lestrade asked about its contents, he was told, truthfully, that it contained nothing. It must have sounded like a lie. The anonymous note which Lestrade had received accused Mycroft of having sent top secret naval plans to Holmes. Holmes insisted that the rooms be searched, but only one unusual thing was found. In a pocket in the back cover of a Medical Directory was a folded copy of diagrams showing how to construct a child's acrobatic clown. I could have explained it, but Holmes and Watson had never seen it before.[/p]
		[p]As the search finished, a message arrived for Lestrade from Lord Holdhurst. It said that certain important documents which he thought had been stolen had been found by his cook, apparently mislaid in his own kitchen.[/p]
		[p]I have no doubt that, had things gone according to plan, Lestrade would also have received news of an “innocent” walker who had found a body on Dartmoor. Papers on the body would have identified it as “Brown”; though that was probably not the man's real name. It would look as if an attempt had been made to conceal the body in the Grimpen Mire and, when it was moved, a letter would be found demanding more money from Holmes for “the job”. The police would already believe that “the job” was the theft of naval secrets. Thanks to Fred, Charlie and myself, there was no body to find and whoever had been paid to “find” it would be disappointed.[/p]
		[p]Holmes had many enemies and both Lestrade and Watson drought that the anonymous letter was just a spiteful joke. Holmes did not agree. He already suspected it was part of a plan which had gone wrong. He might have investigated it had he not been called upon to look into another mysterious death at a place called Lower Norwood.[/p]
		[p]I had solved the mystery, though I wished I could have known who was the mastermind behind it. One of Fred's descriptions of the man who had followed me fitted exactly with Holmes' greatest enemy, Professor Moriarty. Moriarty was believed to have been killed at Reichenbach Falls in 1891, yet who else could have devised so fiendish a plot?[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="44">
    <text>
		[p]Fred reported to me the next morning. Someone had been to the house in Regent Crescent in the night, had been there for a half hour and had left again. The house now appeared empty. I felt sure that they must have come to collect the red Serpollet. It was, of course, not there and I doubted whether its owner would dare to make enquiries as to its whereabouts or report a theft to the police. I didn't expect that anyone would now return to the house.[/p]
		[p]In losing the body in the Grimpen Mire, we had made fairly certain that Sherlock Holmes was not going to be accused of murder but, if the document was found at Baker Street, he might still be accused of treason. I was sure we had looked everywhere. I had not opened the sealed envelope. Mrs Hudson had refused to let me, but that did not worry me. I knew that the envelope would be empty.[/p]
		[p]Sherloch Holmes and Dr Watson returned to Baker Street some days later. Within an hour of their arrival, they had a visit from Inspector Lestrade of Scotland Yard. Mrs Hudson heard only snatches of the conversation. Lestrade had received an anonymous letter accusing Holmes of stealing a secret state document. Nothing was found and Lestrade seemed satisfied that it was only a wicked hoax.[/p]
		[p]I had hoped that when the unfinished article was found among the papers of the late Dr Watson, that might contain the final clues. It did not.[/p]
		[p]Though I had failed to solve the case, I have never revealed these details before because that was the agreement between myself, Mrs Hudson and the Baker Street Irregulars.[/p]
		[p]It is now so long ago that I had almost forgotten it. The reminder came when I was clearing out some old books from my attic. What should I find amongst them but a Medical Directory for 1901. I had always intended to return it to Holmes, but never had. I think that I had deliberately kept it as a sort of memento.[/p]
		[p]Now, it was just a reminder of an exciting mystery – but one that I had still failed to solve. I tied it up, together with some other old books and papers and deposited it in the rubbish bin.[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
  <p id="45">
    <text>
		[p]I had a few more ideas about the mystery, but I was nowhere near to solving it. I was sure that some vital clues had been lost in that blazing car.[/p]
		[p]If my thoughts had come anywhere near the truth, then there should be something else to be found at Baker Street. I had searched Holmes' room thoroughly already. I could try again. In any case, I had to return the Medical Directory which I had not been able to put back on the shelves.[/p]
		[p]I could not find the Medical Directory. It had been in my pocket. I suspected that it was now lying at the bottom of a ditch somewhere near Salisbury, where I had been thrown from the carriage.[/p]
		[p]I thought that it was time to tell Mrs Hudson something of what had been going on. She had, in any case, finished nursing Mrs Baxter and, without her agreement, I could not have made another search of Holmes' rooms. We found nothing more of interest.[/p]
		[p]Mrs Hudson, the Baker Street Irregulars and I agreed that our part in the affair should remain a secret amongst us. I was fairly certain that I had already done enough to foil whatever plan had been afoot. I could only wait and see.[/p]
		[p]Two days later, a paragraph appeared in the provincial news columns of [em]The Times[/em] newspaper, reporting a fatal accident on a road near Salisbury. A horseless carriage had, apparently, run out of control on a steep hill and caught fire when it overturned. It said that [em]four[/em] bodies had been found in the burned out wreckage. Only three men had left Regent Crescent. Who was the fourth?[/p]
		[p]When Holmes and Watson returned to Baker Street, they were visited by Inspector Lestrade of Scotland Yard. Mrs Hudson had heard little of the conversation, other than that the police had received an anonymous note accusing Holmes of some crime. Apparently, Lestrade had been satisfied that there was no evidence to support the accusations.[/p]
		[p]I had hoped that the part-finished article left in the papers of the late Dr Watson might have provided the final clues, but it did not. The case still remains unsolved.[/p]
	</text>
    <victory />
  </p>
</content>